<?xml version='1.0' encoding='GBK'?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by XMLSPY 2004 Professional Ed. Release 2, Installed Multi + SMP for 3 users (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - RFCE Civilizations -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
  <!-- Civilization Burgundy -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Burgundians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>勃艮第文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Burgundy</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>勃艮第</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Burgundian:Burgundians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>勃艮第</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Duchy of Burgundy, with origins in the Roman Empire, was a political entity that at its peak spread from what is today southwestern France, to central France, Belgium and the southern Netherlands. A center of trade, art, thought, and military power, it was at the center of conflict amongst the Kingdoms of France, Spain, Austria, and the Holy Roman Empire; as an independent entity, at times the Duchy rivaled the powers that coveted it.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through political intrigue, fortuitous marriages, financial power, and military strength, the early dukes and kings of Burgundy controlled a wealthy area of Gaul, including much of Provence, Switzerland, Franche-Comt? and the current Rgion de Bourgogne. After battles both martial and legal, Burgundy became nominally a fief of the France. As such a large and wealthy province, Burgundian dukes often rivaled and surpassed their feudal lords: the landed nobility had little interest in becoming a mere French province, and Burgundy flourished as a mostly independent state.[PARAGRAPH:2]Plague in the mid 14th century left Burgundy in a crisis of sucession, but with the outcome of a strong and capable Valois dynasty. Friendly but not subservient to the kings of France, the Valois brought the Duchy's golden age. During this period the Duchy's power extended into the low countries and presided over the wealthy cities of Dijon, Bruges, Ypres, Luxembourg, Brussels, and Ghent, among others.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Valois, flush with wealth and power, attempted to end the suzerainty of France once and for all, but were defeated. When Duke Charles the Bold died in battle in 1477, the duchy was effectively finished as anything more than a French province.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>勃艮第公爵领地起源于罗马帝国，是一个政治实体，在其鼎盛时期从今天的法国西南部扩展到法国中部、比利时和荷兰南部。它是贸易、艺术、思想和军事力量的中心，是法国、西班牙、奥地利王国和神圣罗马帝国之间冲突的中心；作为一个独立的实体，公爵领地有时通过政治阴谋、偶然的婚姻、财政实力和军事实力与觊觎它的列强抗衡，勃艮第早期的公爵和国王控制了高卢的一个富裕地区，包括普罗旺斯、瑞士、法国的大部分地区？以及现在的勃艮第。经过军事和法律上的斗争，勃艮第名义上成为法国的封地。作为一个如此庞大而富有的省份，勃艮第公爵经常与他们的封建领主竞争并超越他们：有土地的贵族对成为一个仅仅是法国的省份兴趣不大，勃艮第作为一个主要独立的国家蓬勃发展。[第2段]14世纪中叶的瘟疫使勃艮第陷入了一个成功的危机中，但结果却是一个强大的国家以及能干的瓦洛瓦王朝。瓦洛瓦人对法国国王很友好，但并不屈从，他带来了公爵的黄金时代。在这一时期，公爵的权力扩展到了低地国家，并统治着富裕的第戎、布鲁日、伊普尔、卢森堡、布鲁塞尔和根特等城市。1477年，当勇敢的查尔斯公爵在战争中去世时，公爵领地实际上已经结束了，不再是法国的一个省。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Burgundy -->
  <!-- Civilization Byzantium -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Byzantines</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>拜占庭文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Byzantium</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>拜占庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Byzantine:Byzantines</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>拜占庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Byzantine Empire, centered around the city of Constantinople, was the successor to the Roman Empire. At its height, the Byzantine Empire reached from Persia to Spain, controlling nearly all the territory that felt the lap of the Mediterranean's warm waters.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the Byzantine Empire began and the Roman Empire ceased is a point of much contention. Some historians place the beginning of the Byzantine Empire in 300 AD, when Constantine I moved the capital of the Roman Empire from Rome to a city called Byzantium (later know as Constantinople). Others place the birth of the Byzantine Empire at the end of the reign of Theodosius I, who at his death split the Roman Empire into the Western Empire, ruled from Rome, and the Eastern Empire, ruled from Constantinople.[PARAGRAPH:2]Regardless of historic debate, after the sacking of Rome in 476 AD, the Byzantine Empire was to become the foremost European nation in art, trade and stability - although not necessarily all at once. Taking the throne in 527 AD, Justinian I extended the grip of the Byzantine Empire from Constantinople to the furthest coasts of the Mediterranean Sea. However the Empire would not be able to enjoy the benefits of such territorial expansions for long, as Justinian's successor, Justin II, would begin a trend of placating the various enemies of the Empire - the Sassanid Persians, the Bulgars, and the Arabs, newly organized under Mohammed - with territory in exchange for peace.[PARAGRAPH:2]Territorial losses would continue to weaken the Byzantines until a new lineage of emperors, known as the Macedonian Emperors, arose to invigorate the Empire once again. Basil I founded the Macedonian line in 869. Under the Macedonians, the Byzantine Empire once again began to reach outwards, solidifying its hold on much of the territory neighboring Constantinople. Art flourished in their roughly two centuries of rule, as did the Greek Orthodox Church.[PARAGRAPH:2]The new millennium would be a painful one for Byzantium. Relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church had been deteriorating for many years, and the conflict came to a head with the Great Schism (1054), which finally split the two religions. Militarily, increased assaults by the Seljuk Turks culminated in a resounding defeat for the Empire at the Battle of Manzikert, the Empire losing much of its freshly-gained holdings.[PARAGRAPH:2]But once again, the rise of a powerful new dynasty reversed the Empire's decline. This new dynasty, the Comnenius, sent the call to Western Europe for aid in fighting the Seljuk Turks. Pope Urban II, seeing a chance to reconquer the Holy Lands of Antioch and Jerusalem, as well as halt the squabbling of the European Kings, spread the word for the First Crusade.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through the Crusaders' efforts, the Byzantine Empire regained a portion of its lost territory. But the holy warriors of Western Europe became difficult to control, often threatening to assault the very Empire that had requested their aid. John II and Manuel I, the two most prestigious of the Comnenius emperors, held off the Crusaders and safeguarded the empire from a host of external foes, while ushering in a new era of Byzantine artistic and economic prowess.[PARAGRAPH:2]Manuel I Comnenius was the last great emperor of the Byzantines and the last Comneni. The Angeloi dynasty, successors to the Comneni, proved unable to halt the Empire's slow collapse. In 1204, the knights of the Fourth Crusade, summoned by a disposed Angeloi prince, sacked Constantinople and split the Byzantine Empire into three smaller kingdoms. Nicaea, one of these ex-Byzantine states, recaptured Constantinople years later, but all hopes of reviving the Byzantine Empire would be ended with the capture of the city by the Ottoman leader Mehmed II in 1461.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>以君士坦丁堡为中心的拜占庭帝国是罗马帝国的继承者。拜占庭帝国在其鼎盛时期，从波斯到西班牙，几乎控制了所有能感受到地中海温暖水域的领土。[第2段]拜占庭帝国开始和罗马帝国结束时是一个争论的焦点。一些历史学家把拜占庭帝国的开始放在公元300年，当时君士坦丁一世把罗马帝国的首都从罗马迁到一个叫做拜占庭（后来被称为君士坦丁堡）的城市。另一些人认为拜占庭帝国的诞生是在狄奥多西一世统治末期，狄奥多西一世死后将罗马帝国分裂为西方帝国，由罗马统治，而东方帝国则由君士坦丁堡统治。[第2段]不管历史上有什么争论，在公元476年罗马被洗劫后，拜占庭帝国将成为最重要的帝国一个在艺术、贸易和稳定方面的欧洲国家――虽然不一定一下子。公元527年，查士丁尼一世即位，将拜占庭帝国的统治范围从君士坦丁堡扩展到地中海最远的海岸。然而，由于查士丁尼的继任者查士丁二世（Justin II）将开始安抚帝国的各种敌人――萨珊王朝的波斯人、保加利亚人和阿拉伯人，帝国将无法长期享受这种领土扩张的好处，在穆罕默德统治下新建立的以领土换取和平的组织。[第2段]领土损失将继续削弱拜占庭帝国，直到一个新的帝王世系，即马其顿帝王，再次振兴帝国。巴兹尔一世于869年建立了马其顿线。在马其顿统治下，拜占庭帝国再次开始向外扩张，巩固了对邻近君士坦丁堡的大部分领土的控制。艺术在大约两个世纪的统治中蓬勃发展，希腊东正教也是如此。罗马天主教和东正教之间的关系多年来一直在恶化，这场冲突最终以大分裂（1054年）告终，最终分裂了两个宗教。在军事上，塞尔柱突厥人的不断进攻最终导致了帝国在曼齐克特战役中的惨败，帝国失去了大部分新获得的财产。[第2段]但是，一个强大的新王朝的崛起再次扭转了帝国的衰落。这个新王朝，科姆涅尼乌斯，向西欧发出了援助塞尔柱土耳其人的呼吁。教皇乌尔班二世，看到有机会重新征服安提俄克和耶路撒冷的圣地，以及停止欧洲国王的争吵，传播了第一次十字军东征的消息。[第2段]通过十字军的努力，拜占庭帝国收复了部分失地。但是西欧的圣战者变得很难控制，他们经常威胁要攻击请求他们援助的帝国。约翰二世和曼努埃尔一世，这两位最负盛名的科姆尼乌斯皇帝，在开启拜占庭艺术和经济实力新纪元的同时，抵挡了十字军的进攻，保护了帝国不受外来敌人的侵扰。[第2段]曼努埃尔一世科姆尼乌斯是拜占庭最后一位伟大的皇帝，也是最后一位科姆尼乌斯。科姆涅尼王朝的继承者安杰洛伊王朝证明无法阻止帝国的缓慢崩溃。1204年，第四次十字军东征的骑士们被安杰洛伊王子召来，洗劫君士坦丁堡，将拜占庭帝国分裂成三个更小的王国。尼西亚，这些前拜占庭国家之一，在数年后夺回了君士坦丁堡，但所有复兴拜占庭帝国的希望都将随着奥斯曼帝国领袖穆罕默德二世于1461年攻占这座城市而告终。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Byzantium -->
  <!-- Civilization France -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The French</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>法兰西文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>France</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>法兰西</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>French</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>法兰西</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Modern France has its roots in ancient Gaul. In the 2nd century BC Rome intervened on the side of Massilia (Marseilles), a Greek colony founded in 600 BC, in its struggle against the barbarian tribes of the hinterland. The result was the formation, in 121 BC, of the Roman Provincia in what is now southern France; between 58 to 50 BC Julius Caesar seized the remainder. For more than four centuries Gaul enjoyed the benefits of Roman rule, and many ruins of aqueducts and bathhouses still dot the French landscape. After 395 AD the internal problems of the Empire encouraged barbarian penetration of Gaul. By 418, the Franks and Burgundians were established west of the Rhine, and the Visigoths had settled in Aquitaine. The period of the Merovingian and Carolingian Frankish dynasties (476-887) frames the Early Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following his ascension, the first Merovingian king, Clovis (481-511), consolidated the position of the Franks in northern Gaul. Clovis came to believe that his victories were due to the Christian God. Clovis' subsequent conversion assured the Frankish rulers of the support not only of the Catholic Church but of the majority of their own subjects. The Frankish kingdom reached its largest extent under Charlemagne (768-814), who united modern-day France, Italy, and Germany under his rule. After Charlemagne's death, his grandsons divided the kingdom into the three parts that have largely survived to the present. France was a divided kingdom for much of the medieval period, but power gradually began to accumulate in the hands of the rulers of the Ile de France region centered around Paris. By the rise of the house of Valois in 1328, France was the most powerful kingdom in Europe. Its ruler could muster larger armies than rivals; he could tap enormous fiscal resources; and the king's courts maintained royal supremacy. The history of France in the Late Middle Ages is dominated by efforts of its kings to maintain their suzerainty, efforts that, despite French advantages, were long frustrated.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hundred Years War was an intermittent struggle between England and France in the 14th-15th centuries over a series of dynastic disputes, including the legitimate succession to the French crown. The war's turning point was reached in 1429, when an English army was forced to raise its siege of Orleans by a relief force organized by Joan of Arc. By 1453, England retained only Calais, which it finally relinquished in 1558. The French kings of the 16th century spent much of their time fighting the Hapsburg monarchs for control of Italy, while religious conflict between Catholics and Protestants led to a series of civil wars between 1562 and 1598.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ascension of the Bourbon line of kings beginning in 1589 brought renewed stability to France, and the country soared to some of its greatest heights during the long rule of Louis XIV (1643-1715). Under Louis, France became the artistic and intellectual capital of Europe. From his magnificent palace of Versailles, Louis was truly the "Sun King", the absolute master of all he surveyed. The French military was the most powerful in Europe at this time, known for the elite Musketeer units that served as the king's personal guard. France was so strong at this time that the other European nations kept banding together to stop France from conquering them - a pattern that would be repeated in the French Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]These intellectual developments, although significant by themselves, gave rise to a still more momentous change: the French Enlightenment. This movement was a cultural transformation based on rationalism, empiricism, and an amorphous concept of freedom found in the influential writings of figures like Voltaire (1694-1778) and Rousseau (1712-78). Compounding the situation was the bankruptcy of the French crown, which forced the king to call upon representatives of the people for additional taxes. Hence, what began in 1787 as a conflict between royal authority and aristocrats became a triangular struggle, with "the masses" opposing both absolutism and privilege. By any standard, the fall of the Bastille to the Parisian crowd in 1789 was a monumental event, a seemingly miraculous triumph of the people. But the French Revolution soon degenerated into a reign of terror and chaos. After a decade of violence and uncertainty, Napoleon terminated the bloodshed by overthrowing the French government in 1800, at the price of suppressing freedom altogether. In utter contrast to the Revolution, militarism became the defining quality of the Napoleonic regime. The French armies under Napoleon won victory after victory against all of the other great European powers, but decades of war led to the exhaustion of the nation and eventual defeat in 1815.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, the revolutionary fervor of the French citizenry was undiminished by the Napoleonic experience, and led to further revolutions in 1830 and 1848. The latter revolution lead to the short-lived Second Republic (1848-1852), which was overthrown by Napoleon's nephew "Napoleon III" who instituted the Second Empire (1852-1870). Following defeat in the Franco-Prussia War, the Third Republic (1870-1940) was formed, which survived the First World War but collapsed in the face of the German invasion in 1940. After the war, the period of the short-lived Fourth Republic (1947-59) was succeeded by the Fifth Republic (the current one), adopted in September 1958 by popular referendum. Although shorn of its past colonial holdings and aura of military invulnerability, France today remains a major economic power and influential member of the European Union.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>现代法国起源于古高卢。公元前2世纪，罗马在马西利亚（马赛）一边进行干预，马西利亚（马赛）是公元前600年建立的一个希腊殖民地，它与内地的野蛮部落进行斗争。其结果是，公元前121年，在现在的法国南部形成了罗马省；公元前58年至50年间，凯撒大帝夺取了剩下的部分。四个多世纪以来，高卢享受着罗马统治的好处，许多水道和澡堂的废墟仍然点缀着法国的风景。公元395年后，帝国内部的问题鼓励野蛮人渗透高卢。到418年，法兰克人和勃艮第人在莱茵河以西建立，西哥特人在阿基坦定居。梅罗文吉王朝和加洛林王朝的法兰克王朝（476-887年）是中世纪早期的框架。[第2段]在他的提升之后，第一位梅罗文吉国王克洛维斯（481-511年）巩固了法兰克人在北高卢的地位。克洛维斯开始相信他的胜利是由于基督教的上帝。克洛维斯随后的皈依保证了法兰克统治者不仅支持天主教，而且支持他们自己的大多数臣民。法兰克王国在查理曼大帝（768-814）统治下达到了最大程度，查理曼大帝在他的统治下统一了现代的法国、意大利和德国。查理曼大帝死后，他的孙子们把王国分成三个部分，这三个部分基本上一直延续到现在。在中世纪的大部分时间里，法国是一个分裂的王国，但权力逐渐开始在以巴黎为中心的法兰西岛地区的统治者手中积累起来。1328年瓦洛瓦家族崛起，法国成为欧洲最强大的王国。它的统治者可以召集比竞争对手更强大的军队；他可以利用巨大的财政资源；国王的宫廷可以维持皇室的至高无上地位。中世纪晚期，法国的历史主要是国王们为维持宗主地位所作的努力，这些努力尽管有法国的优势，但长期以来一直受挫。[第2段]百年战争是14-15世纪英法之间为一系列王朝争端而进行的断断续续的斗争，包括合法继承法国王位。这场战争的转折点是在1429年，当时一支英国军队被圣女贞德组织的一支救援部队强迫提高对奥尔良的围攻。到1453年，英格兰只保留了加莱，1558年最终放弃了加莱。16世纪的法国国王大部分时间都在与哈普斯堡君主争夺意大利的控制权，而天主教徒和新教徒之间的宗教冲突导致1562年至1598年间的一系列内战。[第2段]1589年开始的波旁王朝的崛起给法国带来了新的稳定，在路易十四（1643-1715）长期统治期间，这个国家达到了它的一些最高峰。在路易的统治下，法国成为欧洲的艺术和知识之都。从他宏伟的凡尔赛宫，路易斯是真正的“太阳王”，绝对的主人，他所有的调查。法国军队是当时欧洲最强大的军队，以充当国王私人卫队的精英火枪手部队而闻名。法国在这个时候是如此强大，以至于其他欧洲国家不断联合起来阻止法国征服他们，这种模式将在法国大革命中重演。[第2段]这些智力发展虽然本身意义重大，但却带来了更为重大的变化：法国启蒙运动。这场运动是一场基于理性主义、经验主义和无定形的自由概念的文化变革，这种自由概念见于伏尔泰（1694-1778）和卢梭（1712-178）等有影响力的人物的著作中。使情况更为复杂的是法国王室的破产，迫使国王要求人民代表增税。因此，从1787年开始的皇权与贵族之间的冲突变成了一场三角斗争，“群众”既反对专制，又反对特权。以任何标准衡量，巴士底狱在1789年被巴黎民众攻陷，都是一个不朽的事件，是人民看似奇迹般的胜利。但是法国大革命很快就演变成了一个恐怖和混乱的时代。在经历了十年的暴力和不确定性之后，拿破仑在1800年以完全镇压自由为代价推翻了法国政府，从而结束了流血冲突。与革命形成鲜明对比的是，军国主义成为拿破仑政权的决定性特征。拿破仑领导下的法国军队一次又一次地战胜了欧洲所有其他大国，但几十年的战争导致了国家的衰败，最终在1815年失败。[第2段]然而，法国公民的革命热情并没有因为拿破仑的经历而减弱，并在1830年和1848年导致了进一步的革命。后一次革命导致了短暂的第二共和国（1848-1852），被拿破仑的侄子“拿破仑三世”推翻，拿破仑三世建立了第二帝国（1852-1870）。法国-普鲁士战争失败后，第三共和国（1870-1940）成立，它在第一次世界大战中幸存下来，但在1940年德国入侵面前崩溃。战后，短暂的第四共和国时期（1947-1959）由1958年9月全民公决通过的第五共和国（现为第五共和国）继承。尽管法国摆脱了过去的殖民统治和军事无懈可击的光环，但今天它仍然是欧洲联盟的一个主要经济大国和有影响力的成员。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization France -->
  <!-- Civilization Arabia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Arabs</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉伯文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Arabia</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉伯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Arab:Arabs</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉伯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Before the spread of Islam and the Arabic language, the term "Arab" referred to any of the nomadic residents of the Arabian Peninsula. When used in a modern context, "Arab" refers to any of the Arabic-speaking peoples who reside on the Atlantic Coast of Africa, Southwestern Iran, Egypt, Sudan, Saudi-Arabia, Syria, and Iraq. The earliest nomadic inhabitants of the Arabian Peninsula herded their sheep, goats, and camels through an unforgiving desert environment; while those Arabs who settled in the oases provided date and cereal agriculture as trade staples for Arab caravans that transported spices, ivory, and gold from southern Arabia and the Horn of Africa to the civilizations farther north.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 7th century AD, Muhammad emerged as the prophet for the religion of Islam, which was widely adopted by the Arab community. Islam unified the Bedouins and the town-dwellers of the oases, and within a century, spread throughout most of the present day Arab-speaking world. The newfound social organization that followed Islam offered new possibilities for the Arabs as agricultural production and intercity trading, particularly in luxury goods, saw significant increases. Gradually, the triad of temple, court, and market formed, as well as a standardized style of writing for laws and other texts. New institutions also emerged, including coinage, territorial deities, royal priesthoods, and standing armies, which further enhanced Arab power.[PARAGRAPH:2]By proclaiming his message publicly, Muhammad gained many followers. After his death, the succeeding caliphs continued to spread the faith of Islam far beyond the religion's birthplace in Mecca. Aside from initial conquests in Iraq and Syria, the Arab conquests penetrated regions including Anatolia, Northern Africa, and Iran. Using their Camel Archers to cross difficult desert terrain, the Arabs were able to create an empire stretching from Spain to the borders of India in barely more than a hundred years. The Arab empire of the medieval period was far more advanced than contemporary Europeans; Harun al-Rashid's Baghdad may have held a million people at the same time that Charlemagne's Aachen was a "capital" of ten thousand. Centers of learning attracted scholars from across the Muslim world to great cities such as Baghdad, Damascus, and Cordoba. The Arabs of this period made many advances in medicine, astronomy, mathematics, and other areas, as well as translating many of the classics of the Ancient Greeks into Arabic, thereby saving them from destruction.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the period of the Crusades, the Arabic world came under assault from Christian Europe. The greatest of Muslim generals from this period was Salah al-Din, better known as Saladin, who successfully defeated the Third Crusade and recaptured Jerusalem for the Arabs. In addition to his military skills, Saladin was known to be a pious man and was well-respected by his enemies as well as his allies - which was very unusual indeed for the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2]For most of the past five centuries, much of the Arab world has been ruled by foreigners; first by the Ottoman Turks, then by the Western colonial powers. Since the onset of de-colonization in the 1950s, traditional Arab values have been modified through the combined pressures of urbanization, industrialization, and Western influence. While urban Arabs still tend to identify themselves more by nationality than by tribe, village farmers revere the pastoral nomad's romantic way of life and claim a kinship with the great desert tribes of the past. As heirs to the ancient Egyptians, Babylonians, Persians, Hebrews, even to the Greeks and Indians, the societies created by Muslims bridge time and space. The original Arab tribes, in less than 20 years after Muhammad's death, defeated the Byzantine and Persian empires, occupied a vast territory from Libya to Persia, and then developed into the Arab, or Islamic, Empire known today.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>在伊斯兰教和阿拉伯语传播之前，“阿拉伯”一词指的是阿拉伯半岛的任何游牧居民。在现代语境中，“阿拉伯人”指居住在非洲大西洋沿岸、伊朗西南部、埃及、苏丹、沙特阿拉伯、叙利亚和伊拉克的讲阿拉伯语的民族。阿拉伯半岛最早的游牧居民在无情的沙漠环境中放牧绵羊、山羊和骆驼；而那些定居在绿洲的阿拉伯人则为运送香料、象牙的阿拉伯商队提供日期和谷物农业作为贸易主食，从阿拉伯南部和非洲之角到更远的北方文明的黄金。[第2段]公元7世纪，穆罕默德成为伊斯兰教的先知，被阿拉伯社会广泛采用。伊斯兰教统一了贝多因人和绿洲的城镇居民，并在一个世纪内，传遍了当今大多数讲阿拉伯的世界。随着农业生产和城市间贸易，特别是奢侈品贸易的大幅增长，新成立的追随伊斯兰教的社会组织为阿拉伯人提供了新的可能性。逐渐形成了寺庙、宫廷、市场三位一体的格局，形成了法律等文本的规范化写作风格。新的制度也出现了，包括铸币、领土神、皇家祭司和常备军，这进一步增强了阿拉伯的力量。[第2段]穆罕默德通过公开宣布他的信息，赢得了许多追随者。他死后，继任哈里发继续传播伊斯兰教的信仰，远远超出了该宗教在麦加的发源地。除了最初在伊拉克和叙利亚的征服，阿拉伯的征服还渗透到安纳托利亚、北非和伊朗等地区。阿拉伯人用骆驼弓箭手穿越险峻的沙漠地形，在短短的一百多年内，就创造了一个从西班牙一直延伸到印度边境的帝国。中世纪时期的阿拉伯帝国远比当代欧洲人先进；哈伦・拉希德的巴格达可能拥有一百万人口，而查理曼大帝的亚琛则是一万人的“首都”。学习中心吸引了来自穆斯林世界的学者来到巴格达、大马士革和科尔多瓦等大城市。这一时期的阿拉伯人在医学、天文学、数学和其他领域取得了许多进步，并将古希腊人的许多经典翻译成阿拉伯语，从而使他们免于毁灭。[第2段]在十字军东征时期，阿拉伯世界受到基督教欧洲的攻击。这一时期最伟大的穆斯林将领是萨拉赫丁（Salah al-Din），俗称萨拉丁，他成功地击败了第三次十字军东征，为阿拉伯人夺回了耶路撒冷。除了他的军事技能，萨拉丁是一个虔诚的人，受到他的敌人和盟友的尊敬，这在十字军东征中是非常不寻常的。自20世纪50年代开始去殖民化以来，阿拉伯传统价值观在城市化、工业化和西方影响的共同压力下发生了变化。虽然城市阿拉伯人仍然倾向于更多地通过民族而不是部落来认同自己，但乡村农民崇敬牧民的浪漫生活方式，并声称与过去的大沙漠部落有血缘关系。作为古埃及人、巴比伦人、波斯人、希伯来人，甚至希腊人和印度人的继承人，穆斯林创造的社会架起了时空桥梁。最初的阿拉伯部落，在穆罕默德死后不到20年的时间里，打败了拜占庭帝国和波斯帝国，占领了从利比亚到波斯的广大领土，然后发展成为今天所知的阿拉伯或伊斯兰帝国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Arabia -->
  <!-- Civilization Bulgaria -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Bulgarians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>保加利亚文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Bulgaria</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>保加利亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Bulgarian:Bulgarians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>保加利亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Bulgars originally came from Central Asia, 'somewhere east of the Black Sea,' near modern day Kazakhstan and were occasional allies of the Huns. They began sporadic service with the Byzantines as mercenaries in the late 5th century, and by the time of Emperor Justinian I were actually administering some towns in the Empire, defending them against other Bulgars and nomadic tribes from the east. The Bulgars had a falling outwith the Empire, retreated to the steppes, and were next heard from when they joined the Gepids and Lombards in invading Italy. Around 600 AD, the Bulgars had returned and conquered the Slavic area of the Balkans controlled bythe Byzantines. The Byzantine Empire recognized the first Bulgarian Empire in 681 AD, and this nation lasted until 1081 AD.[PARAGRAPH:2]Even though the Bulgars ruled this area with an iron fist, they ended up assimilating much of the Slavic language and culture and eventually would mingle so much with their subjects that eventually it was impossible to determine who was Bulgar and who was Slav. This interbreeding with their Slavic subjects did not dull their ferocity however, and during the Middle Ages Bulgaria was a great military power. The Bulgars fought many wars against the Byzantine Empire, their other neighbors, and nomadic invaders. By 865 AD, Czar Boris I had converted to Christianity and established an independent Bulgarian branch of the Eastern Orthodox church and adopted the Cyrillic alphabet as the official state language, and this alphabet and church spread from Bulgaria to the rest of eastern Europe and then into Russia. Boris' son, Czar Simeon I (893-927 AD) was one of Bulgaria's greatest rulers and during his reign, Bulgaria flourished as a center of Slavic culture and learning. As befitted his warrior heritage, Simeon also conquered many new territories and at his death, Bulgaria stretched from the Black Sea to the Adriatic. After Simeon's death, Bulgaria waned in power, eventually being conquered by the Byzantines. After almost two hundred years of rule by the Byzantines, there followed a two hundred year second Bulgarian Empire that was, in turn, conquered by the Ottoman Empire.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>保加利亚人最初来自中亚，黑海以东，靠近现代哈萨克斯坦，偶尔是匈奴的盟友。他们在5世纪末开始以雇佣兵的身份为拜占庭人提供零星的服务，到查士丁尼一世皇帝时，我实际上正在管理帝国的一些城镇，保护他们免受来自东方的其他保加利亚人和游牧部落的伤害。保加利亚人与帝国决一死战，撤退到大草原上，然后他们加入了入侵意大利的格皮兹人和伦巴第人。大约公元600年，保加利亚人返回并征服了由拜占庭人控制的巴尔干半岛的斯拉夫地区。拜占庭帝国在公元681年承认了第一个保加利亚帝国，这个国家一直持续到公元1081年[第2段]尽管保加利亚人用铁腕统治着这个地区，但他们最终吸收了大部分斯拉夫语言和文化，并最终与他们的臣民融合在一起，最终无法确定谁是保加利亚人谁是斯拉夫人。然而，这种与斯拉夫臣民的混血并没有削弱他们的凶猛，在中世纪保加利亚是一个强大的军事力量。保加利亚人与拜占庭帝国、其他邻国和游牧入侵者进行了多次战争。到公元865年，沙皇鲍里斯一世皈依基督教，建立了一个独立的东正教保加利亚分支，并采用西里尔字母作为官方国家语言，这个字母表和教会从保加利亚传播到东欧其他地区，然后进入俄罗斯。鲍里斯的儿子，沙皇西缅一世（公元893-927年）是保加利亚最伟大的统治者之一，在他的统治期间，保加利亚作为斯拉夫文化和学习中心蓬勃发展。作为他的战士遗产，西缅还征服了许多新界，在他死后，保加利亚从黑海延伸到亚得里亚海。西缅死后，保加利亚逐渐衰落，最终被拜占庭人征服。在拜占庭人统治了将近两百年之后，又有了一个二百年的第二保加利亚帝国，而这个帝国又被奥斯曼帝国征服了。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Bulgaria -->
  <!-- Civilization Cordoba -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Cordobans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Cordoba</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Cordoban:Cordobans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In 711 AD, thousands of Muslim Arabs and Berbers landed at Gibraltar to begin a rapid conquest of Spain. The Arabs called the region al-Andalus (from which the modern name "Andalusia" is derived) and brought it under the control of the Umayyad Caliphate. This Arabian dynasty had been the civil and spiritual leaders of Islam for the previous fifty years, but their nepotistic rule caused much unrest in the Muslim world. After the ousting of the Umayyads in Damascus by the Abbasids in 750, Abd ar-Rahman, a grandson of a former caliph and one of the few surviving Umayyad clan, fled to al-Andalus and took over this Muslim salient in Europe. His emirate, centered around Cordoba, was the only one that remained independent from the Abbasid Caliphate. The Abbasids did not have the manpower to re-conquer such a far-flung province and under the rule of the ar-Rahman dynasty, Cordovan Spain became a powerful, centralized state, expanding its territory northward at the expense of Christian kingdoms that had resisted the Muslim invaders. Abd ar-Rahman had Cordoba's Great Mosque built in 785, which survives to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 929 AD Abd ar-Rahman III declared himself the Caliph of Cordoba. The title Caliph is reserved for the leader of Islam, but there were already two caliphs in the Muslim world. The Abbasid (or Baghdad) caliph, who was Sunni, traced his descent from Abbas, an uncle of the Prophet Muhammad. The Fatimid caliph, who was Shi'i, traced his descent from Fatima, a daughter of the Prophet. The Umayyads were also Arabs of the Sunni sect, but their lineage traced to Uthman, the third caliph who succeeded Muhammad.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Cordovan Umayyads reached their height in the late 10th century, consolidating their hold on the provinces in Spain and expanding into North Africa against the Fatimids. However, following the familiar pattern seen throughout the history of the Muslim Crescent, regional rulers grew discontented with the leadership at Cordoba and undermined the authority of the Umayyads, and between 1009-1031 a bitter civil war ripped apart the Cordovan Caliphate. Afterwards, al-Andalus was split into small kingdoms called taifas, ruled by local warlords.[PARAGRAPH:2]These local warlords could not stand up to the Christian kingdoms in the north that started the reconquest of Spain. To lend urgency to this push, Pope Alexander II declared it a Crusade, forgiving the sins of those on the way to fight the Muslims. By 1212, the Christian kingdoms of Leon, Castile, Aragon and Catalonia had pushed the Muslims halfway down the peninsula, and a major defeat of the Muslim rulers at Las Navas de Tolosa heralded the beginning of the end for al-Andalus. Cordoba itself fell in 1236. The rest of the history of al-Andalus is a series of defeats, retreats and the shrinking of the Muslim presence in Spain until all that remained of the once mighty al-Andalus was a narrow strip of land near Granada. Ferdinand of Aragon and Isabella of Castile launched a last war against the Muslims and conquered Granada at last in 1492.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>公元711年，成千上万的阿拉伯人和柏柏柏尔人登陆直布罗陀，开始了对西班牙的快速征服。阿拉伯人称之为安达卢斯地区（现代名称“安达卢西亚”源自该地区），并将其置于倭玛亚哈里发的控制之下。这个阿拉伯王朝在过去的五十年里一直是伊斯兰教的公民和精神领袖，但是他们的裙带关系在穆斯林世界引起了很大的动荡。公元750年，阿巴斯人驱逐了大马士革的倭玛亚人之后，阿布德・拉赫曼，一位前哈里发的孙子，也是少数幸存的倭玛亚部族之一，逃到了安达卢斯，接管了欧洲这个穆斯林要塞。他的酋长国，以科尔多瓦为中心，是唯一一个独立于阿巴斯哈里发的酋长国。阿巴斯人没有人力重新征服如此遥远的省份，在拉赫曼王朝的统治下，科尔多瓦西班牙成为一个强大的中央集权国家，以抵抗穆斯林侵略者的基督教王国为代价向北扩张领土。阿布德・拉赫曼于785年建造了科尔多瓦大清真寺，至今仍然存在。[第2段]公元929年，阿布德・拉赫曼三世宣布自己为科尔多瓦哈里发。哈里发这个头衔是留给伊斯兰教领袖的，但穆斯林世界已经有两个哈里发了。阿巴斯（或称巴格达）哈里发是逊尼派，他的后裔来自先知穆罕默德的叔叔阿巴斯。法蒂玛哈里发，即什叶派，从先知的女儿法蒂玛那里追查他的血统。倭玛亚人也是逊尼派的阿拉伯人，但他们的血统可追溯到继承穆罕默德的第三位哈里发乌斯曼（Uthman）。[第2段]科尔多瓦倭玛亚人在10世纪末达到了顶峰，巩固了他们对西班牙各省的控制，并扩展到北非对抗法蒂玛人。然而，按照穆斯林新月会历史上常见的模式，地区统治者对科尔多瓦的领导层越来越不满，并削弱了倭玛亚王朝的权威，在1009-1031年间，一场激烈的内战将科尔多瓦哈里发政权瓦解。后来，安达卢斯被分裂成一个叫塔法斯的小王国，由地方军阀统治。[第2段]这些地方军阀无法与北方的基督教王国抗衡，后者开始了对西班牙的征服。为了使这一努力更加紧迫，教皇亚历山大二世宣布这是一次十字军东征，宽恕了那些在与穆斯林战斗途中的人的罪行。到1212年，利昂、卡斯蒂利亚、阿拉贡和加泰罗尼亚等基督教王国将穆斯林推向半岛的半路，穆斯林统治者在拉斯纳瓦斯德托洛萨（Las Navas de Tolosa）的一次重大失败预示着安达卢斯的末日已经开始。科尔多瓦本身在1236年下跌。安达卢斯的其余历史是一系列的失败、撤退和穆斯林在西班牙的势力的萎缩，直到曾经强大的安达卢斯只剩下格拉纳达附近的一小块土地。阿拉贡的费迪南德和卡斯蒂利亚的伊莎贝拉对穆斯林发动了最后一次战争，并最终在1492年征服了格拉纳达。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Cordoba -->
  <!-- Civilization Spain -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Spanish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>西班牙文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Spain</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>西班牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Spanish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>西班牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Kingdom of Spain is located in the extreme southwest of the European continent, and occupies approximately 85 percent of the Iberian Peninsula. Spain is bordered on the west by Portugal, in the northeast by France, and by the great wall of the Pyrenees Mountains. The Iberian Peninsula that the Spanish inhabited was occupied by various other civilizations, including the Phoenicians, Carthaginians, Romans, Visigoths, and Muslims, and Spain is now associated with having a very rich, eclectic culture as a result.[PARAGRAPH:2]The development of Christian society and culture in the first 300 years following Islamic conquest in Spain was slow, but major changes occurred for the Spanish in the 12th and 13th centuries. The population grew, communication with northern Europe intensified, commerce and urban life gained in importance, and the kingdoms of Castile, Aragon, Navarre, and Portugal emerged as the governing bodies of the Iberian Peninsula. These kingdoms reached the frontiers that they would keep, with minimum amount of alteration, until the end of the Middle Ages, when Isabella I became Queen of Castile.[PARAGRAPH:2]Isabella began participating in the royal court at the age of 13; and when Portugal, Aragon, and France offered their marriage candidates, she favored Ferdinand of Aragon. Isabella ascended to the throne as Queen of Castile to rule sensibly and with a prudent political program. Her unification of the states of the Iberian Peninsula into a single entity, the maintenance and control over the Straits of Gibraltar, policy of expansion into Muslim North Africa, reform of Spanish Catholicism, and support for the exploration and expansion of the unknown were evidence of her wisdom and capabilities as Queen. In 1492 Columbus, with the blessing and financial backing of Isabella, sought a route to the legendary rich markets of China and Japan. He instead discovered what would become known as "The New World", the present day Americas. This voyage gave way to a new golden age of expeditions and conquest, as the Americas contained gold, a valuable resource that Spain happened to be desperately bereft of at the time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Spanish explorer Hernando Cortes came to the New World with the sole purpose of seeking out new frontiers and riches in the unknown. Men like Cortes became known as Conquistadores, adventurers who undertook their expeditions in the vast landmasses of the Americas at their own expense, risking their lives without aid from the Spanish royalty. Their conquests included campaigns in Guatemala, Peru, Cuzco, Columbia, Chile, the Bay of Honduras, and as far as the Pacific coastal regions. The Conquistadors, however, were given to fighting and searching for gold, and were swiftly replaced by administrators and settlers from Spain who governed in their place.[PARAGRAPH:2]The twin forces of disease and conquest combined to devastate the indigenous peoples of the Americas, allowing the Spaniards to carve out an enormous empire comprising most of North and South America. Many of the Spanish colonies proved to yield fabulous wealth in the form of gold and sugar, but working conditions were so harsh that large numbers of Africans were brought across the Atlantic as slaves to replace the Indians who had died working on the plantations. These lucrative operations inevitably became high-profile targets of pirates and other raiders who were endorsed by European powers such as England. The Monarchy of Spain endeavored to retaliate by building an armada of warships that was dubbed "The Invincible Armada". The armada was a collection of over 130 naval warships and transport-ships, which contained approximately 8,000 seamen and 19,000 soldiers. King Philip II (1556-98) directed this armada to invade England when the various and frequent raids on Spanish commerce in the Caribbean became intolerable. England's success in repelling the Spanish fleet saved England and the Netherlands from potential consolidation into the Spanish Empire, but despite the Armada's defeat, Spain remained temporarily the strongest land power in Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Spain declined in power quickly; the enormous influx of gold and silver from the Americas debased the Spanish currency, and most of the nation's military might was wasted in the quagmire of religious conflict known as the Thirty Years War (1618-48). By the beginning of the 18th century, Spain had become somewhat marginal in international politics, even though it continued to hold vast territories in the Americas. Spain's period of imperial power and exploration left a legacy that consisted of 18 nations in Latin American, the Spanish presence in the Phillipines, and the ever-growing Spanish-speaking population in the United States today. It is also due to the work of Jesuit missionaries from Spain that hundreds of millions of people in Latin America practice Roman Catholicism to this day. In 1975 Spain transitioned into a constitutional monarchy by way of a democratic constitution and is now recognized for its eclectic culture as well as for the glory and mystique that it once possessed in its youth.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]西班牙王国位于欧洲大陆的最西南部，占据伊比利亚半岛约85%的面积。西班牙西部与葡萄牙接壤，东北部与法国接壤，并与比利牛斯山脉长城接壤。西班牙所居住的伊比利亚半岛曾被包括腓尼基人、迦太基人、罗马人、西哥特人和穆斯林在内的各种文明所占领，西班牙现在与拥有一个非常富有的国家联系在一起，因此，在伊斯兰征服西班牙后的头300年里，基督教社会和文化的发展是缓慢的，但在12世纪和13世纪，西班牙发生了重大变化。人口增长，与北欧的交流加强，商业和城市生活变得重要，卡斯蒂利亚、阿拉贡、纳瓦拉和葡萄牙王国成为伊比利亚半岛的管理机构。这些王国以最少的改动达到了他们将要保留的疆界，直到中世纪结束，伊莎贝拉一世成为卡斯蒂利亚女王。[第2段]伊莎贝拉13岁开始参加皇家宫廷；葡萄牙、阿拉贡和法国提出了他们的婚姻候选人，她喜欢阿拉贡的费迪南德。伊莎贝拉以卡斯蒂利亚女王的身份登上王位，以明智的方式和审慎的政治计划进行统治。她将伊比利亚半岛各国统一为一个单一的实体，维护和控制直布罗陀海峡，扩大到穆斯林北非的政策，改革西班牙天主教，支持探索和扩大未知领域，这些都证明了她作为女王的智慧和能力。1492年，哥伦布在伊莎贝拉的祝福和资金支持下，寻找通往中国和日本富有传奇色彩的市场之路。相反，他发现了所谓的“新世界”，即今天的美洲。这次航行让位给了一个新的探险和征服的黄金时代，因为美洲蕴藏着黄金，这是一种当时西班牙正极度缺乏的宝贵资源。像科尔特斯这样的人被称为征服者，冒险者在没有西班牙皇室援助的情况下，冒着生命危险，自费前往美洲的广大大陆探险。他们的征服包括在危地马拉、秘鲁、库斯科、哥伦比亚、智利、洪都拉斯湾以及太平洋沿岸地区的战役。然而，征服者被赋予战斗和寻找黄金的权利，很快被西班牙的管理者和定居者所取代，他们在自己的地方进行统治。[第2段]疾病和征服的双重力量共同摧毁了美洲土著人民，允许西班牙人建立一个包括北美和南美大部分地区的庞大帝国。事实证明，许多西班牙殖民地以黄金和糖的形式创造了惊人的财富，但工作条件非常恶劣，大量非洲人被带到大西洋彼岸，成为奴隶，以取代在种植园工作的印第安人。这些有利可图的行动不可避免地成为海盗和其他袭击者的高调目标，这些海盗和袭击者得到了英国等欧洲大国的支持。西班牙君主制试图通过建造一艘被称为“无敌无敌无敌无敌舰队”的军舰来报复。无敌舰队由130多艘军舰和运输舰组成，约有8000名海员和19000名士兵。菲利普二世国王（1556-1998）指挥这支舰队入侵英国，当时加勒比地区对西班牙商业的各种频繁袭击变得无法容忍。英国成功击退西班牙舰队，使英格兰和荷兰免于可能并入西班牙帝国，但尽管无敌舰队战败，西班牙仍暂时成为欧洲最强大的陆地强国；来自美洲的黄金和白银的大量涌入使西班牙货币贬值，该国的大部分军事力量被浪费在被称为30年战争（1618-48）的宗教冲突的泥潭中。到了18世纪初，西班牙在国际政治中已经变得有些边缘化，尽管它继续在美洲拥有广阔的领土。西班牙的帝国权力和探索时期留下了一笔遗产，包括拉丁美洲的18个国家、菲利宾人中的西班牙人，以及今天美国不断增长的西班牙语人口。也正是由于来自西班牙的耶稣会传教士的工作，拉丁美洲数亿人至今信奉罗马天主教。1975年，西班牙通过民主宪法过渡到君主立宪制，现在因其折衷的文化以及它年轻时曾经拥有的荣耀和神秘而得到承认。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Spain -->
  <!-- Civilization Norse -->
  <!--<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>The Norse</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Les Scandinaves</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavier:Die Skandinavier:den Skandinaviern</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Male:Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1:1:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Gli Scandinavi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Los Escandinavos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>Os Escandinavos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Norse</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Scandinavie</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavien</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Scandinavia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Escandinavia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>Escandinvia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Norse:Norse</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>scandinave:scandinave:scandinaves:scandinaves</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavisch:skandinavischen:skandinavische</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>scandinavo:scandinava:scandinavi:scandinave</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>escandinavo:escandinava:escandinavos:escandinavas</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>escandinavo:escandinava:escandinavos:escandinavas</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]More properly known as Scandinavians or Norsemen, the Vikings were a group of people from northern Europe who became famous for carrying out a series of raids across the continent between roughly 800 - 1050 AD. The period is sometimes known as the "Viking Age," and it was an era of chaos and disruption for large parts of Europe. The Vikings can be classified into three main groups: the Danes largely attacked England; the Norwegians visited Scotland, Ireland, and points further west; while the Swedes invaded the river systems of what is now Russia. Although the Vikings usually employed hit and run tactics, many of them settled in new communities in the areas they had subjugated, eventually mixing with the local population. And while the Vikings are thought today to be bloodthirsty brigands, they probably acted more often as commercial traders than as warriors.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Historians debate the reason why the Vikings suddenly emerged from Scandinavia at the end of the eighth century AD and began preying upon other parts of Europe. Theories include: the Vikings were suffering overpopulation caused by better agricultural tools; that the unification of Norway led to an excess of idle warriors; the Vikings were reacting to attempts by the Franks to muscle them out of trade with the east; or that the men went off to raid and pillage out of simple boredom. One particularly interesting theory is that the climate of Europe was warmer during the early Middle Ages, leading to an excess population in Scandinavia and the subsequent Viking colonization of places such as Iceland and Greenland.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Whatever the actual reason for their expansion, the Viking drive outward began with the sacking of the important island monastery of Lindisfarne, located off the coast of Britain, in 793 AD. England was regularly raided by the Danes in the following decade, and in 865 a major invasion landed in East Anglia. This force was led by several landless Viking kings; in the battles that followed most of the English kingdoms were defeated, but the state of Wessex under Alfred the Great managed to hold the invaders off. The Vikings settled in Northumbria, and their territory became known as the "Danela" (most of these Vikings were Danes).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Another wave of Vikings landed in England in 947 under the command of Erik Bloodaxe, who managed to capture the city of York. Vikings would largely remain in control of England until the Norman invasion of 1066 - and the Normans were themselves the French descendents of Vikings. Scotland and Ireland also experienced a heavy Norwegian Viking presence at this time; a number of important cities were founded by them - including Dublin. Eventually the Vikings settled down and intermarried with the native Irish.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]The main target for Viking aggression, however, was France. All throughout the ninth century the Vikings sailed up and down the Seine River with impunity, sacking French towns and monasteries at their leisure. Finally the French king Charles the Simple made an agreement with the Viking leader Hrolf Ganger in 911, in which Hrolf was granted control over territory in northern France. In exchange, Hrolf and his men agreed to convert to Christianity and become vassals of the French king. Hrolf's name was changed to Rollo and he became duke of the province of Normandy (named for the Norsemen who settled in it). The Normans retained their martial edge even after conversion to Christianity, and would go on to make a number of important conquests in England, the Mediterranean, and during the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]The exploits of the Viking sailors were the stuff of legend. Viking mariners found their way to Iceland, Greenland, and even Newfoundland in North America, setting up colonies in all of these locations. Viking longboats were both fast and seaworthy, and their shallow drafts allowed them to sail far up the river systems of Europe. The Vikings could strike from the sea and be gone again before the military forces of a kingdom could be marshaled to meet them. In the east, the Swedes traveled down the rivers of modern Russia and founded the state of Kievan Rus', which grew rich off the river trade between the Baltic and the Byzantine Empire. These Vikings also found employment as mercenaries within the Byzantine domains, and their most elite warriors found employment in the Byzantine Varangian Guard. The Viking Age finally came to a close around 1050AD, as the Vikings were incorporated into Christian Europe and settled down to the less exciting but more stable pursuits of agriculture and fishing; their reputation as fierce invaders from the sea has endured to this day.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Plus connus, et &#224; juste titre, comme des Scandinaves ou des Normands, les Vikings constituent un peuple issu du nord de l'Europe et rendu c&#233;l&#232;bre par ses raids sur le continent entre 800 et 1050 ap. J.-C. Cette p&#233;riode, parfois appel&#233;e "l'&#226;ge viking", est caract&#233;ris&#233;e par le chaos et le bouleversement dans de grandes parties de l'Europe. Les Vikings peuvent &#234;tre class&#233;s en trois groupes principaux : les Danois, qui attaquent essentiellement la Grande-Bretagne ; les Norv&#233;giens qui se rendent en Ecosse, en Irlande et dans divers lieux plus &#224; l'ouest ; et enfin les Su&#233;dois qui envahissent les am&#233;nagements fluviaux de l'actuelle Russie. Si les Vikings emploient souvent des tactiques &#233;clair, bon nombre d'entre eux s'installent dans de nouvelles communaut&#233;s dans les territoires qu'ils conqui&#232;rent, finissant par se m&#233;langer avec la population locale. M&#234;me si, aujourd'hui, on consid&#232;re souvent les Vikings comme des brigands sanguinaires, ils ont sans doute agi plus souvent comme des commer&#231;ants que comme des guerriers.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]La raison de l'&#233;mergence soudaine des Vikings &#224; partir de la Scandinavie, &#224; la fin du VIIIe si&#232;cle ap. J.-C. et du d&#233;but de leurs assauts sur d'autres r&#233;gions d'Europe est l'objet de controverses entre les historiens. Selon les diverses th&#233;ories : les Vikings auraient &#233;t&#233; victimes d'une surpopulation en raison de l'am&#233;lioration des outils agricoles ; l'unification de la Norv&#232;ge aurait conduit &#224; un exc&#232;s de guerriers inactifs ; les Vikings auraient r&#233;agi aux tentatives des Francs de les exclure du commerce avec l'Est ; les hommes auraient organis&#233; des raids et des pillages pour simplement mettre fin &#224; leur ennui. L'une des th&#233;ories est particuli&#232;rement int&#233;ressante : le climat de l'Europe se serait adouci au d&#233;but du Moyen Age, ce qui aurait entra&#238;n&#233; une surpopulation en Scandinavie et par cons&#233;quent la colonisation par les Vikings de territoires tels que l'Islande et le Groenland.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Quelle que soit la raison de leur expansion, l'offensive des Vikings commence avec le pillage de l'important monast&#232;re insulaire de Lindisfarne, situ&#233; au large des c&#244;tes britanniques, en 793 ap. J.-C. L'Angleterre est r&#233;guli&#232;rement la cible de raids par les Danois dans la d&#233;cennie suivante et en 865, une importante flotte accoste dans l'est de l'Angleterre. Ces forces sont dirig&#233;es par plusieurs rois vikings n'ayant aucune terre. Au cours des batailles qui s'ensuivent, la majorit&#233; des royaumes britanniques est vaincue, except&#233; l'Etat de Wessex, dirig&#233; par Alfred le Grand, qui r&#233;ussit &#224; repousser les envahisseurs. Les Vikings s'installent en Northumbrie, et leur territoire est alors connu comme le "Danelaw" (les Danois constituent la majorit&#233; des Vikings).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Une autre vague de Vikings arrive en Angleterre en 947 sous la direction d'Erik Bloodaxe ("&#224; la hache sanglante"), qui r&#233;ussit &#224; s'emparer de la ville de York. Les Vikings contr&#244;lent une grande partie de l'Angleterre jusqu'&#224; l'invasion normande de 1066, les Normands &#233;tant eux-m&#234;mes les descendants fran&#231;ais des Vikings. L'Ecosse et l'Irlande connaissent &#233;galement &#224; cette &#233;poque une forte pr&#233;sence de Vikings norv&#233;giens, qui fondent de nombreuses grandes villes, comme Dublin. Finalement, les Vikings s'installent et se marient avec les Irlandais natifs.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Cependant, la principale cible des agressions vikings est la France. Pendant tout le IXe si&#232;cle, les Vikings remontent et descendent la Seine en toute impunit&#233;, saccageant &#224; loisir les villes et monast&#232;res fran&#231;ais. Le roi de France Charles le Simple finit par signer en 911 un accord avec le chef viking Hrolf Ganger selon lequel ce dernier obtient le contr&#244;le du territoire dans le nord de la France. En &#233;change, Hrolf et ses hommes acceptent de se convertir au christianisme et de devenir des vassaux du roi fran&#231;ais. Hrolf est rebaptis&#233; Rollon et devient duc de la province de Normandie (dont le nom vient des Normands qui s'y &#233;taient install&#233;s). Les Normands conservent leur esprit guerrier m&#234;me apr&#232;s leur conversion au christianisme, et effectuent de nombreuses conqu&#234;tes importantes en Angleterre, en M&#233;diterran&#233;e et pendant les croisades.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Les exploits des navigateurs vikings alimentent la l&#233;gende. Les marins vikings trouvent une voie vers l'Islande, le Groenland et m&#234;me Terre-Neuve en Am&#233;rique du Nord, installant des colonies dans tous ces territoires. Les drakkars vikings sont non seulement rapides mais tiennent aussi la mer, tandis que leur tirant d'eau peu profond leur permet de remonter de nombreux fleuves en Europe. Les Vikings peuvent frapper depuis la mer et dispara&#238;tre avant m&#234;me que les forces militaires d'un royaume ne soient rassembl&#233;es pour les affronter. A l'Est, les Su&#233;dois remontent les fleuves de l'actuelle Russie et fondent l'Etat Rus' de Kiev, qui s'enrichit gr&#226;ce au commerce fluvial entre la mer Baltique et l'Empire byzantin. Ces Vikings cr&#233;ent &#233;galement des postes de mercenaires dans la garde var&#232;gue byzantine. L'&#226;ge viking finit par s'achever vers 1050 ap. J.-C., lorsque les Vikings sont int&#233;gr&#233;s &#224; l'Europe chr&#233;tienne et qu'ils s'installent pour vivre d'activit&#233;s moins prometteuses mais plus stables telles que l'agriculture et la p&#234;che. Leur r&#233;putation de f&#233;roces envahisseurs de la mer a cependant perdur&#233; jusqu'&#224; aujourd'hui.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die auch als Skandinavier oder Nordmnner bekannten Wikinger lebten in Stammesverbnden in Nordeuropa und waren in der Zeit um etwa 800-1050 nach Christus fr ihre Raubzge auf dem ganzen Kontinent berhmt-berchtigt. Diese Periode wird manchmal auch als "Wikingerzeitalter" bezeichnet und war durch Chaos und Unruhen in groen Teilen Europas geprgt. Allgemein lassen sich die Wikinger in drei Hauptgruppen unterteilen: Die Dnen trieben vorwiegend in England ihr Unwesen, die Norweger in Schottland, Irland und den weiter westlich gelegenen Gebieten und die Schweden fielen ber das dortige Flusssystem in die Region des heutigen Russland ein. Obwohl die Wikinger in der Regel die so genannte "Hit and Run"-Taktik anwandten, wurden doch viele von ihnen in neuen Lebensgemeinschaften in den eroberten Gebieten ansssig und mischten sich schlielich mit der rtlichen Bevlkerung. Heute werden sie vorwiegend als blutrnstige Briganten dargestellt, tatschlich waren sie jedoch in erster Linie als Handelstreibende ttig und weniger als Krieger.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Unter Historikern ist es umstritten, warum die Wikinger gegen Ende des 8. Jahrhunderts pltzlich aus Skandinavien aufbrachen und in andere Teile Europas einfielen. Entsprechend wurden zu diesem Thema unterschiedliche Theorien aufgestellt: Die Wikinger litten aufgrund ihrer fortschrittlichen landwirtschaftlichen Technologien unter bervlkerung; die Einigung Norwegens fhrte zu einem berschuss unttiger Krieger; die Wikinger reagierten auf das von den Franken provozierte Krftemessen im Kampf um die Vorherrschaft bei den Handelsaktivitten mit dem Osten; und schlielich: Die Mnner schwrmten aus reiner Langeweile zu ihren berfllen und Plnderungen aus. Eine besonders interessante Theorie besagt allerdings, dass es im frhen Mittelalter wegen des milderen Klimas in Europa zu einer bervlkerung in Skandinavien kam und die Wikinger daher neue Siedlungsgebiete in Island und Grnland erschlieen mussten.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Was auch immer der tatschliche Anlass fr ihre Expansionsbestrebungen gewesen sein mag, fest steht, dass die Wikinger zunchst einmal im Jahr 793 die bedeutende Klosterinsel Lindisfarne an der englischen Kste eroberten. Im darauf folgenden Jahrzehnt wurde England regelm溥ig von den Dnen berfallen und im Jahr 865 begann schlielich der von verschiedenen heimatlosen Wikingerknigen angefhrte groe Einmarsch in das Knigreich Ostanglien. In den nun folgenden Schlachten wurden die meisten angelschsischen Knigreiche erfolgreich geschlagen, einzig das Knigreich Wessex unter Alfred dem Groen schaffte es, die Invasoren abzuwehren. Nachdem die Wikinger sich schlielich in Northumbrien angesiedelt hatten, wurde dieses Gebiet in "Danelag" umbenannt (da es sich bei den Eroberern vorwiegend um dnische Wikinger handelte).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Im Jahr 947 folgte eine weitere Angriffswelle der Wikinger in England, diesmal angefhrt von Erik Blutaxt, der die Stadt York einnahm. Die Wikinger beherrschten nun groe Teile Englands, bis zur Invasion der Normannen im Jahr 1066, die ihrerseits selbst franzsischstmmige Nachfahren der Wikinger waren. In dieser Periode waren die norwegischen Wikinger in Schottland und Irland allgegenwrtig und grndeten mehrere bedeutende Stdte, darunter auch Dublin. Nach und nach wurden die Wikinger in dieser Region vollends heimisch und verbanden sich schlielich durch Heirat mit den gebrtigen Iren.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Das Hauptziel der wikingischen Aggressoren war jedoch Frankreich. Whrend des gesamten 9. Jahrhunderts befuhren die Wikinger ungehindert die Seine und eroberten franzsische Stdte und Klster, wie es ihnen gerade passte. Schlielich schloss der franzsische Knig Karl der Einfltige im Jahr 911 einen Vertrag mit dem Wikingerfhrer Hrolf Ganger, in dem er ihm die Abtretung Nordfrankreichs zusicherte. Im Gegenzug willigten Hrolf und seine Mnner ein, zum Christentum zu konvertieren und Vasallen des franzsischen Knigs zu werden. Hrolf nderte seinen Namen in Rollo und wurde Herzog der Provinz Normandie (nach den "Nordmnnern" benannt, die sich dort ansiedelten). Aber auch nach ihrem Bekenntnis zum Christentum blieben die Normannen ihrem kriegerischen Wesen treu: Sie machten weiterhin bedeutende Eroberungen in England und dem Mittelmeerraum ebenso wie whrend der Kreuzzge.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Die Heldentaten der wikingischen Seefahrer sind legendr. Diese unerschrockenen Seeleute fuhren bis nach Island, Grnland und sogar Neufundland vor der nordamerikanischen Kste und errichteten berall Kolonien. Die Langboote der Wikinger waren schnell und hochseetauglich, gleichzeitig ermglichte ihr geringer Tiefgang aber auch das Befahren der europischen Flsse. So waren die Wikinger in der Lage, von der Seeseite her anzugreifen und lngst wieder verschwunden zu sein, bevor die Militrtruppen eines Knigreichs auch nur herbeigerufen werden konnten. Im Osten nutzten die schwedischen Wikinger das dortige Flusssystem, um bis in das Gebiet des heutigen Russlands vorzudringen. Hier grndeten sie das Reich der Kiewer Rus, das dank des florierenden Flusshandels zwischen den Balten und dem Byzantinischen Reich schnell zu Wohlstand gelangte. Einige dieser Wikinger verdingten sich wiederum als Sldner in byzantinischen Hoheitsgebieten, ihre Elitekrieger wurden sogar in die Wargergarde des byzantinischen Kaisers aufgenommen. Das Ende der Wikingerzeit wird etwa um 1050 nach Christus datiert. Zu diesem Zeitpunkt hatten sich die Wikinger mehr und mehr in das christliche Europa eingegliedert und waren sesshaft geworden, um weniger aufregenden, dafr aber etwas bestndigeren Ttigkeiten in der Landwirtschaft und im Fischereigewerbe nachzukommen. Ihr Ruf als wildes, kmpferisches Seefahrervolk hat jedoch bis zum heutigen Tage berdauert.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Pi&#249; propriamente noti come scandinavi o nordici, i Vichinghi furono un popolo dell'Europa settentrionale divenuto famoso per le serie di incursioni condotte pi&#249; o meno tra l'800 e il 1050 d.C., periodo talvolta detto &quot;era dei Vichinghi&quot; e in cui il caos e la devastazione dominarono in vaste aree del continente. I Vichinghi si possono dividere in tre gruppi: i Danesi, che attaccarono principalmente l'Inghilterra; i Norvegesi, che invasero la Scozia, l'Irlanda e altri territori pi&#249; a ovest; e gli Svedesi, che invasero il bacino dell'odierna Russia. Anche se i Vichinghi spesso adottavano la strategia del mordi e fuggi, molti di loro finirono per insediarsi nelle aree colpite e per mescolarsi con le popolazioni locali. E anche se oggi i Vichinghi hanno fama d'essere stati pirati assetati di sangue, le loro attivit&#224; avevano probabilmente una natura pi&#249; commerciale che militare.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Gli storici ancora discutono sulle cause dell'improvviso sorgere in Scandinavia alla fine del VII secolo d.C. della civilt&#224; dei Vichinghi e delle loro incursioni predatorie in Europa. Alcuni credono che i Vichinghi fossero afflitti da sovrappopolazione (a causa dei migliori strumenti agricoli adottati negli ultimi tempi); altri che l'unificazione della Norvegia avesse portato a un soprannumero di guerrieri inattivi; o che quella dei Vichinghi sia stata una reazione al tentativo dei Franchi di estrometterli dal commercio con l'oriente; o ancora che le incursioni fossero il risultato di semplice noia da parte degli uomini. Una teoria degna di nota &#232; che nel Medioevo il clima dell'Europa settentrionale fosse pi&#249; mite e che ci?abbia determinato prima un problema di sovrappopolazione in Scandinavia e poi la colonizzazione dell'Islanda e della Groenlandia.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Quale che fosse la causa dell'espansionismo dei Vichinghi, la loro avventura inizi?col saccheggio del monastero di Lindisfarne, su un'isola al largo delle coste britanniche, nel 793 d.C. Nel decennio successivo l'Inghilterra fu regolarmente vittima di incursioni da parte dei Danesi, finch&#233; nell'865 nella regione dell'East Anglia non sbarc?una vera e propria invasione guidata da diversi re vichinghi senza una propria terra. Gli scontri successivi videro la sconfitta della maggior parte degli stati inglesi, salvo quello di Wessex, guidato da Alfredo il Grande, che riusc?a respingere gli invasori. I Vichinghi si insediarono nella regione di Northumbria, che venne ribattezzata &quot;Danela&quot; poich&#233; gran parte di questi vichinghi era danese.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Nel 947 segu?un'altra invasione sotto il comando di Erik Ascia-di-sangue, che riusc?a conquistare anche la citt&#224; di York. I Vichinghi mantennero il controllo dell'Inghilterra fino all'invasione dei normanni (discendenti francesi dei Vichinghi stessi) del 1066. Nello stesso periodo, Scozia e Irlanda sperimentarono una massiccia presenza di Norvegesi, ai quali si deve la fondazione di molte importanti citt&#224;, tra cui Dublino. I Norvegesi finirono per insediarsi e mescolarsi con la nativa popolazione degli Irlandesi.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]L'obiettivo principale dell'assalto vichingo fu per?la Francia. Per tutto il IX secolo i Vichinghi spadroneggiarono impuniti lungo la Senna, saccheggiando senza incontrare ostacoli citt&#224; e monasteri, finch&#233; il re dei Francesi Carlo il Semplice non si accord?col capo vichingo Hrolf Ganger nel 911, cedendogli il controllo della Francia settentrionale. In cambio, Hrolf e i suoi uomini accettarono di convertirsi al cristianesimo e di diventare vassalli del re di Francia. Il nome Hrolf si mut?in Rollo ed egli divenne il duca di Normandia (che prende il nome dagli occupanti norvegesi). Nonostante la conversione al cristianesimo, i normanni non mutarono la propria predisposizione agli scontri bellici e difatti furono protagonisti di molte importanti conquiste in Inghilterra, nel Mediterraneo e nel corso delle crociate.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Le imprese dei marinai vichinghi furono tali da assumere dimensioni leggendarie: furono essi a trovare le rotte per l'lslanda, la Groenlandia e per l'isola di Terranova in Nord America (luoghi tutti in cui fondarono delle colonie). Le navi vichinghe erano sia veloci sia resistenti e la relativa piattezza della loro parte inferiore permetteva anche la navigazione sui fiumi europei. I Vichinghi potevano attaccare via mare e salpare via prima ancora che lo stato colpito organizzasse una risposta armata. A est, gli Svedesi navigarono lungo i fiumi della odierna Russia o fondarono lo stato di Kievan Rus', che si arricch?grazie al traffico tra i territori del Mar Baltico e l'Impero bizantino. Alcuni di questi Vichinghi trovarono anche impiego come mercenari a difesa dei confini bizantini; i pi&#249; valorosi tra loro fecero parte del corpo d'elite delle guardie bizantine, i varangi. L'era dei vichinghi si concluse intorno al 1050 d.C., quando i vichinghi si possono considerare ormai in tutto e per tutto integrati nell'Europa cristiana e dediti alle meno eccitanti ma pi&#249; stabili occupazioni dell'agricoltura e della pesca, ma nonostante ci?la loro reputazione di feroci invasori dal mare &#232; rimasta viva fino a oggi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Conocidos tambi&#233;n como normandos, los vikingos eran una serie de pueblos procedentes del norte de Europa que se hicieron famosos por los ataques llevados a cabo por todo el continente en el perodo comprendido aproximadamente entre el 800 y 1050 d. C. Este perodo, conocido a veces como &quot;era vikinga&quot;, se caracteriz?en muchas partes de Europa por el caos y el desorden. Los vikingos se dividan en tres grandes grupos: los daneses centraron sus ataques principalmente en Inglaterra; los noruegos visitaron Escocia, Irlanda y algunas regiones situadas al oeste; y los suecos invadieron el sistema fluvial de lo que en nuestros das es Rusia. Aunque normalmente utilizaban t&#225;cticas de ataque fugaces, muchos de ellos establecieron comunidades nuevas en las &#225;reas sojuzgadas y acabaron por mezclarse con las poblaciones locales. Y, aunque hoy en da se tiene de ellos la imagen de saqueadores sanguinarios, lo m&#225;s probable es que en general actuasen m&#225;s como mercaderes que como guerreros.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Los historiadores debaten las razones que los llevaron a salir de Escandinavia a finales del siglo VIII d. C. y a empezar sus ataques a otras regiones de Europa. Hay diversas teoras: que Escandinavia sufra una superpoblacin provocada por el desarrollo del instrumental agrcola; que la unificacin de Noruega haba provocado la existencia de un exceso de guerreros sin nada que hacer; que se trataba de una reaccin de los intentos de los francos por impedirles acceder al comercio de las regiones orientales; o que los hombres se dedicaban al pillaje y al saqueo por puro aburrimiento. Una teora especialmente interesante es la que asegura que el clima de Europa era m&#225;s c&#225;lido durante la Edad Media, lo que produjo un exceso de poblacin en Escandinavia y la consiguiente colonizacin de regiones como Islandia y Groenlandia.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Pero al margen de la razn ltima de su expansin, lo que sabemos con certeza es que la expansin vikinga se inici?con el saqueo del importante monasterio de Lindisfarne, situado en una isla de la costa de Inglaterra, en el 793 d. C. En la siguiente d&#233;cada, Inglaterra sufri?los constantes saqueos de los daneses y, en el ao 865, una invasin en toda regla desembarc?en Anglia oriental. Este ej&#233;rcito estaba dirigido por varios reyes sin tierra; en las batallas que se produjeron a continuacin, la mayora de los reinos ingleses fueron derrotados, pero el estado de Wessex, bajo el mando de Alfredo el Grande, logr?contener a los invasores. Los vikingos se instalaron en Nortumbria, territorio que pas?a conocerse como &quot;Danela&quot; (pues la mayora de los invasores eran daneses).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Otra oleada de vikingos, bajo el mando de Erik Hacha Sangrienta, desembarc?en la isla en el ao 947 y logr?capturar la ciudad de York. Los vikingos mantendran bajo su control la mayor parte de Inglaterra hasta la invasin normanda de 1066, y hay que recordar que estos normandos eran a su vez los descendientes de los vikingos asentados en Francia. A estas alturas, Escocia e Irlanda haban soportado tambi&#233;n una importante presencia de vikingos noruegos. Muchas ciudades importantes, Dubln incluida, fueron fundadas por ellos. Con el paso del tiempo, los vikingos acabaron por mezclarse con los irlandeses nativos.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Sin embargo, el objetivo principal de los ataques vikingos fue Francia. A lo largo de todo el siglo IX, los vikingos navegaron con impunidad por el ro Sena y saquearon a su antojo los pueblos y monasterios de la regin. Finalmente, en el ao 911, el rey franco Carlos el Simple lleg?a un acuerdo con el lder vikingo Hrolf Ganger en el que le conceda el control del norte de Francia. A cambio, Hrolf y sus hombres se comprometan a convertirse al cristianismo y a jurar fidelidad al rey franco como vasallos. Hrolf se cambi?el nombre por el de Rollo y adopt?el ttulo de duque de Normanda (bautizada as?por los normandos que se asentaron en ella). Los normandos no abandonaron su cultura guerrera a pesar de su conversin al cristianismo, y continuaron realizando importantes conquistas en Inglaterra, el Mediterr&#225;neo y el Levante (durante las Cruzadas).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Las hazaas de los marinos vikingos son legendarias. Parece ser que llegaron hasta Islandia, Groenlandia e incluso el Labrador, en Norteam&#233;rica, y fundaron colonias en todas estas regiones. Sus barcos, adem&#225;s de ser r&#225;pidos y muy marineros, posean un escaso calado que les permita adentrarse profundamente en los sistemas fluviales de Europa. Los vikingos podan atacar desde el mar y retirarse antes de que las fuerzas armadas de un reino pudieran reunirse para ofrecer resistencia. Al este, los suecos viajaron por los ros de la moderna Rusia y fundaron el estado de Kievan Rus, que se hizo rico gracias al comercio entre el B&#225;ltico y el Imperio Bizantino. Adem&#225;s, estos vikingos se emplearon como mercenarios en las tierras de los bizantinos y sus formidables guerreros formaron la guardia varega de los emperadores de Bizancio. La era vikinga lleg?a su fin alrededor del 1050, cuando los vikingos terminaron de incorporarse a la Europa cristiana y empezaron a dedicarse a las tareas, menos excitantes pero m&#225;s estables, de la agricultura y la pesca. Sin embargo, su reputacin de feroces invasores ha perdurado hasta nuestros das.</Spanish>
 	</TEXT>-->
  <!-- Civilization Norse -->
  <!-- Civilization Norway -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Norwegians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>挪威文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Norway</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>挪威</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Norwegian:Norwegians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>挪威</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The looting of the monastery at Lindisfarne in Northeast England on 8 January 793 by 'harrowing inroads of heathen men' has long been regarded as the event which marked the beginning of the Viking Age. The Viking Age was characterised by expansion and emigration by Viking seafarers. According to tradition, Harald Fairhair (Harald Hrfagre) unified them into one in 872 after the Battle of Hafrsfjord in Stavanger, thus becoming the first king of a united Norway. (The date of 872 may be somewhat arbitrary. In fact, the actual date may be just prior to 900). Harald's realm was mainly a South Norwegian coastal state. Harald Fairhair ruled with a strong hand and according to the sagas, many Norwegians left the country to live in Iceland, the Faroe Islands, Greenland, and parts of Britain and Ireland. The modern-day Irish cities of Dublin, Limerick and Waterford were founded by Norwegian settlers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Norse traditions were slowly replaced by Christian ones in the 10th and 11th centuries. This is largely attributed to the missionary kings Olav Tryggvasson and St. Olav. Haakon the Good was Norway's first Christian king, in the mid-10th century, though his attempt to introduce the religion was rejected. Born sometime in between 963-969, Olav Tryggvasson set off raiding in England with 390 ships. He attacked London during this raiding. Arriving back in Norway in 995, Olav landed in Moster. There he built a church which became the first Christian church ever built in Norway. From Moster, Olav sailed north to Trondheim where he was acclaimed King of Norway by the Eyrathing in 995.[PARAGRAPH:2]Feudalism never really developed in Norway and Sweden, as it did in the rest of Europe. However, the administration of government took on a very conservative feudal character. The Hanseatic League forced the royalty to cede to them greater and greater concessions over foreign trade and the economy. The League had this hold over the royalty because of the loans the Hansa had made to the royalty and the large debt the kings were carrying. The League's monopolistic control over the economy of Norway put pressure on all classes, especially the peasantry, to the degree that no real burgher class existed in Norway.[PARAGRAPH:2]Upon the death of Haakon V, King of Norway, in 1319, Magnus Erikson, at just three years old, inherited the throne as King Magnus VII of Norway. At the same time a movement to make Magnus King of Sweden proved successful. (At this time both the kings of Sweden and of Denmark were elected to the throne by their respective nobles.) Thus, with his election to the throne of Sweden, both Sweden and Norway were united under King Magnus VII.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1349, the Black Death radically altered Norway, killing between 50% and 60% of its population and leaving it in a period of social and economic decline. The plague left Norway very poor. Although the death rate was comparable with the rest of Europe, economic recovery took much longer because of the small, scattered population. Before the plague, the population was only about 500,000 people. After the plague, many farms lay idle while the population slowly increased. However, the few surviving farms' tenants found their bargaining positions with their landlords greatly strengthened.[PARAGRAPH:2]King Magnus VII ruled Norway until 1350, when his son, Haakon, was placed on the throne as Haakon VI. In 1363, Haakon VI married Margaret, the daughter of King Valdemar IV of Denmark. Upon the death of Haakon VI, in 1379, his son, Olaf IV, was only 10 years old. Olaf had already been elected to the throne of Denmark on 3 May 1376. Thus, upon Olaf's accession to the throne of Norway, Denmark and Norway entered personal union. Olaf's mother and Haakon's widow, Queen Margaret, managed the foreign affairs of Denmark and Norway during the minority of Olaf IV.[PARAGRAPH:2]Margaret was working toward a union of Sweden with Denmark and Norway by having Olaf elected to the Swedish throne. She was on the verge of achieving this goal when Olaf IV suddenly died. However, Denmark made Margaret temporary ruler upon the death of Olaf. On 2 February 1388 Norway followed suit and crowned Margaret. Queen Margaret knew that her power would be more secure if she were able to find a king to rule in her place. She settled on Eric of Pomerania, grandson of her sister. Thus at an all-Scandinavian meeting held at Kalmar, Erik of Pomerania was crowned king of all three Scandinavian countries. Thus, royal politics resulted in personal unions between the Nordic countries, eventually bringing the thrones of Norway, Denmark, and Sweden under the control of Queen Margaret when the country entered into the Kalmar Union.[PARAGRAPH:2]After Sweden broke out of the Kalmar Union in 1521, Norway tried to follow suit, but the ensuing rebellion was defeated, and Norway remained in a union with Denmark until 1814, a total of 436 years. During the national romanticism of the 19th century, this period was by some referred to as the "400-Year Night", since all of the kingdom's royal, intellectual, and administrative power was centred in Copenhagen in Denmark. In fact, it was a period of great prosperity and progress for Norway, especially in terms of shipping and foreign trade, and it also secured the country's revival from the demographic catastrophe it suffered in the Black Death. Based on the respective natural resources, Denmark-Norway was in fact a very good match, since Denmark supported Norway's needs for grain and food supplies, and Norway supplied Denmark with timber, metal, and fish.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the introduction of Protestantism in 1536, the archbishopric in Trondheim was dissolved, and Norway lost its independence, and effectually became a tributary to Denmark. The Church's incomes and possessions were instead redirected to the court in Copenhagen. Norway lost the steady stream of pilgrims to the relics of St. Olav at the Nidaros shrine, and with them, much of the contact with cultural and economic life in the rest of Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Eventually restored as a kingdom (albeit in legislative union with Denmark) in 1661, Norway saw its land area decrease in the 17th century with the loss of the provinces Bhuslen, Jemtland, and Herjedalen to Sweden, as the result of a number of disastrous wars with Sweden. In the north, however, its territory was increased by the acquisition of the northern provinces of Troms and Finnmark, at the expense of Sweden and Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]The famine of 1695-96 killed roughly 10% of Norway's population. The harvest failed in Scandinavia at least nine times between 1740 and 1800, with great loss of life.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>793年1月8日，英格兰东北部林迪斯法恩的修道院遭到“野蛮人的蹂躏”，长期以来被认为是标志着维京时代开始的事件。海盗时代的特点是海盗的扩张和移民。根据传统，哈拉尔德・费尔黑尔（Harald Hfagre）在斯塔万格（Stavanger）的哈弗峡湾战役后于872年将他们统一为一个国家，从而成为统一挪威的第一位国王。（872年的日期可能有些武断。事实上，实际日期可能刚好在900年之前）。哈拉尔德的领地主要是挪威南部沿海国家。Harald Fairhair统治强大的手，根据传说，许多挪威人离开该国居住在冰岛，法罗群岛，格陵兰岛和部分英国和爱尔兰。现代爱尔兰城市都柏林、利默里克和沃特福德是由挪威殖民者建立的。[第2段]挪威传统在10世纪和11世纪被基督教传统慢慢取代。这主要归功于传教士国王奥拉夫・特里格瓦松和圣奥拉夫。哈康善是挪威的第一个基督教国王，在10世纪中叶，虽然他试图引进宗教被拒绝。奥拉夫・特里格瓦松出生于963-969年间，他率领390艘战舰在英国发动了突袭。他在这次突袭中袭击了伦敦。奥拉夫于995年回到挪威，降落在莫斯特。在那里，他建造了一座教堂，成为挪威有史以来第一座基督教教堂。奥拉夫从莫斯特向北航行到特隆赫姆，在那里，他在995年被埃拉廷称颂为挪威国王。[第2段]封建主义在挪威和瑞典从未像在欧洲其他地方那样真正发展起来。然而，政府的管理却呈现出非常保守的封建性质。汉萨同盟迫使皇室在对外贸易和经济上给予他们越来越大的让步。由于汉莎向皇室贷款以及国王背负的巨额债务，联盟控制了皇室。联盟对挪威经济的垄断控制给所有阶级，特别是农民施加了压力，以至于挪威根本不存在真正的市民阶级。[第2段]1319年挪威国王哈肯五世去世后，年仅三岁的马格努斯・埃里克森继承了挪威国王马格努斯七世的王位。同时，瑞典国王马格努斯的运动也取得了成功。（此时，瑞典国王和丹麦国王都是由各自的贵族选出的）因此，随着他当选瑞典国王，瑞典和挪威在马格努斯七世统治下统一起来。[第2段]1349年，黑死病彻底改变了挪威，造成50%到60%的人口死亡，使其处于社会和经济衰退时期。瘟疫使挪威非常贫穷。尽管死亡率与欧洲其他国家相当，但由于人口稀少、分散，经济复苏的时间要长得多。在瘟疫爆发之前，人口只有50万左右。瘟疫过后，许多农场闲置，而人口却缓慢增加。然而，幸存下来的少数农场主发现，他们与地主的谈判地位大大加强了。[第2段]马格纳斯七世统治挪威，直到1350年，他的儿子哈肯作为哈肯六世登上王位。1363年，哈肯六世与丹麦国王瓦尔德马尔四世的女儿玛格丽特结婚。哈康六世死后，1379年，他的儿子奥拉夫四世才10岁。奥拉夫已于1376年5月3日当选丹麦王位。因此，在奥拉夫登上挪威王位时，丹麦和挪威结成了个人联盟。奥拉夫的母亲和哈肯的遗孀玛格丽特女王在奥拉夫四世的少数派时期管理丹麦和挪威的外交事务。[第2段]玛格丽特正通过让奥拉夫当选瑞典王位，努力实现瑞典与丹麦和挪威的统一。奥拉夫四世突然去世时，她正处于实现这一目标的边缘。然而，在奥拉夫死后，丹麦使玛格丽特成为临时统治者。1388年2月2日，挪威效仿，加冕玛格丽特。玛格丽特女王知道，如果她能找到一位国王接替她的位置，她的权力将更加稳固。她安顿在波美拉尼亚的埃里克，她姐姐的孙子。因此，在卡尔马举行的全斯堪的纳维亚会议上，波美拉尼亚的埃里克被加冕为三个斯堪的纳维亚国家的国王。因此，皇室政治导致了北欧国家之间的个人联合，最终使挪威、丹麦和瑞典的王位在玛格丽特女王加入卡尔玛联盟时处于其控制之下。[第2段]瑞典1521年脱离卡尔马联盟后，挪威试图效仿，但随后的叛乱被击败，挪威与丹麦保持联盟关系，直至1814年，共436年。在19世纪的国家浪漫主义时期，这一时期被一些人称为“400年之夜”，因为王国的所有皇室、知识和行政权力都集中在丹麦的哥本哈根。事实上，对挪威来说，这是一个非常繁荣和进步的时期，特别是在航运和对外贸易方面，它也使挪威从黑死病中遭受的人口灾难中复苏。基于各自的自然资源，丹麦-挪威事实上是一个很好的匹配，因为丹麦支持挪威对粮食和食品的需求，挪威向丹麦提供木材、金属和鱼类。[第2段]1536年，随着新教的引入，特隆赫姆大主教被解散，挪威失去了独立，实际上成为丹麦的一个附属国。教会的收入和财产被转移到哥本哈根的法院。挪威失去了源源不断的朝圣者到尼达罗斯神殿圣奥拉夫遗迹的踪迹，与他们接触的大部分是欧洲其他地区的文化和经济生活。[第2段]最终在1661年恢复为一个王国（尽管与丹麦处于立法联盟），挪威在17世纪的土地面积随着由于与瑞典的一系列灾难性战争，布斯伦省、杰姆特兰省和赫尔杰达伦省进入了瑞典。然而，在北方，它的领土被以牺牲瑞典和俄罗斯为代价的特罗姆斯和芬马克两个北部省份的占领而扩大。在1740年到1800年间，斯堪的纳维亚半岛的收成至少失败了9次，造成了巨大的生命损失。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Norway -->
  <!-- Civilization Denmark -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Danish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>丹麦文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Denmark</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>丹麦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Danish:Danish</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>丹麦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The unified kingdom of Denmark emerged in the 10th century as a proficient seafaring nation in the struggle for control of the Baltic Sea. Danish rule over the personal Kalmar Union, established in 1397 (over Norway and Sweden), ended with Swedish secession in 1523. However, Denmark still kept a union over Norway which lasted until its dissolution in 1814. Denmark inherited an expansive colonial empire from this union, of which the Faroe Islands and Greenland are remnants. Beginning in the 17th century, there were several cessions of territory; these culminated in the 1830s with a surge of nationalist movements, which were defeated in the 1864 Second Schleswig War. Denmark remained neutral during World War I. In April 1940, a German invasion saw brief military skirmishes while the Danish resistance movement was active from 1943 until the German surrender in May 1945. An industrialized exporter of agricultural produce in the second half of the 19th century, Denmark introduced social and labour-market reforms in the early 20th century, making the basis for the present welfare state model with a highly developed mixed economy.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Constitution of Denmark was signed on 5 June 1849, ending the absolute monarchy which had begun in 1660. It establishes a constitutional monarchy -the current monarch is Queen Margrethe II- organised as a parliamentary democracy. The government and national parliament are seated in Copenhagen, the nation's capital, largest city and main commercial centre. Denmark exercises hegemonic influence in the Danish Realm, devolving powers to handle internal affairs. Denmark became a member of the European Union in 1973, maintaining certain opt-outs; it retains its own currency, the krone. It is among the founding members of NATO, the Nordic Council, the OECD, OSCE, and the United Nations; it is also part of the Schengen Area.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]丹麦统一王国在10世纪作为一个精通航海的国家出现在波罗的海控制权的斗争中。丹麦对个人卡尔马联盟的统治，建立于1397年（对挪威和瑞典），结束于1523年瑞典分离。然而，丹麦仍然在挪威问题上保持着一种联盟，这种联盟一直持续到1814年解散。丹麦从这个联盟中继承了一个扩张的殖民帝国，法罗群岛和格陵兰岛是其中的残余。从17世纪开始，有几次领土割让；这些割让在19世纪30年代达到高潮，民族主义运动激增，在1864年的第二次石勒苏益格战争中被击败。丹麦在第一次世界大战期间保持中立。1940年4月，德国入侵时发生了短暂的军事冲突，而丹麦抵抗运动从1943年一直活跃到1945年5月德国投降。丹麦是19世纪下半叶农产品的工业化出口国，20世纪初开始实行社会和劳动力市场改革，为目前混合经济高度发达的福利国家模式奠定了基础1660年开始的君主制。它建立了君主立宪制――现任君主是玛格丽特二世女王――作为议会民主组织。政府和国家议会坐落在哥本哈根，这个国家的首都，最大的城市和主要的商业中心。丹麦在丹麦王国行使霸权影响力，下放处理内政的权力。丹麦于1973年成为欧盟成员国，保留了一定的退出权；丹麦保留了自己的货币克朗。它是北约、北欧理事会、经合组织、欧安组织和联合国的创始成员之一，也是申根地区的一部分。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Denmark -->
  <!-- Civilization Venezia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Venetians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>威尼斯文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Venezia</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>威尼斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Venetian:Venetians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>威尼斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The city of Venice originated as a collection of lagoon communities banded together for mutual defence from the Lombards as the power of the Byzantine Empire dwindled in northern Italy in the late seventh century. Sometime in the first decades of the eighth century, the people of the lagoon elected their first leader Ursus, who was confirmed by Byzantium and given the titles of hypatus and dux. He was the first historical Doge of Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the reign of the Participazio, Venice grew into its modern form. Though Heraclean by birth, Agnello, first doge of the family, was an early immigrant to Rialto and his dogeship was marked by the expansion of Venice towards the sea via the construction of bridges, canals, bulwarks, fortifications, and stone buildings. Agnello was succeeded by his son Giustiniano, who brought the body of Saint Mark the Evangelist to Venice from Alexandria and made him the patron saint of Venice. During the reign of the successor of the Participazio, Pietro Tradonico, Venice began to establish its military might which would influence many a later crusade and dominate the Adriatic for centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the High Middle Ages, Venice became extremely wealthy through its control of trade between Europe and the Levant, and began to expand into the Adriatic Sea and beyond. Venice was involved in the Crusades almost from the very beginning; Venetian ships assisted in capturing the coastal cities of Syria after the First Crusade, and in 1123 they were granted virtual autonomy in the Kingdom of Jerusalem through the Pactum Warmundi. In the 12th century the Venetians also gained extensive trading privileges in the Byzantine Empire and their ships often provided the Empire with a navy. The Venetian fleet was crucial to the transportation of the Fourth Crusade, but when the crusaders could not pay for the ships, the fleet was directed against Zara, a city on the Adriatic formerly under Venetian control. The crusade was then diverted to Constantinople, which was sacked in 1204. As a result of the partition of the Byzantine Empire which followed, Venice gained a great deal of territory in the Aegean Sea, including the islands of Crete and Euboea. Later, in 1489, the island of Cyprus, previously a crusader state, was annexed to Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the early fifteenth century, the Venetians also began to expand in Italy, as well as along the Dalmatian coast from Istria to Albania. By 1410, Venice had taken over most of Venetia, including such important cities as Verona and Padua.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1499 Venice allied itself with France against Milan, gaining Cremona. In the same year the Ottoman sultan moved to attack Lepanto by land, and sent a large fleet to support his offensive by sea. Antonio Grimani, more a businessman than a sailor, was defeated in the sea battle of Zonchio. Preferring peace to total war against the Turks, Venice surrendered the bases of Lepanto, Modon and Coron.[PARAGRAPH:2]Venice's attention was diverted from her usual maritime position by the delicate situation in northern Italy. Eager to take some of Venice's lands, all neighbouring powers joined in the League of Cambrai in 1508, under the leadership of Pope Julius II. The pope wanted Romagna, emperor Maximilian I Friuli and Veneto, Spain the Apulian ports, the king of France Cremona, the king of Hungary Dalmatia, and each of the others some part. The offensive against the huge army enlisted by Venice was launched from France. On 14 May 1509 Venice was crushingly defeated at the battle of Agnadello, in the Ghiara d'Adda, marking one of the most delicate points of the entire Venetian history. French and imperial troops were occupying the Veneto, but Venice managed to extricate herself through diplomatic efforts. The Apulian ports were ceded in order to come to terms with Spain, and pope Julius II soon recognized the danger brought by the eventual destruction of Venice (then the only Italian power able to face national states like France or the Ottomans). Andrea Gritti recaptured Padua in July 1509, successfully defending it against the besieging imperial troops. Spain and the pope broke off their alliance with France, and Venice regained Brescia and Verona. After seven years of ruinous war, the Serenissima regained her mainland dominions up to the Adda. Although the defeat had turned into a victory, the events of 1509 marked the end of the Venetian expansion.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]威尼斯城起源于7世纪末拜占庭帝国在意大利北部的势力逐渐减弱时，为了共同防御伦巴第人而聚集起来的泻湖社区。八世纪头几十年的某个时候，泻湖的人民选出了他们的第一任领导人乌尔苏，他被拜占庭确认，并被授予了海皮塔斯和杜克斯的称号。他是威尼斯的第一个历史教条。[第2段]在帕西帕齐奥统治时期，威尼斯发展成为现代形式。虽然赫拉克林出生，阿格内洛，家庭的第一个狗，是一个早期移民到里亚尔托和他的狗的标志是通过建造桥梁，运河，防波堤，防御工事和石头建筑的威尼斯向大海扩展。阿格尼洛的继承人是他的儿子朱斯蒂尼亚诺，他把传福音者圣马可的遗体从亚历山大带到威尼斯，并使他成为威尼斯的守护神。在参与者皮埃特罗・特拉多尼科（Pietro Tradonico）的继任者统治期间，威尼斯开始建立其军事力量，这将影响许多后来的十字军东征，并统治亚得里亚海几个世纪。[第2段]在中世纪晚期，威尼斯通过控制欧洲和黎凡特之间的贸易变得极其富有，开始向亚得里亚海和更远的地方扩张。威尼斯几乎从一开始就参与了十字军东征；威尼斯船只在第一次十字军东征后协助占领了叙利亚的沿海城市，并在1123年通过Pactum Warmundi获得了耶路撒冷王国的实际自治权。在12世纪，威尼斯人在拜占庭帝国也获得了广泛的贸易特权，他们的船只经常为帝国提供海军。威尼斯舰队对第四次十字军东征的运输至关重要，但当十字军无法支付船只的费用时，该舰队的目标是扎拉，一个以前由威尼斯控制的亚得里亚海城市。十字军东征随后转移到君士坦丁堡，于1204年被洗劫。由于随后拜占庭帝国的分裂，威尼斯在爱琴海获得了大量领土，包括克里特岛和尤波亚岛。后来，在1489年，塞浦路斯岛，以前是一个十字军国家，被并入威尼斯。[第2段]在15世纪初，威尼斯人也开始在意大利扩张，并沿着达尔马提亚海岸从伊斯特拉到阿尔巴尼亚。到1410年，威尼斯已经占领了威尼斯的大部分地区，包括维罗纳和帕多瓦等重要城市。[第2段]1499年，威尼斯与法国结盟对抗米兰，获得克里莫纳。同年，奥斯曼苏丹开始从陆路进攻勒潘托，并派出一支庞大的舰队支持他的海上进攻。安东尼奥・格里马尼，与其说是个水手，不如说是个商人，在宗丘海战中被打败了。威尼斯宁愿和平，也不愿对土耳其人发动全面战争，因此放弃了莱潘托、莫顿和科隆的基地。[第2段]意大利北部的微妙局势转移了威尼斯的注意力，使她偏离了通常的海上位置。由于渴望夺取威尼斯的一些土地，1508年，在教皇朱利叶二世的领导下，所有邻国都加入了坎布雷联盟。教皇想要罗马尼亚、马克西米利安弗里利皇帝和维尼托、西班牙的阿普利安港口、法国的克里莫纳国王、匈牙利的达尔马提亚国王，以及其他每一个部分。对威尼斯征召的庞大军队的进攻是从法国发起的。1509年5月14日，威尼斯在阿格那德罗战役中惨败，这是威尼斯历史上最微妙的时刻之一。法国和帝国军队占领了威尼斯，但威尼斯通过外交努力设法摆脱了困境。为了与西班牙达成协议，阿普利安港口被割让，教皇朱利叶斯二世很快认识到威尼斯（当时意大利唯一有能力面对法国或奥斯曼帝国等民族国家）的最终毁灭所带来的危险。安德烈亚・格里蒂于1509年7月夺回了帕多瓦，成功地防御了被围困的帝国军队。西班牙和教皇解除了与法国的同盟关系，威尼斯重新夺回了布雷西亚和维罗纳。经过七年毁灭性的战争，塞雷尼西玛号重新夺回了她的大陆领土，直到阿达。虽然这场失败已经变成了一场胜利，但1509年的事件标志着威尼斯扩张的结束。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Venezia -->
  <!-- Civilization Kiev -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Kievans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>基辅文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Kievan Rus</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>基辅罗斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Kievan:Kievans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>基辅</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Rus people probably dominated what is now northwestern Russia since the eighth century. In the early ninth they became loosely organized under the Rus Khaganate, which may be regarded as a predecessor state to the Kievan Rus. According to the Primary Chronicle, the earliest chronicle of Kievan Rus, a Varangian named Rurik first established himself in Novgorod in about 860 before moving south and extending his authority to Kiev.[PARAGRAPH:2]These Varangians settled in Ladoga, then moved southward to Novgorod eventually reaching Kiev, putting an end to the Khazars' collecting tribute from Kievans. The Kievan Rus was founded by prince Oleg about 880. During the next thirty-five years, Oleg and his warriors subdued the various Eastern Slavic and Finnic tribes. In 907, Oleg led an attack against Constantinople, and in 911 he signed a commercial treaty with the Byzantine Empire as an equal partner. The new Kievan state prospered because it had an abundant supply of furs, beeswax, and honey for export and because it controlled three main trade routes of Eastern Europe: the Volga trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Orient, the Dnieper trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Black Sea, and the trade route from the Khazars to the Germans.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the reign of Svyatoslav (945-972) Kievan rulers had adopted Slavic religion and names, but their druzhina still consisted primarily of Scandinavians. Svyatoslav's military conquests were astonishing: he dealt lethal blows to two of his strongest neighbours, Khazaria and the Bulgarian Empire, which collapsed soon after his raids.[PARAGRAPH:2]The region of Kiev dominated the state of Kievan Rus for the next two centuries. The grand prince of Kiev controlled the lands around the city, and his theoretically subordinate relatives ruled in other cities and paid him tribute. The zenith of the state's power came during the reigns of Prince Vladimir the Great (980-1015) and Prince Yaroslav the Wise (1019-1054). Both rulers continued the steady expansion of Kievan Rus that had begun under Oleg.[PARAGRAPH:2]Vladimir rose to power in Kiev after the death of his father Sviatoslav I in 972 and after defeating his half-brother Yaropolk in 980. As Prince of Kiev, Vladimir's most notable achievement was the Christianization of Kievan Rus, a process that began in 988.[PARAGRAPH:2]Kievan Rus was not able to maintain its position as a powerful and prosperous state, in part because of the amalgamation of disparate lands under the control of a ruling clan. As the members of that clan became more numerous, they identified themselves with regional interests rather than with the larger patrimony. Thus, the princes fought among themselves, frequently forming alliances with outside groups such as the Polovtsians, Poles, and Hungarians. During the years from 1054 to 1224 no fewer than 64 principalities had a more or less ephemeral existence, 293 princes put forward succession claims, and their disputes led to 83 civil wars.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Crusades brought a shift in European trade routes that accelerated the decline of Kievan Rus. In 1204 the forces of the Fourth Crusade sacked Constantinople, making the Dnieper trade route marginal. As it declined, Kievan Rus splintered into many principalities and several large regional centers. The three most powerful of them were the Halych-Volhynia (eventually conquered by Poland and Lithuania), Novgorod Republic (later incorporated into Muscovy) and Vladimir-Suzdal, which gradually evolved into the Grand Duchy of Moscow.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]自8世纪以来，俄罗斯人可能统治了现在的俄罗斯西北部。九月初，他们在可汗国统治下变得松散，可汗国可能被视为基辅罗斯的前身。根据基辅罗斯最早的编年史《原始编年史》记载，一个名叫鲁里克的瓦兰吉安人于860年左右首先在诺夫哥罗德建立了自己的地位，然后向南迁移并将其权力扩展到基辅。[第2段]这些瓦兰吉安人定居在拉多加，然后向南迁移到诺夫哥罗德，最终到达基辅，结束了卡扎尔从基辅收集贡品的活动。基辅罗斯是奥列格王子在880年左右建立的。在接下来的35年里，奥列格和他的战士们征服了东斯拉夫和芬兰的各个部落。在907年，奥列格领导了对君士坦丁堡的进攻，在911年，他与拜占庭帝国签署了一项商业条约，作为平等的伙伴。新的基辅国家之所以繁荣，是因为它有丰富的毛皮、蜂蜡和蜂蜜出口，而且它控制了东欧的三条主要贸易路线：从波罗的海到东方的伏尔加贸易路线，从波罗的海到黑海的第聂伯河贸易路线，从哈扎尔人到德国人的贸易路线。[第2段]在斯维雅托斯拉夫（945-972）统治时期，基辅统治者采用了斯拉夫宗教和名字，但他们的德鲁日纳人仍然主要是斯堪的纳维亚人。斯维雅托斯拉夫的军事征服是惊人的：他对他的两个最强大的邻国卡扎里亚和保加利亚帝国进行了致命的打击，这两个国家在他的袭击后不久就崩溃了。基辅大王子控制了城市周围的土地，他的理论上的从属亲属统治着其他城市并向他致敬。国家权力的顶峰出现在弗拉基米尔大帝（980-1015）和雅罗斯拉夫王子（1019-1054）在位期间。两位统治者都继续着在奥列格统治下开始的基辅罗斯的稳步扩张。[第2段]弗拉基米尔在父亲斯维亚托斯拉夫一世于972年去世后，以及在980年击败同父异母兄弟亚罗波尔克后，在基辅上台执政。作为基辅王子，弗拉基米尔最显著的成就是基辅罗斯的基督教化，这一进程始于988年。[第2段]基辅罗斯未能保持其作为一个强大和繁荣的国家的地位，部分原因是在一个统治家族的控制下，不同的土地合并。随着这个家族的成员越来越多，他们认同自己的地区利益，而不是更大的遗产。因此，王子们互相争斗，经常与外部团体结成联盟，如波罗的海人、波兰人和匈牙利人。从1054年到1224年，至少有64个君主国的存在或多或少是短暂的，293个君主提出了继承权要求，他们的争端导致了83场内战。[第2段]十字军东征带来了欧洲贸易路线的转变，加速了基辅罗斯的衰落。1204年，第四次十字军东征的军队洗劫了君士坦丁堡，使得第聂伯河的贸易路线处于边缘。随着其衰落，基辅罗斯分裂成许多公国和几个大的地区中心。其中最强大的三个国家是哈利奇・沃希尼亚（最终被波兰和立陶宛征服）、诺夫哥罗德共和国（后来并入莫斯科）和弗拉基米尔・苏兹达尔，后者逐渐演变为莫斯科大公国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Kiev -->
  <!-- Civilization Hungary -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Hungarians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>匈牙利文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Hungary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>匈牙利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Hungarian:Hungarians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>匈牙利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Magyars were nomads related to the Huns and Avars and came originally from near Finland and Estonia. They settled north of the Black Sea and entered into service with the Byzantine Empire, making war on the Bulgars at Byzantine request. They then migrated from the Ukraine to escape the Pechenegs, who were attacking them at the behest of the Bulgars, and settled in the Danube River basin in 896 AD, under the rule of their Great Chief, Arpad. They were expert horsemen and terrifying warriors and conducted Viking-like raids on all the lands around them, but on horse, instead of by ship. They soon dominated the entire region, even laying siege to German cities and Constantinople itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 997, Duke Geza, the Magyar leader, died and his son Istvan promptly and forcefully asserted his supremacy over the nation and several discontented elder relatives who disputed his right to the succession. Until this point, Magyar leadership had been elected by seniority in the ruling family, not passed on by primogeniture. In 1000 AD, Istvan asked Pope Sylvester II for a royal crown, which the Pope sent, thus recognizing him as the first Christian king of Hungary, King Stephen. During his 38-year reign, Stephen I consolidated the Magyar state under a group of powerful nobles using modified Carolingian administrative practices, completed conversion of the Magyars to Christianity, and allied the kingdom more closely with the West, most notably by marrying Otto the Great's niece. Stephen was canonized in 1083, and the Crown of Saint Stephen became a symbol of Hungarian nationhood.[PARAGRAPH:2]The thrones of Hungary and Croatia were united in 1091, and during the reign of Bela III (1173-1196) Hungary became the strongest state in east central Europe. The power of the monarchy declined under the weak rule of Andrew II, who was forced to grant a charter, called the Golded Bull, to the nobles, allowing them greater privileges. In 1241, the Mongols invaded and devastated the land, further weakening the Magyar monarchy. The last of the Arpad dynasty died in 1301, and most of Hungary's rulers after that were foreigners.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[表]马扎尔人是与匈奴和阿瓦尔人有关的游牧民族，最初来自芬兰和爱沙尼亚附近。他们在黑海以北定居，并在拜占庭帝国服役，应拜占庭的要求对保加利亚人发动战争。然后，他们从乌克兰移民，以逃避Pechenegs，他们是在保加利亚的命令下攻击他们，并在多瑙河流域定居在公元896年，在其伟大的酋长，Arpad的统治下。他们是专业的骑兵和可怕的战士，在他们周围的所有土地上进行海盗式的突袭，但不是坐船，而是骑马。他们很快就统治了整个地区，甚至包围了德国城市和君士坦丁堡本身。[第2段]997年，马扎尔的领袖格扎公爵去世，他的儿子伊斯特万迅速而有力地宣称他对国家的至高无上地位，还有几位不满的老亲戚对他的继承权提出异议。在此之前，马扎尔的领导权是由统治家族的资历选举产生的，而不是由长子继承。公元1000年，伊斯特万向教皇西尔维斯特二世索要皇冠，教皇派遣了皇冠，从而承认他是匈牙利第一位基督教国王斯蒂芬国王。在他38年的统治期间，斯蒂芬一世通过改良加洛林王朝的管理方式，将马扎尔王朝巩固在一群强大的贵族之下，完成了马扎尔人向基督教的转变，并与西方更紧密地结盟，最显著的是与奥托大帝的侄女结婚。1083年斯蒂芬被封为圣徒，圣斯蒂芬的王冠成为匈牙利国家地位的象征。[第2段]1091年匈牙利和克罗地亚的王位统一，贝拉三世（1173-1196）统治期间，匈牙利成为中东欧最强大的国家。在安德鲁二世（Andrew II）的软弱统治下，君主制的权力下降了。安德鲁二世被迫向贵族授予一个名为金牛（Golded Bull）的宪章，允许他们享有更大的特权。1241年，蒙古人入侵并毁坏了这片土地，进一步削弱了马扎尔的君主政体。阿尔帕德王朝的最后一个王朝死于1301年，此后匈牙利的统治者大多是外国人。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Hungary -->
  <!-- Civilization Germany -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Germans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>日耳曼文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Germany</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>德意志</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>German:Germans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>德意志</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Julius Caesar's Gallic Wars brought the Germanic tribes into the spotlight of history. Although Roman efforts to establish hegemony across the Rhine continued for decades, the frontier eventually stabilized along the Rhine and Danube rivers. At that time, Germanic culture extended from Scandinavia as far south as the Carpathians. Although it was heavily fortified, the frontier was never a barrier to trade or culture. Germanic fear of the Huns eventually drove many of the tribes inside the borders of the Roman Empire in the 4th and 5th centuries, where the weakened Romans were unable to contain them. The Eastern Roman Empire survived the crisis and lasted for another thousand years, but the Germanic peoples carved out their own independent kingdoms in the West.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Germanics tribes that had invaded the Roman Empire, the Franks proved to be the most successful. The Merovingian kings and their Carolingian successors eventually brought much of what would later constitute Germany under Frankish control, but the ceaseless blows from Danes, Saracens (Muslims), and Magyars in the later 9th and 10th centuries weakened the kingdom's cohesion. Because the Carolingians themselves were unable to provide effective defense for the empire, there arose in nearly all the German lands powerful lines of margraves, counts, and hereditary rulers; their intrigues and wars against each other were interrupted only briefly by the rise of strong emperors such as Frederick Barbarossa (1155-1190). The subsequent history of Germany is, despite the role of the central rule of the Holy Roman Empire, one of the rise and fall of feuding principalities. It would be a thousand years before Germany was again unified under a single ruler.[PARAGRAPH:2]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.[PARAGRAPH:2]The same nationalism that had brought unity would also bring disaster. Ignoring the careful diplomacy that had isolated Prussia's opponent in each of Bismarck's wars, Germany rushed into World War I against a coalition of Britain, France, and Russia. Despite initial successes, the war eventually turned into a stalemate that Germany could not win, especially once the United Stated entered the war on the Entente side in 1917. Already staggering under a vengeful peace imposed by the Western Allies following World War I, the worldwide economic collapse that began in 1929 proved the catalyst for political extremism. Although bitterly opposed to each other, the Nazis and Communists during the next decade succeeded in mobilizing the political and economic resentments generated by defeat and depression. When Hitler finally became chancellor in January 1933, it was not on the crest of a wave of popular support but as the result of ruthless political intrigue.[PARAGRAPH:2]World War II is appropriately called "Hitler's War." Spearheaded by Panzer formations using revolutionary new tactics, Hitler came close to realizing his aim of establishing German hegemony in Europe. But the turning point of the war came with his decision to send his Panzers into Soviet Russia. Though at the end of 1942 an ultimate German victory still seemed possible, by spring 1945 the Third Reich was prostrate. As a legacy of surrender and the ensuing Cold War, a truncated Germany was divided into two zones of military occupation. While under Soviet rule East Germany suffered and stagnated, West Germany's recovery from total economic and political prostration at the end of World War II was of such dramatic proportions as to become a modern legend. The swift and unexpected downfall of the Soviet order in Europe led to a unification treaty, ratified by the West German Bundestag and the East German People's Chamber in September 1990. After 45 years of division, Germany was once again a united nation. Today Germany is one of the world's economic powerhouses, and a leading force in the European Union.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>凯撒的高卢战争使日耳曼部落成为历史的焦点。尽管罗马人在莱茵河上建立霸权的努力持续了几十年，但边界最终稳定在莱茵河和多瑙河沿岸。当时，日耳曼文化从斯堪的纳维亚延伸到南部的喀尔巴阡山脉。尽管边境设防森严，但从来不是贸易或文化的障碍。日耳曼人对匈奴的恐惧最终驱使许多部落在4世纪和5世纪进入罗马帝国的边界，在那里，虚弱的罗马人无法控制他们。东罗马帝国在危机中幸存下来并延续了一千年，但是日耳曼人在西方建立了自己的独立王国。[第2段]在入侵罗马帝国的日耳曼部落中，法兰克人是最成功的。梅罗文吉国王和他们的加洛林王朝继承者最终将大部分后来构成德国的东西置于法兰克人的控制之下，但丹麦人、撒拉逊人（穆斯林）和马扎尔人在9世纪末和10世纪的不断打击削弱了王国的凝聚力。由于加洛林人本身无法为帝国提供有效的防御，几乎在所有的德国土地上都出现了强大的边疆、伯爵和世袭统治者的防线；他们之间的阴谋和战争只因弗雷德里克・巴巴罗萨（Frederick Barbarossa，1155-1190）等强大皇帝的崛起而短暂中断。随后的德国历史，尽管是神圣罗马帝国的中心统治，但却是世仇公国兴衰的历史之一。在组成德国的数百个国家中，普鲁士王国将最终成功地把它们结合在一起。从波罗的海沿岸的一个小公国开始，普鲁士统治者通过战争和婚姻协议的结合，逐渐积累了越来越多的领土。腓特烈国王威廉一世（1713-1710）训练普鲁士军队成为欧洲最优秀的军队之一，他的儿子腓特烈二世（1740-1746）也被称为腓特烈大帝，用它赢得了一系列对奥地利和俄罗斯等大国的军事胜利。弗雷德里克也被称为艺术赞助人，他的宫廷吸引了来自欧洲各地的伏尔泰等知识分子。作为一个开明的独裁者，腓特烈同样擅长于击败俄国的侵略和吹笛子。[第2段]在法国大革命和拿破仑战争中的屈辱和失败之后，普鲁士设法恢复元气，按照更现代的路线重新组织自己。受1848年德国革命期间发生的民众起义的困扰，普鲁士的威廉一世（1861-1888）考虑退位，以支持他的儿子，据信，他的政治观点接近自由反对派。然而，他被说服考虑组建一个由普鲁士驻巴黎大使奥托・冯・俾斯麦（Otto von Bismarck）领导的新政府。1862年9月，一个以保守主义、民族主义和（现实政治）著称的政治家成为普鲁士总理的消息震惊了欧洲。俾斯麦被证明是一位杰出的战略家，1871年1月，在对丹麦、奥地利和法国进行了三次短暂而决定性的战争之后，新德意志帝国宣告成立。在十年的时间里，俾斯麦统一了德国，或者，正如一些人所说，普鲁士征服了德国。德国无视在俾斯麦的每一场战争中孤立普鲁士对手的谨慎外交，冲进了第一次世界大战，对抗英、法、俄的联盟。尽管最初取得了成功，但战争最终演变成了德国无法取胜的僵局，尤其是1917年美国加入协约国一方的战争。在第一次世界大战后西方盟国实施报复性和平的情况下，世界范围内始于1929年的经济崩溃已经令人震惊，成为政治极端主义的催化剂。纳粹和共产党虽然彼此强烈反对，但在接下来的十年里，他们成功地动员了因战败和萧条而产生的政治和经济仇恨。当希特勒在1933年1月最终成为财政大臣时，这并不是一场民众支持的浪潮的高潮，而是残酷的政治阴谋的结果。[第2段]第二次世界大战被恰当地称为“希特勒之战”。以使用革命性新战术的装甲编队为先锋，希特勒几乎实现了在欧洲建立德国霸权的目标。但战争的转折点是他决定把他的装甲车开进苏联。尽管在1942年底，德国似乎仍有可能取得最终的胜利，但到1945年春天，第三帝国已经垮台。作为投降和随后的冷战的遗产，被截断的德国被分为两个军事占领区。在苏联统治下，东德受苦受难，停滞不前，而西德在二战结束时从经济和政治上的彻底崩溃中恢复过来，其戏剧性程度足以成为一个现代传奇。苏联在欧洲秩序的迅速和意外崩溃导致了一项统一条约，该条约于1990年9月得到了西德联邦议院和东德人民院的批准。经过45年的分裂，德国再次成为一个统一的国家。今天，德国是世界经济强国之一，也是欧盟的主导力量。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Germany -->
  <!-- Civilization Poland -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Polish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>波兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Poland</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>波兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Polish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>波兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]There can be little doubt that, had they been able to overcome their internal divisions, the Poles would have been a dominant power in the Middle Ages. The first institution that can be called a Polish kingdom or nation arose in around 980 AD, when a tribal leader named Mieszko united three major tribes in eastern Europe and converted to Catholicism. The concept of a dynasty had not yet caught on in that part of Europe, though, so successions were often extremely violent and chaotic. After Mieszko's rule, the fortunes of the Polish nation-state depended entirely on the ruthlessness and strength of will of its leader. Some of Mieszko's successors were strong and able to impose their wills on the fractious principalities and tribes of Poland and Pomerania, and thereby defend effectively against foreign, usually German or Bohemian, invasion. Others were not.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1226 AD, just over two hundred years after Boleslaw II successfully reunited the Polish kingdom, Poland was deeply divided once again. Baltic tribes menaced the north and the German state of Brandenburg sought greater land and influence in the west. The Polish king, Conrad of Mazovia, decided to import an army to fight off both of these threats in exchange for an indefinite homeland in Poland. The army was the Teutonic Knights. They accepted Conrad's offer and, after arriving in northern Poland, waged several bloody campaigns of conquest against the German and Baltic occupiers. To Conrad's surprise, though, the Knights then decided that they would rather have their own country rather than a dependent homeland inside someone else's kingdom. Conrad had saved the Polish kingdom from outside invasion, only to be invaded from within.[PARAGRAPH:2]Future Polish kings then had to deal not just with Germans, Bohemians and Lithuanians, but the restless and aggressive Teutonic Knights. As if that were not enough, in 1241 a major Mongol invasion force arrived in Silesia (southeastern Poland). The Poles were able to defeat the Mongols, but at huge cost. Vast lands were laid waste and thousands of soldiers perished. In 1330 tensions between the Teutonic Knights and Poland erupted into open war, and after many political and military stalemates, the Polish king Casimir III was able to expand and recover from the Mongol attack and the endless conflicts with Poland's neighbors. But despite holding firm, Casimir had to settle for survival rather than prosperity.[PARAGRAPH:2]The golden age of Poland came at the end of the Middle Ages, when alliance with Lithuania led to a combined assault on the Teutonic Knights that culminated in the fated battle of Grunwald in 1410. The Knights were able to fight off one contingent of the allied force, but were crushed by the other. The Knights were not totally defeated, but they would never again exert their will upon Poland as forcefully as they had in the preceding two centuries. Casimir IV, perhaps the greatest Polish king, was able to capitalize on this success to unite the Polish succession lines with those of Hungary and Bohemia, creating, albeit briefly, an eastern European super-state that dominated the region culturally and militarily for two generations.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]毫无疑问，如果波兰人能够克服内部分歧，那么他们在中世纪将成为一个主导力量。第一个可以称为波兰王国或国家的机构出现在公元980年左右，当时一个叫米什科的部落首领联合了东欧的三个主要部落，并皈依了天主教。然而，王朝的概念还没有在欧洲的这一地区流行起来，因此，王朝的更替往往极其暴力和混乱。米什科统治后，波兰民族国家的命运完全取决于其领导人的冷酷无情和意志坚强。米什科的一些继任者很强大，能够将他们的意志强加给波兰和波美拉尼亚的暴躁的公国和部落，从而有效地抵御外国，通常是德国或波希米亚人的入侵。另一些则不然。[第2段]公元1226年，就在博莱斯洛二世成功地统一了波兰王国两百多年后，波兰再次分裂。波罗的海部落威胁北部，德国勃兰登堡州则在西部寻求更大的土地和影响力。波兰国王，马佐维亚的康拉德，决定引进一支军队来对抗这两种威胁，以换取在波兰无限期的家园。军队是日耳曼骑士。他们接受了康拉德的提议，到达波兰北部后，对德国和波罗的海占领者发动了几次血腥的征服运动。然而，令康拉德惊讶的是，骑士们随后决定，他们宁愿拥有自己的国家，也不愿在别人的王国里拥有一个依附的家园。康拉德把波兰王国从外来入侵中拯救出来，结果却遭到了来自内部的入侵。[第2段]未来的波兰国王不仅要对付德国人、波希米亚人和立陶宛人，还要对付躁动不安、咄咄逼人的日耳曼骑士。似乎这还不够，1241年，一支主要的蒙古入侵部队到达了西里西亚（波兰东南部）。波兰人打败了蒙古人，但付出了巨大的代价。广袤的土地被荒废，成千上万的士兵丧生。1330年，日耳曼骑士团与波兰之间的紧张关系爆发了公开战争，经过多次政治和军事僵局，波兰国王卡西米尔三世得以从蒙古人的进攻和与波兰邻国的无休止的冲突中扩大和恢复。但是，尽管卡西米尔坚持了下来，但他不得不满足于生存而不是繁荣。骑士们能够击退盟军的一支分队，但被另一支部队压垮了。骑士们并没有被彻底打败，但他们再也不会像过去两个世纪那样，把他们的意志强加于波兰。卡西米尔四世，也许是波兰最伟大的国王，能够利用这一成功，将波兰的继承路线与匈牙利和波希米亚的继承路线结合起来，创造了一个东欧超级国家，尽管是短暂的，它在文化和军事上统治了该地区两代人。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Poland -->
  <!-- Civilization Moscow -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Muscovites</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>莫斯科文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Muscovy</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>莫斯科</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Muscovy:Muscovites</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>莫斯科</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Indo-European, Ural-Altaic, and other races have occupied what is now the territory of Russia since 2000 BC, but little is known about their institutions and activities. Modern Russia dates from about 770 AD, when Viking explorers began an intensive penetration of the Volga region. From bases in estuaries along the eastern Baltic, Scandinavian bands, probably in search of new trade routes to the east, began to penetrate territory populated by Finnish and Slavic tribes, where they found unlimited natural resources.[PARAGRAPH:2]Within a few decades the Rus, as the Viking settlers were known, together with other Scandinavians operating farther west, extended their raiding activities down the main river routes toward Baghdad and Constantinople, reaching the Black Sea in 860. In the period from 930 to 1000, the region came under complete control by the Rus from their capital at Kiev. The lifeblood of this sprawling Kievan empire was the commerce organized by these Viking princes. Sometime around 1000 the Kievan princes were converted to Christianity by Byzantine missionaries, and the medieval Russian states would maintain close cultural ties with the Byzantines. The united Kievan state broke apart after 1054 under the pressure of attacks by nomads from the steppes, fragmenting Russia into a number of independent principalities. The devastating attack by the Mongols in 1237-40 resulted in widepread destruction of cities, loss of life, and wiped out a developing commercial middle class centered around the fur trade. This helped bring about the long rule of autocracy in Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Russian principalities, it was Muscovy that proved to be the most successful. Beginning as the state that collected taxes for Russia's Mongol overlords, the princes of Muscovy eventually gained a position of leadership by throwing off the yoke of their oppressors. Ivan III (1462-1505) consolidated the gains his father, Vasily II, had won in the saddle, and his warrior descendent Ivan IV (1533-84), known as Ivan the Terrible, gained enough power to take the title of "Tsar", or Emperor, in 1547. This "gathering of the Russian lands" became a conscious and irresistible five-century drive by Moscow to annex all Slavic lands, both the Russian territories and the Belorussian and Ukrainian regions. The ascension of Peter I (1694-1725), known as Peter the Great, ushered in and established the social, political, and intellectual trends that were to dominate Russia for the next two centuries. The location of his new capital, St. Petersburg, on the shores of the Gulf of Finland symbolized this shift toward a European involvement. But while the Russian aristocracy may have adopted the courtly behavior and modern military tactics of the West, the vast majority of the Russian people remained mired in a slave-like state of feudal servitude.[PARAGRAPH:2]Catherine the Great (1762-1796), though a German princess who was unrelated to Peter in any way, would prove to be his true intellectual and political heir. Catherine's reign was notable for imperial expansion. Most important were the securing of the northern shore of the Black Sea, the annexation of the Crimea, and the expansion into the steppes beyond the Urals. This permitted the protection of Russian agricultural settlements in the south and the establishment of trade routes through the Black Sea. In the process, the military democracies of the Cossack hosts along the Dnieper, Don, and Volga rivers lost their autonomy and special privileges; the wealthier officers became Russian nobles, receiving the right to own and settle serfs on their own lands, while the fierce horsemen sank to the level of peasants with special military obligations. Catherine's partitioning of Poland also helped bring Russia closer to the rest of Europe, at least geographically.[PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the heritage of Peter and Catherine, by the time of Nicholas II (1894-1917) Russia was in disarray, plagued by internal misery and oppression. Defeat in the Russo-Japanese War followed by the 1905 Revolution indicated that Russia was in need of drastic reforms, but the autocratic structure of the Tsarist state was poorly suited to adapt to changing conditions. World War I imposed stresses on the Tsardom that it could not meet, and the Russian Revolution broke out in 1917, riding on a wave of popular discontent. The Kerensky Provisional Government, a moderate attempt to resolve the problems, collapsed in the face of the Bolshevik (Communist) revolution. Given the Bolshevik desire to dominate the whole of Russia and the rest of the former Tsarist empire, civil war was inevitable, and a bitter struggle between Red (Communist) and White (Tsarist) forces lasted until the Bolsheviks were victorious in 1922. Stalin would complete the consolidation of Communist power begun by Lenin, most notably through the forced industrialization of the Five-Year Plans and the mass starvations engendered by the collectivization of agriculture. Despite an almost inhuman level of suffering imposed on the Russian people, Stalin would lead the Soviet Union through the greatest threat to its existence during the Nazi invasion of 1941-45, and help it emerge as one of the world's superpowers following the Second World War.[PARAGRAPH:2]But in the ensuing Cold War, Russia's economy tottered towards collapse. The Communist economic system worked well at producing millions of tons of iron for use in tanks, but was unable to produce simple household goods to improve the daily lives of its people. Mikhail Gorbachev attempted to revive the stagnant Soviet economy through the relaxation of economic and political controls, but the forces of free speech and a free market quickly took hold in a way Gorbachev never would have imagined. Within a few years, the Soviet satellites in Eastern Europe were declaring their independence and new politicians like Boris Yeltsin were demanding democratic elections. An ill-conceived, ill-planned, and poorly executed coup attempt to unseat Yeltsin occurred in August 1991, bringing an end to the Communist Party and accelerating the movement to disband the Soviet Union. Yeltsin dissolved the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in December 1991, banned the Communist Party in Russia, and seized all of its property, becoming the first president of Russia. Today, as it often has throughout its history, Russia finds itself struggling between whether to follow the example of the West or pursue its own unique path of development.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>印欧、乌拉尔阿尔泰和其他民族自公元前2000年以来占领了现在的俄罗斯领土，但他们的机构和活动鲜为人知。现代俄罗斯可以追溯到公元770年，当时海盗探险家开始深入伏尔加地区。斯堪的纳维亚人从波罗的海东部的河口基地出发，可能是为了寻找通往东部的新贸易路线，开始渗透芬兰和斯拉夫部落聚居的领土，在那里他们发现了无限的自然资源。[第2段]几十年内，人们就知道了北欧海盗定居者罗斯，与其他斯堪的纳维亚人一起，在更远的西部活动，扩大了他们的袭击活动沿着主要的河流路线向巴格达和君士坦丁堡，到达黑海在860年。在930年至1000年期间，该地区完全由俄罗斯从其首都基辅控制。这个庞大的基辅帝国的生命线是这些维京王子组织的商业活动。大约1000名基辅王子被拜占庭传教士皈依基督教，中世纪的俄罗斯国家将与拜占庭保持密切的文化联系。1054年后，在来自大草原的游牧民族的袭击压力下，统一的基辅国解体，将俄罗斯分裂成多个独立的公国。1237-1230年蒙古人的毁灭性袭击造成了城市的大面积破坏和生命损失，消灭了以毛皮贸易为中心的发展中的商业中产阶级。这有助于在俄罗斯实现长期的独裁统治。从为俄罗斯蒙古霸主收税的国家开始，莫斯科王子最终摆脱了压迫者的枷锁，获得了领导地位。伊凡三世（1462-1505）巩固了他父亲瓦西里二世（Vasily II）在马鞍上赢得的战利品，他的勇士后裔伊凡四世（1533-1534）被称为可怕的伊凡，在1547年获得了足够的权力，获得了“沙皇”或皇帝的称号。这一“俄罗斯土地的聚集”成为莫斯科在五个世纪内有意识和不可抗拒地吞并所有斯拉夫土地的行动，包括俄罗斯领土、白俄罗斯和乌克兰地区。彼得一世（1694-1725）被称为彼得大帝（Peter The Great），他的升天开创并确立了未来两个世纪统治俄罗斯的社会、政治和知识潮流。他的新首都圣彼得堡位于芬兰湾沿岸，象征着向欧洲介入的转变。但是，尽管俄罗斯贵族可能采取了西方的宫廷行为和现代军事战术，但绝大多数俄罗斯人民仍然深陷于奴隶般的封建奴役状态。[第2段]凯瑟琳大帝（1762-1796），尽管她是一位与彼得毫不相干的德国公主，将被证明是他真正的知识和政治继承人。凯瑟琳的统治以帝国扩张而闻名。最重要的是黑海北岸的安全，克里米亚的吞并，以及乌拉尔以外的大草原的扩张。这使俄罗斯得以保护南部的农业定居点，并建立通过黑海的贸易路线。在这一过程中，哥萨克的军事民主国家在第聂伯河、顿河和伏尔加河沿岸失去了自治权和特权；富裕的军官成为俄罗斯贵族，获得了在自己土地上拥有和安置农奴的权利，而凶猛的骑兵则沦落到了负有特殊军事义务的农民的水平。凯瑟琳对波兰的分割也有助于使俄罗斯更接近欧洲其他国家，至少在地理上是如此。1905年革命后的日俄战争的失败表明，俄罗斯需要大刀阔斧的改革，但沙皇国家的专制结构不适应不断变化的条件。第一次世界大战对沙皇施加了无法满足的压力，1917年，俄国革命爆发，掀起了民众不满的浪潮。克伦斯基临时政府，一个温和的解决问题的尝试，在布尔什维克（共产主义）革命面前崩溃了。考虑到布尔什维克想要统治整个俄罗斯和前沙皇帝国的其他地区，内战不可避免，红（共）军和白（沙皇）军之间的激烈斗争一直持续到1922年布尔什维克取得胜利。斯大林将完成列宁开始的巩固共产主义政权的工作，最主要的是通过五年计划的强制工业化和农业集体化带来的大规模饥荒。尽管俄罗斯人民遭受了几乎不人道的痛苦，但斯大林将带领苏联度过1941-1945年纳粹入侵期间对其生存的最大威胁，并帮助苏联在第二次世界大战后成为世界超级大国之一，俄罗斯经济摇摇欲坠走向崩溃。共产主义的经济体系在生产数百万吨铁用于坦克方面做得很好，但却无法生产简单的生活用品来改善人民的日常生活。米哈伊尔・戈尔巴乔夫试图通过放松经济和政治控制来重振停滞的苏联经济，但言论自由和自由市场的力量很快以戈尔巴乔夫想象不到的方式占据了政权。不到几年，苏联在东欧的卫星就宣布独立，而像鲍里斯・叶利钦这样的新政治家则要求举行民主选举。1991年8月发生了一场构思不周、计划不周、执行不力的政变企图推翻叶利钦，结束了共产党，加速了解散苏联的运动。1991年12月，叶利钦解散了苏维埃社会主义共和国联盟，取缔了俄罗斯共产党，没收了苏维埃社会主义共和国的全部财产，成为俄罗斯第一任总统。今天，正如俄罗斯历史上经常发生的那样，它发现自己正挣扎于是效仿西方，还是走自己独特的发展道路。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Moscow -->
  <!-- Civilization Genoa -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Genoans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>热那亚文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Genoa</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>热那亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Genoan:Genoans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>热那亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Republic initially came into existence in the early 11th century, when Genoa became a self-governing commune within the old Regnum Italicum. In its early centuries, Genoa was an important trading city, like Venice. Genoa started her expansion during the Crusades: the Republic granted her fleet for the transportations and gained many settlements on the Middle East and favored commercial treaties. During 13th century the Republic of Genoa was allied with the Byzantine Empire of Nicaea, which received Genoese help to regain Constantinople in 1261. The alliance permitted a great commercial expansion on the Empire and also the conquest of many isles and settlements on the Aegean Sea (the most important was the isle of Chios which was lost only in 1566). In the same century the Republic conquered important trading interests throughout the Black Sea, where Genoa controlled many settlements on Crimea.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the west Mediterranean the principal rival to Genoa was Pisa, which was ultimately defeated in the naval Battle of Meloria (1284), gaining the island of Corsica from it in the late 13th century and later the control of the north-west of Sardinia, where Genoese families gained territories. In the contest between the Angevins and the Aragonese for control of Sicily after the Sicilian Vespers of 1283, Genoese merchants luckily chose to support Aragon, the winning side, and moved into the Sicilian economy with energy, lending money to the ruling class, organizing and controlling the production of sugar and silks and monopolizing the export of Sicilian grain, on which Genoa depended, situated by nature with no grain-growing contado to support its population, but which the Maghreb also required. In exchange, Genoa received African gold.[PARAGRAPH:2]As a result of the economic retrenchment Europe in the late 14th century, as well as its long war with Venice, which culminated in its defeat at Chioggia (1380), Genoa went into a decline. The rising Ottoman power cut into the Genoese emporia in the Aegean, and the Black Sea trade was squeezed off.[PARAGRAPH:2]Genoa was ultimately occupied by the French or the Milanese for much of the period. From 1499 to 1528, the Republic reached its nadir, being under nearly continual French occupation. The Spanish, with their intramural allies, the "old nobility" entrenched in the mountain fastnesses behind Genoa, captured the city on May 30, 1522 and subjected the city to a merciless pillage. When the great admiral Andrea Doria of the powerful Doria family allied with the Emperor Charles V to oust the French and restore Genoa's independence, a renewed prospect opened: 1528 marks the first loan from Genoese banks to Charles.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Genoa underwent something of a revival as a junior associate of the Spanish Empire, with Genoese bankers, in particular, financing many of the Spanish crown's foreign endeavors from their counting houses in Seville. The decline of Spain in the 17th century brought also the renewed decline of Genoa, and the Spanish crown's frequent bankruptcies, in particular, ruined many of Genoa's merchant houses.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]共和国最初于11世纪初成立，当时热那亚成为意大利老雷格努姆的自治公社。在早期的几个世纪里，热那亚和威尼斯一样是一个重要的贸易城市。热那亚在十字军东征期间开始扩张：共和国批准了她的运输船队，并在中东获得了许多定居点，并赞成签订商业条约。13世纪，热那亚共和国与拜占庭帝国尼西亚结盟，后者在1261年得到热那亚人的帮助，重新夺回君士坦丁堡。联盟允许帝国进行大规模的商业扩张，也征服了爱琴海上的许多岛屿和定居点（最重要的是1566年才消失的奇奥斯岛）。同一世纪，共和国征服了整个黑海的重要贸易利益，在那里热那亚控制了克里米亚的许多定居点。[第2段]在西地中海，热那亚的主要竞争对手是比萨，比萨最终在米洛里亚海战（1284年）中被击败，在13世纪末从中获得了科西嘉岛世纪及以后对撒丁岛西北部的控制，热那亚家族在那里获得了领土。在1283年西西里晚祷之后，安格文人和阿拉贡人争夺西西里岛的控制权，热那亚商人幸运地选择支持获胜的阿拉贡人，带着活力进入西西里经济，借钱给统治阶级，组织和控制糖和丝绸的生产，垄断热那亚赖以生存的西西里谷物的出口。热那亚的自然条件是没有种植谷物的康塔多来养活其人口，但马格里布也需要这样做。作为交换，热那亚获得了非洲黄金。[第2段]由于14世纪末欧洲经济紧缩，以及与威尼斯的长期战争，最终在Chioggia（1380年）战败，热那亚走向衰落。崛起的奥斯曼帝国切断了爱琴海热那亚的商业区，黑海贸易也被切断了。[第2段]热那亚在这一时期的大部分时间里最终被法国人或米兰人占领。从1499年到1528年，共和国处于几乎持续不断的法国占领之下，达到了它的最低点。西班牙人和他们的内部盟友，在热那亚后面的山上扎根的“老贵族”，于1522年5月30日占领了这座城市，并无情地掠夺了这座城市。当强大的多利亚家族伟大的海军上将安德烈亚・多利亚与国王查理五世结盟，驱逐法国人，恢复热那亚的独立时，一个新的前景开启了：1528年是热那亚银行向查尔斯的第一笔贷款。[第2段]此后，热那亚作为西班牙帝国的一个初级合伙人经历了某种复兴尤其是热那亚的银行家们，他们从塞维利亚的计票处为西班牙皇室的许多海外活动提供资金。17世纪西班牙的衰落也带来了热那亚的再次衰落，尤其是西班牙皇冠的频繁破产，毁掉了热那亚的许多商铺。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Genoa -->
  <!-- Civilization England -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The English</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>英格兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>England</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>英格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>English</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>英格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In the classical age Britain lay on the periphery of the civilized world; Julius Caesar's visitations to the island in 55/54 BC were viewed as a daring voyage into the unknown. But in 43 AD the island was invaded by Roman soldiers under the Emperor Claudius, and it was to spend the next four centuries as a Roman province. The Romans built cities, roads, and great bathhouses, the ruins of which can still be seen today. With the collapse of Roman power under Germanic onslaught, tribal migrations into Britain began about the middle of the 5th century. The first arrivals were invited by a British chieftain to defend his kingdom against the Picts and Scots. These first mercenaries were from three tribes - the Angles, Saxons, and Jutes - which were located on the coastlands of northwestern Germany. Eventually, these peoples would themselves topple the existing order, and Britain would spend many centuries divided between various warring kingdoms such as Mercia, East Anglia, and others. The first political entity that could rightly be called "England" formed out of the efforts of the kingdom of Wessex to unite the island against the invasion of Danes and Vikings in the 9th century. But the English domination was fleeting; the subsequent Norman Conquest (1066) resulted in the subordination of England to a Frankish aristocracy, and the introduction of feudalism to the Isles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Norman invasion reoriented England from the Scandinavian world to the Mediterranean one, and reintroduced many elements of Latin culture that had been lost in the Germanic invasions. The English Normans would eventually give rise to a purely British line of kings, the Plantagenets. Three centuries later, the Wars of the Roses was the final struggle between the Yorkist and Lancastrian descendants of the Plantagenets for control of the throne. When Henry Tudor, earl of Richmond, seized the crown in 1485, leaving the Yorkist Richard III dead upon the field of battle, few Englishmen would have predicted that 118 years of Tudor rule had begun. Elizabeth I (1558-1603) proved to be the most able Tudor monarch. No observer in 1558, any more than in 1485, would have predicted that despite the social discord, political floundering, and international humiliation of the past decades, the kingdom again stood on the threshold of an extraordinary age. Her reign ushered in two centuries of British exploration, colonization, and artistic and intellectual advances. When Elizabeth, the "Virgin Queen," died childless, Parliament offered the crown to the closest blood kin, James VI of Scotland, who became James I of England (1603-1625) and founded the Stuart dynasty. The Stuarts kings did not possess the best luck; Charles I was defeated by the forces of Parliament in the English Civil War and executed, and a scant four decades later his descendent James II was also overthrown in the "Glorious Revolution" of 1688. But despite all this turbulence, by 1700 England had merged with Scotland to become "Britain" and established an identity that would be both Protestant and Parliamentry.[PARAGRAPH:2]The British Empire was to be one based on trade and control of the seas. Using the soldiers commonly denoted "Redcoats", every major war Britain engaged in during the 18th and 19th centuries increased its colonial power. The Seven Years' War was particularly notable in this respect, and so were the Napoleonic Wars. By 1820 the total population of the British Empire was 200 million, 26%% of the world's total population. However acquired, all these acquisitions added to the crown's and the country's power and reputation. For the privileged and the rich, the Victorian era was pre-eminently one of confidence and arrogance, under the able guidance of Britain's two longtime Prime Ministers, Gladstone and Disraeli. Stretching from Australia and New Zealand through India, much of Africa, and Canada, the British Empire under Victoria was truly one on which the "sun never set."[PARAGRAPH:2]But the "long summer of peace" came to an end in the bloodbath of Flanders. Although Britain suffered far less physical damage than France and underwent no political revolution, World War I may have affected it more fundamentally than any other European power. The war was a catalyst for social and economic change. The mainstays of the early Industrial Revolution, such as coal mining, textile production, and shipbuilding, upon which British prosperity had been built, were now impoverished or redundant. Britain was slow to develop many of the newer manufacturing industries, such as those involving chemicals, electronics, and automobiles. British foreign policy for much of the postwar period aimed at rehabilitating Germany, while domestic policy focused on institutionalizing socialism to counter public concerns. In general, these movements were opposed by France and resulted in a rupture between Britain and its wartime ally, forcing France into a position of isolation that would have prodigious consequences for Europe with the rise of Hitler in the 1930s. World War II was a British victory, but left the nation bankrupt and unable to prevent the onset of decolonization in the 1950s and 1960s. Although Britons maintained a high standard of living, the British economy continued to perform poorly throughout the 1960s and 1970s. As a reaction, Margaret Thatcher (1979-1990) set out to end socialism in Britain. Her most dramatic acts consisted of a continuing series of statutes to denationalize nearly every industry that Labour had brought into public ownership during the previous 40 years. Promising that "we shall govern as New Labour," the Blair government installed in general elections in 1997 accepted some of Thatcher's foreign policies but also carried out the economic reforms it promised in its manifesto. Faced now with terrorist attacks that threaten the lives of ordinary civilians, Britain has pledged to work together with the United States and other nations to defend this attack on civilization.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>在古典时代，英国处于文明世界的边缘；公元前55/54年，凯撒大帝访问该岛，被视为一次大胆的未知之旅。但是在公元43年，在克劳迪斯皇帝的统治下，这个岛被罗马士兵入侵，并在接下来的四个世纪里成为罗马的一个省。罗马人建造了城市、道路和大澡堂，如今仍然可以看到它们的废墟。随着罗马政权在日耳曼人的冲击下崩溃，部落移民进入英国开始于大约5世纪中叶。第一批移民是受一位英国酋长的邀请，来保卫他的王国，抵御皮克特人和苏格兰人。这些第一批雇佣兵来自三个部落――盎格鲁人、撒克逊人和黄麻人，他们位于德国西北部沿海地区。最终，这些民族将自己推翻现有的秩序，英国将花费许多世纪的时间在不同的战国之间，如麦西亚，东英吉利亚和其他。第一个可以正确地称为“英格兰”的政治实体是在威塞克斯王国的努力下形成的，在9世纪，威塞克斯王国将该岛团结起来，反对丹麦人和维京人的入侵。但英国的统治转瞬即逝；随后诺曼人的征服（1066年）导致英国屈从于法兰克贵族，并将封建主义引入了该岛。[第2段]诺曼人的入侵使英国从斯堪的纳维亚世界转向了地中海世界，重新引入了许多在日耳曼入侵中消失的拉丁文化元素。英国的诺曼人最终会产生一个纯粹的英国国王，金雀花。三个世纪后，玫瑰战争是约克主义者和兰开斯特的金雀花后裔为争夺王位而进行的最后一场斗争。当里士满伯爵亨利・都铎（Henry Tudor）于1485年夺取王位，使约克主义者理查三世（Richard III）战死在战场上时，很少有英国人会预测到都铎王朝118年的统治已经开始。伊丽莎白一世（1558-1603）被证明是最有能力的都铎王朝君主。1558年的观察家们，甚至比1485年的观察家们，都不会预测到，尽管过去几十年里社会不和谐、政治动荡和国际耻辱，王国还是站在了一个非凡时代的门槛上。她的统治带来了两个世纪的英国探索、殖民统治以及艺术和智力的进步。当“处女女王”伊丽莎白无子去世时，议会将王冠献给了最亲密的血亲苏格兰的詹姆斯六世，詹姆斯六世成为英格兰的詹姆斯一世（1603-1625），并建立了斯图尔特王朝。斯图亚特国王并不拥有好运；查理一世在英国内战中被议会的力量打败并被处决，不到40年后，他的后裔詹姆斯二世也在1688年的“光荣革命”中被推翻。但尽管发生了这些动荡，到1700年，英格兰与苏格兰合并成为“英国”，并确立了一种新教和议会的身份。使用通常被称为“红大衣”的士兵，英国在18和19世纪进行的每一场主要战争都增加了它的殖民势力。七年战争在这方面尤其引人注目，拿破仑战争也是如此。到1820年，大英帝国的总人口为2亿，占世界总人口的26%。然而，所有这些收购都增加了皇室和国家的权力和声誉。对于特权阶层和富人来说，维多利亚时代在英国两位长期首相格拉德斯通和迪斯雷利的干练指导下，是一个自信和傲慢的时代。维多利亚统治下的大英帝国从澳大利亚和新西兰一直延伸到印度、非洲大部分地区和加拿大，是一个真正的“太阳永不落下”的帝国。[第2段]但是“漫长的和平之夏”在佛兰德斯的大屠杀中结束了。尽管英国遭受的身体伤害远低于法国，也没有经历任何政治革命，但一战对英国的影响可能比任何其他欧洲强国都要深远。战争是社会和经济变革的催化剂。早期工业革命的中流砥柱，如煤炭开采、纺织生产和造船业，是英国繁荣的基础，现在却变得贫穷或多余。英国在发展许多较新的制造业方面进展缓慢，例如那些涉及化学、电子和汽车的制造业。战后大部分时间英国的外交政策旨在恢复德国的元气，而国内政策则侧重于将社会主义制度化，以应对公众的关注。总的来说，这些运动遭到了法国的反对，导致了英国与其战时盟友的分裂，迫使法国陷入孤立的境地，随着希特勒在20世纪30年代的崛起，这将给欧洲带来巨大的后果。第二次世界大战是英国的胜利，但却让英国破产，无法阻止20世纪50年代和60年代非殖民化的开始。尽管英国人维持着高水平的生活，但英国经济在整个60年代和70年代仍然表现不佳。作为一种反应，玛格丽特・撒切尔（1979-1990）着手结束英国的社会主义。她最具戏剧性的行为包括一系列持续的法令，将劳工在过去40年中几乎所有公有制的行业都剥夺了国籍。布莱尔政府在1997年大选中承诺“我们将以新工党的身份执政”，接受了撒切尔夫人的一些外交政策，但同时也进行了其在宣言中承诺的经济改革。面对威胁普通平民生命的恐怖袭击，英国承诺将与美国和其他国家一道，为这场对文明的袭击进行防御。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization England -->
  <!-- Civilization Portugal -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Portuguese</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>葡萄牙文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Portugal</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>葡萄牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Portuguese</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>葡萄牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The area which encompasses modern Portugal was originally settled by Celtic tribes around 1000 BC and was then subsequently conquered by the Visigoths and finally the Moors. The Christian Kings of Asturia eventually drove the Moors out of the area; the new nation of Portugal was formed after its separation from Spanish rule.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portugal was one of the first great internationally-based sea empires in the European world. Between 1415 and 1665, Portugal created a series of resting and refueling ports along the eastern and western coasts of Africa in a bid to eventually reach the profitable shores of India. In 1498 they achieved their goals when Vasco da Gama reached Kozhikode (known then as Calicut). Several important battles took place between the Arabs (who had previously monopolized spice trade in the Indian Ocean) and the Portuguese during this era, the most important of them being the victory over the Egyptian-Gujarati fleet off of Diu in 1509. This victory assured the Portuguese maritime superiority in the Indian Ocean and enabled them to capitalize on the rich spice trade routes between India and Europe. However, in 1578 King Sebastian of Portugal was killed at the battle of "Field of the Three Kings" in Morocco (which Portugal had long hoped to conquer), along with the majority of his force, destroying a central part of Portugal's land armies.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1580 the throne of Portugal was given over to the Habsburg kings of Spain, partially a result of the Portuguese weakness after the demise of its own king. At the same time, Portuguese power in both the east and west was declining due to a lack of skilled sailors available in Portugal. The English and the Dutch had also been amassing large navies, and began expanding their spheres of influence along routes traditionally held solely by the Portuguese. Although the Portuguese wrested national control back from the Spanish in a 1640 revolt, they lost their control in Malacca, Ceylon, Cochin, Hormuz, among many others to the Dutch or other seafaring nations. With their eastern territories diminishing, Brazil, discovered by Pedro Alvares Cabral in 1500, became increasingly important.[PARAGRAPH:2]Gold was discovered in Brazil in 1690, which had previously been exploited mostly for its dyewood, sugar, diamonds, tobacco and slaves. The ensuing gold rush boosted the population of Brazil from 200,000 in 1650 to 1.5 million in 1770. Brazil today remains the largest Portuguese-speaking country in the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1808, French troops under Napoleon Bonaparte invaded Portugal, forcing the prince regent, Dom Joo, to flee to Brazil and set up a new government. In 1821, the royal family moved back to Portugal after reclaiming the country. Dom Joo stayed behind, and then his son, Dom Pedro I, ruled Brazil until the country broke away from its mother country, declaring independence in 1822.[PARAGRAPH:2]After losing Brazil, Portugal focused on building its African acquisitions in order to compete with their British and French counterparts. However, after World War II, the majority of European nations began abandoning their outlying colonies. India forcibly retook the Portuguese colonies still in their territory. In 1974, a democratic government was established in Portugal. This new government negotiated the release of its African holdings, which were promptly devastated by civil war and vicious in-fighting generated by the Cold War.[PARAGRAPH:2]Today Portugal is ruled from its capital in Lisbon as a democratic republic under the constitution of 1976. It remains an important participant in the European Union as well as one of the major environmental reformers of Europe.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[TAB]这片包括现代葡萄牙在内的地区，最初由凯尔特人部落在公元前1000年左右建立，后来被西哥特人和摩尔人征服。阿斯图里亚的基督教国王最终把摩尔人赶出了这个地区；葡萄牙这个新国家是在脱离西班牙统治后形成的。[第2段]葡萄牙是欧洲世界第一个以国际为基础的伟大海洋帝国之一。1415年至1665年间，葡萄牙在非洲东部和西部沿海建立了一系列休憩和加油港口，以期最终抵达印度利润丰厚的海岸。1498年，当瓦斯科・达加马到达科日科德（当时称为卡利克特）时，他们实现了自己的目标。在这一时期，阿拉伯人（先前在印度洋垄断香料贸易）和葡萄牙人之间发生了几场重要的战斗，其中最重要的一场是1509年在迪乌附近战胜了埃及古吉拉特舰队。这场胜利确保了葡萄牙在印度洋的海上优势，并使他们能够利用印度和欧洲之间丰富的香料贸易路线。然而，1578年，葡萄牙国王塞巴斯蒂安（Sebastian）在摩洛哥的“三王之地”战役中阵亡（葡萄牙一直希望征服这场战役），连同他的大部分兵力，摧毁了葡萄牙陆军的一个中心部分。[第2段]1580年，葡萄牙的王位被交给了西班牙的哈布斯堡国王，部分原因是葡萄牙国王去世后的虚弱。与此同时，由于葡萄牙缺乏熟练的水手，葡萄牙在东西方的势力都在下降。英国和荷兰也一直在集结大型海军，并开始沿着传统上只由葡萄牙人控制的航线扩大势力范围。尽管葡萄牙人在1640年的叛乱中从西班牙人手中夺回了国家控制权，但他们在马六甲、锡兰、科钦、霍尔木兹等地的控制权却被荷兰或其他航海国夺回。随着东部领土的减少，佩德罗・阿尔瓦雷斯・卡布拉尔在1500年发现的巴西变得越来越重要。[第2段]1690年巴西发现了黄金，此前黄金主要被用来开采染料、糖、钻石、烟草和奴隶。随后的淘金热使巴西人口从1650年的20万增加到1770年的150万。今天的巴西仍然是世界上最大的葡萄牙语国家。1821年，皇室收回葡萄牙后搬回葡萄牙。多姆乔伊留下来，然后他的儿子多姆佩德罗一世统治巴西，直到该国脱离其祖国，于1822年宣布独立。[第2段]在失去巴西后，葡萄牙专注于建立其非洲收购，以便与英国和法国同行竞争。然而，在第二次世界大战之后，大多数欧洲国家开始放弃他们的边远殖民地。印度强行夺回仍在其领土上的葡萄牙殖民地。1974年，葡萄牙成立了民主政府。这个新政府通过谈判释放了它在非洲的财产，这些财产很快就被内战所摧毁，并在冷战所引发的恶战中被摧毁。它仍然是欧盟的重要参与者，也是欧洲主要的环境改革者之一。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Portugal -->
  <!-- Civilization Austria -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Austrians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>奥地利文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Austria</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>奥地利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Austrian:Austrians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>奥地利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Austria was first settled by various Celtic tribes. Noricum, a Celtic kingdom, was claimed by the Roman Empire and made a province. After the Roman Empire's fall, Austria was invaded by Bavarians, Slavs, and Avars. When Charlemagne conquered the land in 788, he encouraged colonization and Christianity. Austria, now part of Eastern Francia, was under the control of the house of Babenberg. In 976, the area known as Marchia Orientalis was given to Leopold of Babenberg in 976.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first record of the land being known as Austria is in 966 when referring to the territory of the Babenberg March. The following centuries are characterized by the early settlements of the country. In 1156, the Privilegium Minus elevated Austria to the duchy statues. The Babenbergs also gained the Duchy of Styria in 1192.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the death of Frederick II in 1246, the Barenberg line ended. Otakar II of Bohemia effectively controlled the duchies of Austria. After his defeat and Durnkrut by Rudolf I of Germany in 1278, his reign came to an end. The following centuries would mark a time of Austrian prosperity, under the ruling dynasty, the Habsburgs. In the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries, the Habsburgs accumulated provinces in the area of the Duchy of Austria. In 1438, Duke Albert V of Austria was chosen as the successor to his father-in-law, Emperor Sigismund. Although Albert ruled for only a year, from that time on, every emperor of the Holy Roman Empire was a Habsburg, with one exception.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Habsburgs began to accumulate lands over the years, and in 1477 the Archduke Maximilian acquired most of the Low Countries after marrying the heiress of Burgundy. His son Philip the Fair married the heiress of Castile and Aragon, and acquired Spain and its Italian, African, and New World adjuncts for the Habsburgs.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the Battle of Mohacs, Austrian rulers expanded their territories. However, the Ottoman expansion into Hungary led to frequent conflicts between the two powers. The long reign of Leopold I ended the Austrian conflict with the Turks. Following the defense of Vienna in 1628, a series of campaigns resulted in the return of Hungary to Austrian Control in 1699. However, during the latter part of the reign of Emperor Charles VI, Austria surrendered some of these gains. After this time, the age of Austrian-Prussian dualism began in Hungary.[PARAGRAPH:2]Various defeats against Napoleon spelled the end of the old Holy Roman Empire in 1806, and in 1804 the Austrian Empire was founded. In 1867, it was transformed into the dual-monarchy of Austria-Hungary. Following the Napoleonic wars, Austria emerged as one of Europe's dominant powers along with Prussia and Russia. In 1815, the German Confederation was founded under the presidency of Austria. Austria and Prussia were one of the two leading powers. After Germany wished to become a unified country, Austria was unwilling to become part of it and grew out of Germany, while Prussia grew into it. Following the defeat of Prussia at the battle of Koniggratz in Bohemia, Austria had to leave the German Confederation and was subsequently no longer permitted to take part in German politics.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Austro-Hungarian Compromise of 1867 provided a dual sovereignty under Franz Joseph I, who ruled until his death. The diversity of the empire made it difficult to control in an age of emerging nationalist movements. The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914 was the probable cause of World War I, which led to the downfall of the Austro-Hungarian Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1918 and 1919, Austria was known as the Republic of German Austria. The monarchy was, however, dissolved in 1919 and a parliamentary democracy was set up in 1920. In 1922, Austria was given a loan to improve the general economic condition. With the granting of the loan, Austria passed from an independent state to the control exercised by the League of Nations. At the time, the real ruler of Austria became the League, through its commissioner in Vienna.[PARAGRAPH:2]The First Austrian Republic lasted until 1933. The two major parties fought each other within the parliament. After the Austrian Civil War in 1934, several members of the Schutzbund Party were executed and the Social Democratic Party was outlawed. In 1936, German troops occupied the country and Hitler, a native of Austria himself, lost citizenship in 1925. Just before the collapse of the Third Reich, Karl Renner set up a Provisional Government in Vienna. Much like Germany, Austria, too, was divided into a British, French, a Soviet and an American Zone and governed by the Allied Commission for Austria.[PARAGRAPH:2]On May 1955, Austria regained independence and declared itself permanently neutral, which it remains today. The political system of the Second Republic came to be characterized by the system of Proporz, meaning that most posts of some political importance were split evenly between members of the Social Democrats and the People's Party. Today, Austria has five major parties: the SPO (Labour Party), the OVP (Conservatives), the Greens (Environmentalists), and FPO (nationalists). Austria became a member of the European Union in 1995, and has retained its constitutional neutrality.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>奥地利最早是由凯尔特部落建立的。诺里库姆，凯尔特王国，被罗马帝国占领并成为一个省。罗马帝国灭亡后，奥地利遭到巴伐利亚人、斯拉夫人和阿瓦尔人的侵略。当查理曼在788年征服这片土地时，他鼓励殖民和基督教。奥地利现在是东弗朗西娅的一部分，由巴本贝格家族控制。976年，巴本贝格的利奥波德于976年获得了被称为东方马基亚的地区。[第2段]当提到巴本贝格进军的领土时，第一个被称为奥地利的记录是在966年。接下来的几个世纪以该国早期的定居点为特点。1156年，特权减掉奥地利的公爵雕像。巴本贝格家族也在1192年获得了斯蒂里亚公爵领地（Duchy of Styria）。[第2段]随着腓特烈二世（Frederick II）在1246年去世，巴本贝格家族也结束了。波希米亚的奥塔卡二世有效地控制了奥地利的公爵领地。他在1278年被德国鲁道夫一世击败和德伦克鲁特之后，他的统治结束了。接下来的几个世纪将标志着奥地利在哈布斯堡王朝统治下的繁荣时期。在十四和十五世纪，哈布斯堡人在奥地利公爵领地积累了许多省份。1438年，奥地利阿尔伯特五世公爵被选为其岳父西吉斯蒙德皇帝的继承人。尽管阿尔伯特只统治了一年，但从那时起，神圣罗马帝国的每一位皇帝都是哈布斯堡人，只有一个例外。[第2段]哈布斯堡人多年来开始积累土地，1477年，马克西米利安大公与勃艮第女继承人结婚后，获得了大部分低地国家。他的儿子菲利浦集市嫁给了卡斯蒂利亚和阿拉贡的女继承人，并为哈布斯堡家族获得了西班牙及其意大利、非洲和新大陆的附属国。然而，奥斯曼帝国向匈牙利的扩张导致了两个大国之间频繁的冲突。利奥波德的长期统治结束了奥地利与土耳其的冲突。在1628年保卫维也纳之后，一系列的战役导致匈牙利在1699年回到奥地利的控制之下。然而，在查理六世统治后期，奥地利交出了其中的一部分。此后，奥地利-普鲁士二元论的时代开始于匈牙利。[第2段]对拿破仑的种种失败意味着1806年旧神圣罗马帝国的终结，1804年奥地利帝国成立。1867年，它转变为奥匈帝国的双重君主政体。拿破仑战争后，奥地利与普鲁士和俄罗斯一起成为欧洲的主要强国之一。1815年，德国联邦在奥地利总统的领导下成立。奥地利和普鲁士是两个主要大国之一。在德国希望成为一个统一的国家之后，奥地利不愿意成为德国的一部分，并从德国成长起来，而普鲁士则成长为德国。普鲁士在波希米亚的科尼格拉茨战役中战败后，奥地利不得不离开德国联邦，随后不再被允许参与德国政治。[第2段]1867年奥匈妥协提供了弗朗茨・约瑟夫一世（Franz Joseph I）的双重主权，约瑟夫一世一直统治到他去世。帝国的多样性使得在一个民族主义运动兴起的时代很难控制。1914年弗兰兹・费迪南德大公遇刺是第一次世界大战的可能原因，这场战争导致奥匈帝国垮台。[第2段]1918年和1919年，奥地利被称为德奥共和国。然而，1919年君主制解体，1920年建立了议会民主制度。1922年，奥地利获得贷款以改善总体经济状况。随着贷款的发放，奥地利从一个独立的国家移交给了国际联盟的控制。当时，奥地利真正的统治者通过其驻维也纳的专员成为联盟（League）。[第2段]第一个奥地利共和国持续到1933年。两个主要政党在议会内互相争斗。1934年奥地利内战后，舒茨邦德党的几名成员被处决，社会民主党被取缔。1936年，德国军队占领了这个国家，希特勒本人也是奥地利人，1925年失去了公民身份。就在第三帝国垮台前，卡尔・伦纳在维也纳成立了临时政府。奥地利和德国一样，也被划分为英、法、苏、美三个区，由奥地利同盟委员会（Allied Commission for Austria）管辖。[第2段]1955年5月，奥地利重新获得独立，并宣布永久中立，至今仍保持中立。第二共和国的政治制度以比例制度为特征，即大多数具有一定政治意义的职位在社会民主党和人民党之间平均分配。今天，奥地利有五大政党：SPO（工党）、OVP（保守党）、Greens（环保主义者）和FPO（民族主义者）。奥地利于1995年成为欧盟成员国，并保持其宪法中立性。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Austria -->
  <!-- Civilization Ottoman -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Ottomans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>突厥文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Turkey</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>土耳其</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Ottoman:Ottomans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>奥斯曼</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Ottoman Empire was a Turkish state situated upon the eastern Mediterranean that lasted for some 630 years, from 1299 - 1922 AD. At the height of its power, in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, the Ottoman domains stretched across vast regions in Anatolia, the Balkans, the Near East and northern Africa. For several centuries it was one of the foremost military powers in the world (until it began to stagnate technologically and fell far behind its competitors).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottoman state began as a vassal of the earlier Seljuk Turks, who had formed a large empire in the Near East in the eleventh century. When the Seljuk state of Rum in Anatolia collapsed, the Ottomans took advantage of the ensuing power vacuum and rose in power. According to tradition, Osman I became the bey, or chief, of the state of Sgt in 1281. When Osman captured the Byzantine city of Bilecik in 1299, he declared his state's independence from the Seljuks. This is the traditional date given as the foundation of the Ottoman Empire - which was named after its first leader, Osman.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans expanded rapidly in Anatolia throughout the fourteenth century. A series of capable military leaders made many gains against the tottering Byzantine state. The important cities of Nicaea and Nicomedia fell in 1331 and 1337, and by the 1360s the Ottomans had crossed over into Europe and began capturing territory in Thrace. As a sign of this growing power, Murad I declared himself a sultan (or king) in 1383. Around the year 1400, Timur invaded Anatolia. This caused a great deal of disruption, but the Ottomans bounced back and continued to make territorial gains. Under the rule of Mehmed II, the Ottomans attacked and captured Constantinople, whose mighty walls finally fell to the cannon of the Ottomans. This destroyed the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottomans made Constantinople their capital. Mehmed II became known as "Mehmed the Conqueror." Suleiman I, also known as Suleiman the Magnificent, continued to expand and consolidate the Empire; the Ottomans were at the height of their power and influence during his reign[PARAGRAPH:2]After the capture of Constantinople the Ottoman state virtually adopted the Byzantine civil service to run the empire, and its administration was generally sound (until the nineteenth century, when it began to fossilize and became outdated). The Ottoman Empire was very much a pre-modern dynastic state, made up of many different nationalities - in fact, Greeks largely ran its bureaucracy and were vital to its continued success. Militarily, the Ottomans were very strong largely because of their early adoption of gunpowder and their powerful cavalry forces. The military also employed elite slave soldiers known as "janissaries" who won victory after victory for the expanding Ottoman state. The military remained powerful until the late eighteenth century, when they fell fatally behind Western Europe in military technology.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans were known for their religious tolerance. The Empire was an Islamic state, and Islamic law dominated its legal system, but non-Muslims were generally well treated and enjoyed the freedom to worship their own religion. The Ottoman Empire was long seen as a refuge for Jews across Europe. Economically, the Ottoman Empire was somewhat of a failure. Most of the region's commerce was carried on by Greek or Italian merchants, which slowed the development of Turkish industry. Once the European voyages of exploration found new routes to India and China which did not involve passing through the Near East, the Ottoman Empire began a slow commercial decline.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the start of the nineteenth century, the Ottoman Empire still held enormous amounts of land, but the empire was stagnant and corrupt, and was widely viewed as the "sick man of Europe." The western powers, their commercial and military strength exploding under the influence of the Industrial Revolution, began to snap up vulnerable Ottoman territories. Britain and France forced humiliating commercial treaties on the Ottomans, and the Ottoman state was forced to take out massive loans to cover its debts - the start of a vicious cycle which only incurred more debt for the empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]While some positive reforms were carried out in terms of modernizing the Ottoman state, custom and tradition prevented the reformers from moving fast enough. Furthermore, the rising tide of nationalism began to tear the empire apart, as Serbians, Bulgarians, Romanians, and Greeks all declared their independence and set up their own nations. By the outbreak of World War I, the Ottomans had lost virtually all of their holdings in Europe. Desperate to preserve what was left, the Ottomans threw in their lot with the Central Powers (Germany and Austria), only to be defeated by a British-led Arab revolt in the Near East. When the war ended the victors partitioned and dissolved the Ottoman Empire at the Paris Peace Conference. However, the Turkish Revolution prevented the planned division of Anatolia from taking place. With the creation of the nation of Turkey in 1922, and the deposition of the final sultan Mehmed VI, the Ottoman Empire came to a close.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>奥斯曼帝国是一个土耳其国家，位于东地中海，从公元1299年到1922年，历时约630年。在其鼎盛时期，在16和17世纪，奥斯曼帝国的版图横跨安纳托利亚、巴尔干、近东和北非的广大地区。几个世纪以来，它一直是世界上最重要的军事强国之一（直到它开始在技术上停滞不前，远远落后于它的竞争对手）。[第2段]奥斯曼帝国开始是早期塞尔柱土耳其人的附庸，塞尔柱土耳其人在11世纪在近东建立了一个大帝国。当安纳托利亚的塞尔柱朗姆酒州崩溃时，奥斯曼人利用随之而来的权力真空而崛起。根据传统，奥斯曼一世在1281年成为了Sgt州的首领。当奥斯曼在1299年占领拜占庭的比莱克城时，他宣布自己的国家从塞尔柱独立出来。这是奥斯曼帝国成立的传统日期，它以其第一任领导人奥斯曼命名。[段：2 ]奥斯曼人在整个十四世纪安纳托利亚迅速扩张。一系列有能力的军事领导人在对抗摇摇欲坠的拜占庭国家时取得了许多成果。尼西亚和尼科米底亚的重要城市在1331年和1337年沦陷，到了13世纪60年代，奥斯曼人越过边境进入欧洲，开始占领色雷斯的领土。1383年，穆拉德一世宣布自己为苏丹（或国王），以示权力的增长。公元1400年左右，帖木儿入侵安纳托利亚。这造成了巨大的破坏，但奥斯曼帝国反弹并继续取得领土利益。在穆罕默德二世的统治下，奥斯曼帝国进攻并占领了君士坦丁堡，君士坦丁堡的强大城墙最终落入奥斯曼帝国的大炮之下。这摧毁了拜占庭帝国，奥斯曼帝国将君士坦丁堡作为首都。穆罕默德二世被称为“征服者穆罕默德”，苏莱曼一世，也被称为苏莱曼大帝，继续扩张和巩固帝国；奥斯曼帝国在君士坦丁堡被攻占后，在其统治期间处于权力和影响力的顶峰[第2段]，奥斯曼帝国实际上采用了拜占庭式的公务员制度来管理帝国，其管理总体上是健全的（直到19世纪，它开始僵化并过时）。奥斯曼帝国在很大程度上是一个前现代王朝的国家，由许多不同的民族组成――事实上，希腊人在很大程度上管理着它的官僚机构，对它的持续成功至关重要。在军事上，奥斯曼帝国非常强大，主要是因为他们早期使用火药和强大的骑兵部队。军队还雇佣了被称为“janissaries”的精锐奴隶士兵，他们为扩张的奥斯曼帝国赢得了一次又一次的胜利。直到十八世纪末，当他们在军事技术上严重落后于西欧时，军事力量才得以保持强大。帝国是一个伊斯兰国家，伊斯兰法律主导其法律体系，但非穆斯林普遍受到良好待遇，享有信仰自己宗教的自由。奥斯曼帝国长期以来被视为整个欧洲犹太人的避难所。在经济上，奥斯曼帝国有点失败。该地区的大部分商业活动是由希腊或意大利商人进行的，这减缓了土耳其工业的发展。一旦欧洲的探险之旅发现了通往印度和中国的新航线，而这些航线并不涉及通过近东，奥斯曼帝国就开始了缓慢的商业衰落。[第2段]到19世纪初，奥斯曼帝国仍然拥有大量的土地，但帝国却停滞不前，腐败不堪，在工业革命的影响下，西方列强的商业和军事实力迅速膨胀，开始抢占脆弱的奥斯曼帝国领土。英国和法国强迫奥斯曼帝国签订羞辱性的商业条约，奥斯曼帝国被迫发放巨额贷款来偿还债务，这是一个恶性循环的开始，只会给帝国带来更多的债务，习俗和传统阻碍了改革者的行动。此外，随着塞尔维亚人、保加利亚人、罗马尼亚人和希腊人都宣布独立并建立了自己的国家，民族主义的浪潮开始将帝国撕裂。到第一次世界大战爆发时，奥斯曼人几乎失去了在欧洲的所有财产。奥斯曼帝国为了保存仅存的东西，不顾一切地向中央列强（德国和奥地利）抛出了自己的命运，结果被英国领导的近东阿拉伯起义击败。战争结束后，胜利者在巴黎和平会议上分裂并解散了奥斯曼帝国。然而，土耳其革命阻止了计划中的安纳托利亚分裂。随着1922年土耳其民族的建立，以及最后一任苏丹穆罕默德六世的宣誓就职，奥斯曼帝国走到了尽头。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Ottoman -->
  <!-- Civilization Sweden -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Swedish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>瑞典文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Sweden</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>瑞典</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Swedish:Swedish</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>瑞典</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Little is known of Swedish history before the Viking period of the late 8th century. Two related peoples, the Svear and the Gtar, then lived in south central Sweden. Almost incessantly at war with each other, they united in the 9th century under the control of Svear. The Swedish name for Sweden, Sverige, means "realm of the Svear." Swedish Vikings sailed eastward across the Baltic Sea and into the rivers of Russia. By the 9th and 10th centuries they were doing business as far east as Constantinople. According to legend, a Swedish Viking chieftain, Rurik, was the creator of the first Russian monarchy. Finland came under Swedish rule in the 12th century. In 1397 the Union of Kalmar joined the kingdoms of Sweden, Denmark, and Norway under the Danish monarchy. The Swedes opposed Danish command, which ended in 1523, when Gustavus Vasa came to the Swedish throne as King Gustav I.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under Gustav I and his successors, Sweden became a martial power. Two Swedish monarchs were famed as warrior kings. Gustav II, also known as Gustavus Adolphus, won great triumphs in the Thirty Years' War. As an effect of this war, Sweden increased land in northern Germany and became master of the Baltic region. In 1638, Sweden founded a brief colony in America called New Sweden. Continually challenged by its neighbors, Sweden fought a series of wars with Denmark, Russia, Poland, and Saxony during the early 18th century. The Swedish king Charles XII won first impressive victories. But his devastating defeat by the Russian Tsar Peter the Great in 1709 commenced Sweden's decline as a European power.[PARAGRAPH:2]The loss of Finland to Russia in 1809 led to the deposition of King Gustav IV. A new constitution was adopted and a Frenchman, Jean Baptiste Bernadotte, was chosen as the Swedish crown prince. After Napoleon's defeat in 1814, Norway was taken from Denmark and given to Sweden to substitute its loss of Finland. The union of Sweden and Norway lasted until 1905, when Norway peacefully gained its independence. Bernadotte came to the throne in 1818 as King Charles XIV John and was the founder of the present Swedish royal house.[PARAGRAPH:2]The constant years of war impoverished Sweden. A lack of financial prospects caused a large number of Swedes to emigrate from the country. Sweden was never again to go to war, adopting the policy of neutrality and nonalignment that continues today. The growth of Swedish industry in the early 20th century restored its economy. Sweden also developed its social welfare system that guaranteed the needs of existence to every Swedes. Sweden was able to uphold its neutrality in both World War I and II, establishing itself as a haven for refugees escaping the damage of both these wars. Sweden has also sought to promote peace in not only itself, but in all countries. Many of Sweden's troops served in the United Nations peacekeeping forces.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]在8世纪末的北欧海盗时期之前，瑞典历史鲜为人知。两个相关的民族，斯韦尔人和盖尔人，当时居住在瑞典中南部。他们几乎不停地打仗，9世纪在斯韦尔的控制下联合起来。瑞典的名字，斯韦里奇，意思是“斯韦尔王国”。瑞典海盗向东航行，穿过波罗的海，进入俄罗斯的河流。到了9世纪和10世纪，他们在遥远的东方，如君士坦丁堡做生意。根据传说，瑞典海盗首领鲁里克是第一个俄国君主政体的创造者。芬兰在12世纪被瑞典统治。1397年，卡尔马尔联盟加入了瑞典、丹麦和挪威王国的丹麦君主政体。瑞典人反对丹麦的指挥权，直到1523年古斯塔夫一世和他的继任者古斯塔夫一世即位，瑞典才成为一个军事强国。两位瑞典君主被誉为勇士国王。古斯塔夫二世，又称古斯塔夫・阿道夫，在三十年的战争中取得了巨大的胜利。由于这场战争的影响，瑞典在德国北部增加了土地，成为波罗的海地区的主人。1638年，瑞典在美国建立了一个短暂的殖民地，称为新瑞典。在18世纪早期，瑞典不断受到邻国的挑战，与丹麦、俄罗斯、波兰和萨克森进行了一系列战争。瑞典国王查理十二世赢得了第一个令人印象深刻的胜利。但1709年他惨败于俄国沙皇彼得大帝，开始了瑞典作为欧洲强国的衰落。[第2段]1809年芬兰输给俄国，导致古斯塔夫四世国王宣誓就职。新宪法通过，法国人让巴蒂斯特・贝纳多特被选为瑞典王储。1814年拿破仑战败后，挪威被从丹麦夺走，交给瑞典以代替失去芬兰。瑞典和挪威的联盟一直持续到1905年，挪威和平获得独立。1818年，伯纳多特以查理十四世约翰国王的身份登基，并成为瑞典王室的创始人。由于缺乏经济前景，许多瑞典人移居国外。瑞典再也没有开战，采取了中立和不结盟的政策，这种政策一直延续到今天。20世纪初瑞典工业的发展恢复了经济。瑞典还发展了社会福利制度，保证每个瑞典人的生存需要。瑞典在第一次和第二次世界大战中都保持中立，成为难民逃离这两次战争破坏的避难所。瑞典还寻求不仅在本国，而且在所有国家促进和平。瑞典的许多部队在联合国维和部队服役。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Sweden -->
  <!-- Civilization Dutch -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Dutch</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>荷兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Netherlands</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>尼德兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Dutch</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>荷兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Originally several separate territories under the control of the Holy Roman Empire, and then united into one state under Habsburg rule (16th century), the Netherlands did not acquire national independence until the conclusion of the Eighty Years' War (1568-1648 AD) when the Spanish formally renounced all claims to Dutch sovereignty in the Treaty of Mnster.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Eighty Years' War was sparked by Spanish religious oppression and an occupation by Spanish forces led by the Duke of Alba, during which over one thousand people were sentenced to death, including two prominent and popular Dutch nobles; these actions caused dissention among the Dutch people. In 1568 Willem, Prince of Orange, returned from a self-imposed exile (in order to avoid prosecution by the Duke of Alba) and led the uprising against the Spanish occupation.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Dutch fight for independence can be seen as a war against religious oppression, with the Pacification of Ghent treaty being a written representation of this sentiment. Signed on November 8th, 1576 the document specified an alliance between the Dutch provinces, in which religious differences would be put aside for the purposes of expelling the Spanish and restoring local provincial control to the Netherlands.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the seventeenth century the Dutch began using their large military and merchant navies to both create their own trading posts along the African coast and rob those of the Portuguese in an effort to reach valuable markets in India and Indonesia. The inrush of treasure, trade and knowledge from these trading and military expeditions was extremely beneficial, and during this first half of the seventeenth century the Dutch experienced a Golden Age of cultural and economic growth. This Golden Age would soon come to a crushing end.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1795, France, under Napoleon I, conquered the Dutch mainland. The Netherlands quickly declined in influence and power, locally and internationally, with the British taking most of their colonial possessions. After Napoleon was defeated a few colonial territories were restored to the Dutch and remained under their control until the decolonization of the twentieth century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Many historians regard the Dutch empire as the first truly capitalist country. In addition to developing the first stock exchange, many modern services such as corporate insurance and retirement funds were attributed to Dutch inventiveness.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Netherlands is also the birthplace of one of the world's early democratic institutions - the Dutch Water Boards. Due to the unique topography of the Netherlands - about half of the mainland is a foot or more under sea level - the country's waterways must be constantly monitored and controlled in order to prevent flooding that would result in tremendous loss of life and property. Each Water Board is in charge of one of the nation's 27 water districts and all matters pertaining to local water management. The creation of these water boards predates the Netherlands itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]The modern Netherlands, with a diverse population and liberal laws towards drugs, prostitution, abortion, same-sex marriage, and euthanasia, has been a constant haven for refugees from other countries. Cultural minorities are encouraged to protect their own cultural identity while at the same time integrate into Dutch culture at large, further reinforcing the open-minded ideals for which Dutch ancestors fought and died.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[表]最初几个独立的领土在神圣罗马帝国的控制下，然后在哈布斯堡统治下（16世纪）统一为一个州，荷兰直到八十年战争（公元1568-1648年）结束才获得国家独立，当时西班牙人正式放弃了Mnster条约中对荷兰主权的所有主张。[第2段]八十年战争的导火索是西班牙的宗教压迫和阿尔巴公爵领导的西班牙军队的占领，在这期间，一千多人被判处死刑，其中包括两个著名和受欢迎的荷兰贵族；这些行为在荷兰人民中引起了不同意见。1568年，奥兰治王子威廉从一个自我放逐的地方回来（为了避免阿尔巴公爵的起诉），领导了反对西班牙占领的起义，《根特条约》的和平化正是这种情绪的书面表现。1576年11月8日签署的这份文件明确规定了荷兰各省之间的同盟关系，在同盟关系中，为了驱逐西班牙人和恢复对荷兰的地方省控制，将搁置宗教分歧。[第2段]在17世纪，荷兰开始使用其庞大的军事和商业海军双方都在非洲海岸建立自己的贸易站，抢夺葡萄牙人的贸易站，以期在印度和印度尼西亚开拓有价值的市场。从这些贸易和军事远征中涌入的财富、贸易和知识极为有益，在17世纪上半叶，荷兰人经历了文化和经济增长的黄金时代。1795年，拿破仑一世统治下的法国征服了荷兰大陆。荷兰在当地和国际上的影响力和权力迅速下降，英国人夺走了他们大部分的殖民地财产。拿破仑被打败后，一些殖民地重新归荷兰人控制，直到20世纪的非殖民化。除了发展第一家证券交易所外，许多现代服务，如企业保险和退休基金，都归功于荷兰的创造性。[第2段]荷兰也是世界上早期民主制度之一的发源地荷兰水利委员会。由于荷兰独特的地形――大约一半的大陆在海平面以下1英尺或1英尺以上――该国的水道必须不断受到监测和控制，以防止洪水造成巨大的生命和财产损失。每个水务委员会负责全国27个水区中的一个，以及与当地水管理有关的所有事务。这些水务局的建立早于荷兰本身。[第2段]现代荷兰人口多样，对毒品、卖淫、堕胎、同性婚姻和安乐死的法律自由，一直是其他国家难民的避风港。鼓励文化少数民族保护自己的文化身份，同时融入整个荷兰文化，进一步强化荷兰祖先为之奋斗和牺牲的开放理想。</Chinese>
    </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Dutch -->
  <!-- Civilization Lithuania -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Lithuanians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>立陶宛文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Lithuania</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>立陶宛</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Lithuanian:Lithuanians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>立陶宛</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The history of Lithuania between 1219 and 1295 deals with the establishment and early history of the first Lithuanian state, the Grand Duchy of Lithuania. The beginning of the 13th century marks the end of the prehistory of Lithuania. From this point on the history of Lithuania is recorded in chronicles, treaties, and other written documents. In 1219, twenty-one Lithuanian dukes signed a peace treaty with Halych-Volhynia. This event is widely accepted as the first proof that the Baltic tribes were uniting and consolidating.[PARAGRAPH:2]Mindaugas, the duke who governed southern Lithuania between the Neman and Neris Rivers, eventually became the founder of the state. Mindaugas is referred to as the ruler of all Lithuania in the Livonian Rhymed Chronicle in 1236. The means by which he managed to acquire this title are not well-known. In 1251, Mindaugas agreed to receive baptism and relinquish control over some lands in western Lithuania, for which he was to receive a crown in return. As promised, Mindaugas was crowned at some time during the summer of 1253 (The exact date and location of the coronation is not known), and the Kingdom of Lithuania, proclaimed by the pope in 1251, was soundly established. Pope Innocent IV supported Mindaugas, hoping that a new Christian state could stem the inroads being made by the Golden Horde, a state of Mongol Empire. On July 17, 1251, the pope signed two crucial papal bulls. One of them ordered the Bishop of Chelm to crown Mindaugas as King of Lithuania, appoint a bishop for Lithuania, and to build a cathedral.[PARAGRAPH:2]Immediately after his coronation, Mindaugas transferred some western lands to the Livonian Order - portions of Samogitia, Nadruva, and Dainava. There is some discussion as to whether in later years Mindaugas gave even more lands to the Order. Relative peace and stability was established for about eight more years. Mindaugas used this opportunity to concentrate on expansion to the east. The Livonian Order used this period to consolidate their control over Samogitian lands. The Samogitians responded by electing Algminas as their war leader. In 1259, the Livonian Order lost the Battle of Skuodas, and in 1260, it lost the Battle of Durbe. The first loss encouraged a rebellion by the Semigalians, and the later loss spurred the Prussians into an uprising against the Order. Encouraged by Treniota, his nephew, Mindaugas broke peace with the Order. Some chronicles hint that he also relapsed into his former pagan beliefs. All the diplomatic achievements made since his coronation were lost. As a result of the war, Mindaugas was assassinated by the Order and Lithuania lapsed into political chaos.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1295, a new dynasty rose: the Gediminids. The Gediminids were to rule Lithuania for the next several centuries. Vytenis, the first Gediminid ruler, was able to recapture lands lost after the death of Mindaugus, and established a defensive network along his border with the Teutonic Order. Lithuanian expansion reached its height under Gediminas, who annexed or vassalized most of Kieven Rus, and parts of the Golden Horde. Lithuania reached its peak under Vytautas the Great, who backed economic development of his state and introduced many reforms. Under his rule the Grand Duchy of Lithuania slowly became more centralized, as the governors loyal to Vytautas replaced local princes with dynastic ties to the throne. Under Vytautas, Lithuanian and Polish forces defeated the Teutonic Order.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, in the 16th century, Moscow began making aggressive expansion west, and Lithuania developed closer ties with Poland, eventually unifying under the Treaty of Lublin. However, after the partitions of Poland, Lithuania was annexed by Russia. During the Napoleonic Wars, French forces proclaimed a new Grand Duchy, which never materialized, as shorty afterwards Napoleon's forces were pushed west by the Russians, who again annexed Lithuania. Lithuania remained part of Russia until after World War I, where it was formed as a new Republic. During World War II, however, Soviet forces annexed Lithuania. Following a brief occupation by Nazi forces shortly afterwards, Lithuania was absorbed into the USSR. In the early 1990s, Lithuania restored its sovereignty and now continues to grow into an economically strong country.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]立陶宛1219年至1295年的历史涉及立陶宛第一个国家立陶宛大公国的建立和早期历史。13世纪初标志着立陶宛史前时代的结束。从这一点上讲，立陶宛的历史记录在编年史、条约和其他书面文件中。1219年，21位立陶宛公爵与Halych Volhynia签署了和平条约。这一事件被广泛接受为波罗的海各部落正在团结和巩固的第一个证据。[第2段]明达格斯公爵，在尼曼河和尼瑞斯河之间统治立陶宛南部，最终成为国家的缔造者。在1236年的利沃尼亚押韵编年史中，明多加斯被称为立陶宛的统治者。他设法获得这一头衔的手段并不为人所知。1251年，明多加斯同意接受洗礼，放弃对立陶宛西部一些土地的控制权，作为回报，他将获得一个王冠。正如所承诺的那样，明多加斯在1253年夏天的某个时候加冕（加冕的确切日期和地点不得而知），1251年由教皇宣布的立陶宛王国也稳固地建立起来。教皇英诺森四世支持明达格斯，希望一个新的基督教国家能够阻止蒙古帝国黄金部落的入侵。1251年7月17日，教皇签署了两个至关重要的教皇公牛。其中一位命令切姆主教将明多加封为立陶宛国王，为立陶宛任命一位主教，并修建一座大教堂。[第2段]明多加在加冕典礼后，立即将一些西部土地转让给利沃尼亚教团――萨莫吉亚、纳德鲁瓦和达尼瓦的一部分。有一些讨论是关于明多加斯在晚年是否给了秩序更多的土地。相对和平与稳定又建立了大约八年。Mindaugas利用这个机会集中精力向东方扩张。利沃尼亚教团利用这一时期巩固了他们对萨莫吉田土地的控制。作为回应，萨莫吉人选举阿尔米纳斯为他们的战争领袖。1259年，利沃尼亚教团在斯库达战役中失败，1260年，它在杜比战役中失败。第一次失利激起了塞米加利人的叛乱，而后来的失利则激起了普鲁士人反抗秩序的起义。在特利奥塔的鼓励下，他的侄子明多加斯打破了秩序。一些编年史暗示，他也重新回到他以前的异教徒信仰。他加冕以来所取得的外交成就全都丧失了。战争的结果是，明达格斯被骑士团暗杀，立陶宛陷入政治混乱。接下来的几个世纪里，格迪米尼王朝将统治立陶宛。维泰尼斯，第一个盖迪米尼德统治者，能够夺回在明德奥古斯死后失去的土地，并在他与日耳曼秩序的边界建立了防御网络。在盖迪米纳斯的统治下，立陶宛的扩张达到了顶峰，盖迪米纳斯吞并或供奉了基文罗斯的大部分地区和黄金部落的部分地区。立陶宛在维塔塔塔斯大帝（Vytautas the Great）的领导下达到了顶峰，维塔塔塔斯大帝支持立陶宛的经济发展，并推行了许多改革。在他的统治下，立陶宛大公国逐渐变得更加集权，效忠维塔塔斯的总督们用王位的王朝关系取代了当地的王子。在维塔塔斯统治下，立陶宛和波兰军队打败了日耳曼帝国。[第2段]然而，在16世纪，莫斯科开始向西侵略扩张，立陶宛与波兰发展了更紧密的关系，最终在卢布林条约下统一起来。然而，波兰分裂后，立陶宛被俄罗斯吞并。在拿破仑战争期间，法国军队宣布建立一个新的大公国，但这个大公国从未实现，因为不久之后拿破仑的军队被俄国人向西推进，俄国人又吞并了立陶宛。立陶宛一直是俄罗斯的一部分，直到第一次世界大战后，立陶宛才成为一个新的共和国。然而，在第二次世界大战期间，苏联军队吞并了立陶宛。不久之后，纳粹军队短暂占领立陶宛，立陶宛被并入苏联。1990年代初，立陶宛恢复了主权，现在继续发展成为一个经济强国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Lithuania -->
  <!-- Civilization Scotland -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Scottish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>苏格兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Scotland</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>苏格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Scottish</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>苏格兰人</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Kingdom of the Picts (based in Fortriu by the 6th century) was the state that eventually became known as "Alba" or "Scotland". The development of "Pictland", according to the historical model developed by Peter Heather, was a natural response to Roman imperialism. Another view places emphasis on the Battle of Dun Nechtain, and the reign of Bridei m. Beli (671-693), with another period of consolidation in the reign of engus mac Fergusa (732-761).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Kingdom of the Picts as it was in the early 8th century, when Bede was writing, was largely the same as the kingdom of the Scots in the reign of Alexander I (1107-1124). However, by the tenth century, the Pictish kingdom was dominated by what we can recognise as Gaelic culture, and had developed a traditional story of an Irish conquest around the ancestor of the contemporary royal dynasty, Cined mac Ailpn (Kenneth MacAlpin).[PARAGRAPH:2]From a base of territory in eastern Scotland north of the River Forth and south of the River Oykel, the kingdom acquired control of the lands lying to the north and south. By the 12th century, the kings of Alba had added to their territories the English-speaking land in the south-east and attained overlordship of Gaelic-speaking Galloway and Norse-speaking Caithness; by the end of the 13th century, the kingdom had assumed approximately its modern borders. However, processes of cultural and economic change beginning in the 12th century ensured Scotland looked very different in the later Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]The push for this change was the reign of David I and the Davidian Revolution. Feudalism, government reorganisation and the first legally recognised towns (called burghs) began in this period. These institutions and the immigration of French and Anglo-French knights and churchmen facilitated cultural osmosis, whereby the culture and language of the low-lying and coastal parts of the kingdom's original territory in the east became, like the newly acquired south-east, English-speaking, while the rest of the country retained the Gaelic language, apart from the Northern Isles of Orkney and Shetland, which remained under Norse rule until 1468. The Scottish state entered a largely successful and stable period between the 12th and 14th centuries, there was relative peace with England, trade and educational links were well developed with the Continent and at the height of this cultural flowering John Duns Scotus was one of Europe's most important and influential philosophers.[PARAGRAPH:2]The death of Alexander III in March 1286, followed by that of his granddaughter Margaret, Maid of Norway, broke the centuries-old succession line of Scotland's kings and shattered the 200-year golden age that began with David I. Edward I of England was asked to arbitrate between claimants for the Scottish crown, and he organised a process known as the Great Cause to identify the most legitimate claimant. John Balliol was pronounced king in the Great Hall of Berwick Castle on 17 November 1292 and inaugurated at Scone on 30 November, St. Andrew's Day. Edward I, who had coerced recognition as Lord Paramount of Scotland, the feudal superior of the realm, steadily undermined John's authority. In 1294, Balliol and other Scottish lords refused Edward's demands to serve in his army against the French. Instead the Scottish parliament sent envoys to France to negotiate an alliance. Scotland and France sealed a treaty on 23 October 1295, known as the Auld Alliance (1295-1560). War ensued and King John was deposed by Edward who took personal control of Scotland. Andrew Moray and William Wallace initially emerged as the principal leaders of the resistance to English rule in what became known as the Wars of Scottish Independence (1296-1328).[PARAGRAPH:2]The nature of the struggle changed significantly when Robert the Bruce, Earl of Carrick, killed his rival John Comyn on 10 February 1306 at Greyfriars Kirk in Dumfries. He was crowned king (as Robert I) less than seven weeks later. Robert I battled to restore Scottish Independence as King for over 20 years, beginning by winning Scotland back from the Norman English invaders piece by piece. Victory at the Battle of Bannockburn in 1314 proved the Scots had regained control of their kingdom. In 1315, Edward Bruce, brother of the King, was briefly appointed High King of Ireland during an ultimately unsuccessful Scottish invasion of Ireland aimed at strengthening Scotland's position in its wars against England. In 1320 the world's first documented declaration of independence, the Declaration of Arbroath, won the support of Pope John XXII, leading to the legal recognition of Scottish sovereignty by the English Crown.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, war with England continued for several decades after the death of Bruce. A civil war between the Bruce dynasty and their long-term Comyn-Balliol rivals lasted until the middle of the 14th century. Although the Bruce dynasty was successful, David II's lack of an heir allowed his half-nephew Robert II to come to the throne and establish the Stewart Dynasty. The Stewarts ruled Scotland for the remainder of the Middle Ages. The country they ruled experienced greater prosperity from the end of the 14th century through the Scottish Renaissance to the Reformation. This was despite continual warfare with England, the increasing division between Highlands and Lowlands, and a large number of royal minorities.[PARAGRAPH:2]This period was the height of the Franco-Scottish alliance. The Scots Guard - la Garde cossaise - was founded in 1418 by Charles VII of France. The Scots soldiers of the Garde cossaise fought alongside Joan of Arc against England during the Hundred Years War. In March 1421, a Franco-Scots force under John Stewart, 2nd Earl of Buchan, and Gilbert de Lafayette, defeated a larger English army at the Battle of Baug? Three years later, at the Battle of Verneuil, the French and Scots lost around 7000 men. The Scottish intervention contributed to France's victory in the war.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1502, James IV of Scotland signed the Treaty of Perpetual Peace with Henry VII of England. He also married Henry's daughter, Margaret Tudor, setting the stage for the Union of the Crowns. For Henry, the marriage into one of Europe's most established monarchies gave legitimacy to the new Tudor royal line. A decade later, James made the fateful decision to invade England in support of France under the terms of the Auld Alliance. He was the last British monarch to die in battle, at the Battle of Flodden. Within a generation the Auld Alliance was ended by the Treaty of Edinburgh. France agreed to withdraw all land and naval forces. In the same year, 1560, John Knox realised his goal of seeing Scotland become a Protestant nation and the Scottish parliament revoke papal authority in Scotland. Mary, Queen of Scots, a Catholic and former queen of France, was forced to abdicate in 1567.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1603, James VI, King of Scots inherited the thrones of the Kingdom of England and the Kingdom of Ireland, and became King James I of England and Ireland, and left Edinburgh for London. With the exception of a short period under the Protectorate, Scotland remained a separate state, but there was considerable conflict between the crown and the Covenanters over the form of church government. The Glorious Revolution of 1688-89 saw the overthrow of the King James VII of Scotland and II of England by the English Parliament in favour of William and Mary. As late as the 1690s, Scotland experienced famine, which reduced the population of parts of the country by at least 20 per cent.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1698, the Scots attempted an ambitious project to secure a trading colony on the Isthmus of Panama. Almost every Scottish landowner who had money to spare is said to have invested in the Darien scheme. Its failure bankrupted these landowners, but not the burghs. Nevertheless, the nobles' bankruptcy, along with the threat of an English invasion, played a leading role in convincing the Scots elite to back a union with England.[PARAGRAPH:2]On 22 July 1706, the Treaty of Union was agreed between representatives of the Scots Parliament and the Parliament of England and the following year twin Acts of Union were passed by both parliaments to create the united Kingdom of Great Britain with effect from 1 May 1707.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>皮克特斯王国（公元6世纪建立在福特里亚）是一个最终被称为“阿尔巴”或“苏格兰”的国家。根据彼得・希瑟的历史模式，“皮克特兰”的发展是对罗马帝国主义的自然反应。另一种观点则强调了邓内克丹战役和布里代・m・贝利（Bridei m.Beli）统治时期（671-693年），还有一个巩固时期是在恩格斯・麦克・费格斯（732-761年）统治时期。[第2段]皮克特人的王国，就像8世纪初贝德写作时一样，与亚历山大一世（1107-1124）统治时期的苏格兰王国大体相同。然而，到了10世纪，皮克特王国被我们认为是盖尔文化的东西所统治，并且发展了一个关于爱尔兰征服当代皇室王朝祖先Cined mac Ailpn（Kenneth MacAlpin）的传统故事在奥伊克尔河以南，王国控制了南北两侧的土地。到了12世纪，阿尔巴国王在他们的领土上增加了东南部讲英语的土地，并获得了讲盖尔语的加洛韦和讲挪威语的凯斯尼斯的统治权；到了13世纪末，王国已经承担了大约其现代边界。然而，从12世纪开始的文化和经济变化过程确保了苏格兰在中世纪后期看起来非常不同。[第2段]推动这种变化的是大卫一世的统治和戴维大革命。封建主义、政府改组和第一个被法律承认的城镇（称为市镇）开始于这一时期。这些机构以及法国和英法骑士和教士的移民促进了文化渗透，从而使王国东部原领土低洼和沿海地区的文化和语言变得像新获得的东南部一样，讲英语，除了奥克尼岛和设得兰岛在1468年之前一直受挪威人统治外，该国其他地区仍保留盖尔语。从12世纪到14世纪，苏格兰国家进入了一个大体上成功和稳定的时期，与英国有了相对的和平，与欧洲大陆的贸易和教育联系十分发达，在文化繁荣的鼎盛时期，约翰・邓斯・斯科特是欧洲最重要和最有影响力的哲学家之一。[第2段]亚历山大三世于1286年3月去世，他的孙女、挪威女仆玛格丽特随后去世，打破了苏格兰国王长达数百年的继承线，打破了始于大卫一世的200年黄金时代。英格兰的爱德华一世被要求在苏格兰皇冠的申领者之间进行仲裁，他组织了一个被称为伟大事业的过程来确定最合法的申领者。约翰巴利奥尔于1292年11月17日在贝里克城堡大会堂被宣布为国王，并于11月30日圣安德鲁节在斯科恩举行就职典礼。爱德华一世曾强迫人们承认他为苏格兰的派拉蒙勋爵，这个国家的封建统治者，他不断地削弱约翰的权威。1294年，巴利奥尔和其他苏格兰贵族拒绝了爱德华的要求，拒绝了他在军队中对抗法国人的要求。相反，苏格兰议会派使节到法国谈判结盟。苏格兰和法国于1295年10月23日签署了一项条约，称为“奥尔德联盟”（1295-1560）。战争接踵而至，约翰国王被爱德华废黜，爱德华亲自控制了苏格兰。安德鲁・莫雷和威廉・华莱士最初是苏格兰独立战争（1296-1328）中反抗英国统治的主要领导人。[第2段]当罗伯特・布鲁斯，卡里克伯爵，于1306年2月10日在格雷弗里亚斯・柯克杀死他的对手约翰・科门时，斗争的性质发生了重大变化在炸薯条里。不到七个星期，他就被加冕为国王（罗伯特一世）。罗伯特一世为恢复苏格兰作为国王的独立进行了20多年的斗争，从一个接一个地从诺曼英国侵略者手中夺回苏格兰开始。1314年班诺克本战役的胜利证明苏格兰人已经重新控制了他们的王国。1315年，爱德华布鲁斯，国王的兄弟，在苏格兰入侵爱尔兰的一次最终失败的战争中，短暂地被任命为爱尔兰的最高国王，旨在加强苏格兰在对英格兰的战争中的地位。1320年，世界上第一份有文件记载的独立宣言《阿布罗斯宣言》获得了教皇约翰二十二世的支持，导致英国王室在法律上承认苏格兰主权。[第2段]当罗伯特・布鲁斯，卡里克伯爵，于1306年2月10日在达姆弗里斯的格雷弗里亚斯・柯克杀死他的对手约翰・科门时，斗争的性质发生了重大变化。不到七个星期，他就被加冕为国王（罗伯特一世）。罗伯特一世为恢复苏格兰作为国王的独立进行了20多年的斗争，从一个接一个地从诺曼英国侵略者手中夺回苏格兰开始。1314年班诺克本战役的胜利证明苏格兰人已经重新控制了他们的王国。1315年，爱德华布鲁斯，国王的兄弟，在苏格兰入侵爱尔兰的一次最终失败的战争中，短暂地被任命为爱尔兰的最高国王，旨在加强苏格兰在对英格兰的战争中的地位。1320年，世界上第一份有文件记载的独立宣言《阿布罗斯宣言》获得了教皇约翰二十二世的支持，导致英国王室在法律上承认苏格兰主权。[第2段]然而，在布鲁斯去世后，与英国的战争持续了几十年。布鲁斯王朝和他们的长期对手科曼・巴利奥尔之间的内战一直持续到14世纪中叶。尽管布鲁斯王朝取得了成功，但大卫二世没有继承人，这使得他同父异母的侄子罗伯特二世登上了王位，建立了斯图尔特王朝。斯图尔特一家在中世纪统治苏格兰。从14世纪末到苏格兰文艺复兴，再到宗教改革，他们统治的国家经历了更大的繁荣。尽管与英国的战争持续不断，高地和低地之间的分裂不断加剧，还有大量的王室少数民族，但这一时期是法苏联盟的鼎盛时期。苏格兰卫队-拉加德奥萨伊-由法国的查理七世于1418年建立。在百年战争中，苏格兰士兵与圣女贞德并肩作战，对抗英国。1421年3月，布坎二世伯爵约翰・斯图尔特（John Stewart）和吉尔伯特・德・拉斐特（Gilbert de Lafayette）领导的一支法苏格兰军队在包格战役中击败了一支规模更大的英国军队？三年后，在凡尔内伊战役中，法国和苏格兰损失了大约7000人。苏格兰的干预促成了法国在战争中的胜利。他还娶了亨利的女儿玛格丽特・都铎（Margaret Tudor），为皇冠联合创造了条件。对亨利来说，与欧洲最成熟的君主制之一的联姻使新都铎王朝合法化。十年后，詹姆斯做出了一个决定性的决定，根据奥尔德联盟的条款入侵英国支持法国。他是最后一个在战斗中死去的英国君主。不到一代人，奥尔德联盟就被爱丁堡条约终止了。法国同意撤出所有陆海军。同年，1560年，约翰诺克斯实现了他的目标，即苏格兰成为一个新教国家，苏格兰议会撤销在苏格兰的教皇权力。苏格兰女王玛丽是天主教徒，曾是法国女王，1567年被迫退位。[第2段]1603年，苏格兰国王詹姆斯六世继承了英格兰王国和爱尔兰王国的王位，成为英格兰和爱尔兰国王詹姆斯一世，离开爱丁堡前往伦敦。除了在保护国统治下的短暂时期外，苏格兰仍然是一个独立的国家，但在教会政府的形式上，王室和立约人之间存在着相当大的冲突。1688-1689年的光荣革命见证了英国议会推翻苏格兰国王詹姆斯七世和英格兰国王二世，支持威廉和玛丽。早在16世纪90年代，苏格兰就经历了饥荒，使该国部分地区的人口减少了至少20%。[第2段]1698年，苏格兰人试图实施一项雄心勃勃的计划，在巴拿马地峡建立一个贸易殖民地。据说，几乎所有有余钱的苏格兰地主都投资了达里安计划。它的失败使这些土地所有者破产，但不是市民破产。然而，贵族的破产，以及英国入侵的威胁，在说服苏格兰精英支持与英国的联盟方面发挥了主导作用，苏格兰议会和英国议会的代表商定了《联合条约》，并于第二年通过了两项联合法案，从1707年5月1日起建立大不列颠联合王国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Scotland -->
  <!-- Civilization Novgorod -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Novgorodians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Novgorod</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Novgorodian:Novgorodians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Slightly predating the chronology of the legend of Rurik (which dates the first Norse arrival in the region around 858-860), an earlier record for the Scandinavian settlement of the region is found in the Annales Bertiniani (written up until 882) where a Rus' delegation is mentioned as having visited Constantinople in 838 and, intending to return to the Rus' Khaganate via the Baltic Sea, were questioned by Frankish Emperor Louis the Pious at Ingelheim am Rhein, where they said that although their origin was Swedish, they had settled in Northern Rus' under a leader who they designated as chacanus (the Latin form of Khagan, a title they had likely borrowed from contact with the Avars).[PARAGRAPH:2]In 882, Rurik's successor, Oleg of Novgorod, conquered Kiev and founded the state of Kievan Rus'. Novgorod's size as well as its political, economic, and cultural influence made it the second most important city in Kievan Rus'. According to a custom, the elder son and heir of the ruling Kievan monarch was sent to rule Novgorod even as a minor. When the ruling monarch had no such son, Novgorod was governed by posadniks, such as the legendary Gostomysl, Dobrynya, Konstantin, and Ostromir.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of all their princes, Novgorodians most cherished the memory of Yaroslav the Wise, who sat as Prince of Novgorod from 1010 to 1019, while his father, Vladimir the Great, was a prince in Kiev. Yaroslav promulgated the first written code of laws (later incorporated into Russkaya Pravda) among the Eastern Slavs and is said to have granted the city a number of freedoms or privileges, which they often referred to in later centuries as precedents in their relations with other princes. His son, Vladimir, sponsored construction of the great St. Sophia Cathedral, more accurately translated as the Cathedral of Holy Wisdom, which stands to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In Norse sagas the city is mentioned as the capital of Gardariki. Four Viking kings-Olaf I of Norway, Olaf II of Norway, Magnus I of Norway, and Harald Hardrada-sought refuge in Novgorod from enemies at home. No more than a few decades after the 1030 death and subsequent canonization of Olaf II of Norway, the city's community had erected in his memory Saint Olaf's Church in Novgorod.[PARAGRAPH:2]The town of Visby in Gotland functioned as the leading trading center in the Baltic before the Hansa League. At Novgorod in 1080, Visby merchants established a trading post which they named Gutagard (also known as Gotenhof). Later, in the first half of the 13th century, merchants from northern Germany also established their own trading station in Novgorod, known as Peterhof. At about the same time, in 1229, German merchants at Novgorod were granted certain privileges, which made their position more secure.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1136, the Novgorodians dismissed their prince Vsevolod Mstislavich. The year is seen as the traditional beginning of the Novgorod Republic. The city was able to invite and dismiss a number of princes over the next two centuries, but the princely office was never abolished and powerful princes, such as Alexander Nevsky, could assert their will in the city regardless of what Novgorodians' said. The city state controlled most of Europe's northeast, from lands east of today's Estonia to the Ural Mountains, making it one of the largest states in medieval Europe, although much of the territory north and east of Lakes Ladoga and Onega was sparsely populated and never organized politically.[PARAGRAPH:2]One of the most important local figures in Novgorod was the posadnik, or mayor, an official elected by the public assembly (called the Veche) from among the city's boyarstvo, or aristocracy. The tysyatsky, or "thousandman", originally the head of the town militia but later a commercial and judicial official, was also elected by the Veche. Another important local official was the Archbishop of Novgorod who shared power with the boyars. Archbishops were elected by the Veche or by the drawing of lots, and after their election, were sent to the metropolitan for consecration.[PARAGRAPH:2]While a basic outline of the various officials and the Veche can be drawn up, the city-state's exact political constitution remains unknown. The boyars and the archbishop ruled the city together, although where one official's power ended and another's began is uncertain. The prince, although his power was reduced from around the middle of the 12th century, was represented by his namestnik, or lieutenant, and still played important roles as a military commander, legislator and jurist. The exact composition of the Veche, too, is uncertain, with some historians, such as Vasily Klyuchevsky, claiming it was democratic in nature, while later scholars, such as Marxists Valentin Ianin and Aleksandr Khoroshev, see it as a "sham democracy" controlled by the ruling elite.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 13th century, Novgorod, while not a member of the Hanseatic League, was the easternmost kontor, or entrepot, of the league, being the source of enormous quantities of luxury (sable, ermine, fox, marmot) and non-luxury furs (squirrel pelts).[PARAGRAPH:2]Throughout the Middle Ages, the city thrived culturally. A large number of birch bark letters have been unearthed in excavations, perhaps suggesting widespread literacy, although this is uncertain (some scholars suggest that a clerical or scribal elite wrote them on behalf of a largely illiterate populace). It was in Novgorod that the Novgorod Codex, the oldest Slavic book written north of Macedonia, and the oldest inscription in a Finnic language (Birch bark letter no. 292) were unearthed. Some of the most ancient Russian chronicles (Novgorod First Chronicle) were written in the scriptorium of the archbishops who also promoted iconography and patronized church construction. The Novgorod merchant Sadko became a popular hero of Russian folklore.[PARAGRAPH:2]Novgorod was never conquered by the Mongols during the Mongol invasion of Rus. The Mongol army turned back about 200 kilometers (120 mi) from the city, not because of the city's strength, but probably because the Mongol commanders did not want to get bogged down in the marshlands surrounding the city. However, the grand princes of Moscow, who acted as tax collectors for the khans of the Golden Horde, did collect tribute in Novgorod, most notably Yury Danilovich and his brother, Ivan Kalita.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1259, Hordes tax-collectors and census-takers arrived in the city, leading to political disturbances and forcing Alexander Nevsky to punish a number of town officials (he cut off their noses) for defying him as Grand Prince of Vladimir (soon to be the khan's tax-collector in Russia) and his Mongol overlords. In the 14th century, raids by Novgorod pirates, or ushkuiniki, sowed fear as far as Kazan and Astrakhan, assisting Novgorod in wars with the Grand Duchy of Moscow.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the era of Old Rus' State, Novgorod was a trade hub at the northern end of both the Volga trade route and the "route from the Varangians to the Greeks" along the Dnieper river system. A vast array of goods were transported along these routes and exchanged with local Novgorod merchants and other traders. The farmers of Gotland retained the Saint Olof trading house well into the 12th century. Later German merchantmen also established tradinghouses in Novgorod. Scandinavian royalty would intermarry with Russian princes and princesses.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the great schism, Novgorod struggled from the beginning of the 13th century against Swedish, Danish, and German crusaders. During the Swedish-Novgorodian Wars, the Swedes invaded lands where some of the population had earlier paid tribute to Novgorod. The Germans had been trying to conquer the Baltic region since the late 12th century. Novgorod went to war 26 times with Sweden and 11 times with the Livonian Brothers of the Sword. The German knights, along with Danish and Swedish feudal lords, launched a series of uncoordinated attacks in 1240-1242. Novgorodian sources mention that a Swedish army was defeated in the Battle of the Neva in 1240. The Baltic German campaigns ended in failure after the Battle on the Ice in 1242. After the foundation of the castle of Viborg in 1293 the Swedes gained a foothold in Karelia. On August 12, 1323, Sweden and Novgorod signed the Treaty of Nteborg, regulating their border for the first time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The city's downfall occurred partially as a result of its inability to feed its large population, making it dependent on the Vladimir-Suzdal region for grain. The main cities in the area, Moscow and Tver, used this dependence to gain control over Novgorod. Eventually Ivan III forcibly annexed the city to the Grand Duchy of Moscow in 1478. The Veche was dissolved and a significant part of Novgorod's population was either killed or deported. The Hanseatic League kontor was closed in 1494 and the goods stored there were seized by Muscovite forces.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>略早于鲁里克传说的年代（约858-860年挪威人第一次到达该地区），该地区斯堪的纳维亚人定居的早期记录出现在伯提尼亚尼年鉴（写于882年）中，在该年鉴中，一个罗斯代表团被称为在838年访问过君士坦丁堡，打算经由波罗的海返回罗斯汗国的法兰克皇帝路易・莱因（Louis the Pious）在英格尔海姆莱茵（Ingelheim am Rhein）接受质询时说，虽然他们的血统是瑞典人，但他们在罗斯北部的一位领袖下定居下来，他们将这位领袖命名为查卡努斯（拉丁形式的汗国，他们很可能是从与阿瓦尔人的接触中借来的一个头衔）。诺夫哥罗德的规模以及它的政治、经济和文化影响力使它成为基辅罗斯第二重要的城市。根据一个习俗，统治基辅的君主的长子和继承人甚至作为未成年人被派去统治诺夫哥罗德。当统治君主没有这样的儿子时，诺夫哥罗德由波萨德尼克统治，比如传说中的戈斯托米、多布里亚、康斯坦丁和奥斯特罗米尔。[第2段]在他们所有的王子中，诺夫哥罗德人最珍视雅罗斯拉夫的记忆，雅罗斯拉夫在1010年至1019年担任诺夫哥罗德王子，而他的父亲弗拉基米尔大帝是基辅的王子。雅罗斯拉夫颁布了东部斯拉夫人中的第一部成文法典（后来被纳入俄罗斯真理报），据说给予了该城一些自由或特权，在后来的几个世纪里，他们经常将这些自由或特权称为与其他王子关系的先例。他的儿子弗拉基米尔赞助了圣索菲亚大教堂的建设，更准确地说，圣索菲亚大教堂被称为圣智大教堂，至今仍屹立不倒。挪威的奥拉夫一世、挪威的奥拉夫二世、挪威的马格努斯一世和哈拉尔德・哈德拉达四位北欧海盗国王在诺夫哥罗德躲避国内敌人。在1030年挪威奥拉夫二世去世并随后被封为圣徒后不到几十年，这个城市的社区就在他记忆中建立了诺夫哥罗德的圣奥拉夫教堂（Saint Olaf's Church）。在1080年的诺夫哥罗德，维斯比商人建立了一个贸易站，他们命名为古塔加德（也称为戈登霍夫）。后来，在13世纪上半叶，来自德国北部的商人也在诺夫哥罗德建立了自己的贸易站，称为彼得霍夫。大约在同一时间，1229年，诺夫哥罗德的德国商人获得了某些特权，这使得他们的地位更加稳固。[第2段]1136年，诺夫哥罗德人解雇了他们的王子维斯沃德・姆斯蒂斯拉维奇。这一年被视为诺夫哥罗德共和国的传统开端。在接下来的两个世纪里，这座城市能够邀请和罢免一些王子，但王子的职位从未被废除，像亚历山大・涅夫斯基这样有权势的王子可以在这座城市维护他们的意愿，而不管诺夫哥德人说了什么。这个城邦控制了欧洲东北部的大部分地区，从今天爱沙尼亚东部的土地到乌拉尔山脉，使它成为中世纪欧洲最大的国家之一，尽管拉多加湖和奥涅加湖北部和东部的大部分地区人口稀少，从未有过政治组织。[第2段]诺夫哥罗德最重要的地方人物之一是波萨德尼克（posadnik）或市长，他是由市民大会（称为维切）从该市的博雅尔斯特沃（boyarstvo）或贵族中选出的官员。提希亚茨基，或“千人”，最初是镇民兵的首领，但后来是一个商业和司法官员，也由维切选举产生。另一位重要的地方官员是诺夫哥罗德大主教，他与博雅家族分享权力。大主教由维切人或通过抽签选举产生，选举后，他们被送往大都会进行献祭。[第2段]在北欧传说中，这座城市被称为加德里基的首都。挪威的奥拉夫一世、挪威的奥拉夫二世、挪威的马格努斯一世和哈拉尔德・哈德拉达四位北欧海盗国王在诺夫哥罗德躲避国内敌人。在1030年挪威奥拉夫二世去世并随后被封为圣徒后不到几十年，这个城市的社区就在他记忆中建立了诺夫哥罗德的圣奥拉夫教堂（Saint Olaf's Church）。在1080年的诺夫哥罗德，维斯比商人建立了一个贸易站，他们命名为古塔加德（也称为戈登霍夫）。后来，在13世纪上半叶，来自德国北部的商人也在诺夫哥罗德建立了自己的贸易站，称为彼得霍夫。大约在同一时间，1229年，诺夫哥罗德的德国商人获得了某些特权，这使得他们的地位更加稳固。[第2段]1136年，诺夫哥罗德人解雇了他们的王子维斯沃德・姆斯蒂斯拉维奇。这一年被视为诺夫哥罗德共和国的传统开端。在接下来的两个世纪里，这座城市能够邀请和罢免一些王子，但王子的职位从未被废除，像亚历山大・涅夫斯基这样有权势的王子可以在这座城市维护他们的意愿，而不管诺夫哥德人说了什么。这个城邦控制了欧洲东北部的大部分地区，从今天爱沙尼亚东部的土地到乌拉尔山脉，使它成为中世纪欧洲最大的国家之一，尽管拉多加湖和奥涅加湖北部和东部的大部分地区人口稀少，从未有过政治组织。[第2段]诺夫哥罗德最重要的地方人物之一是波萨德尼克（posadnik）或市长，他是由市民大会（称为维切）从该市的博雅尔斯特沃（boyarstvo）或贵族中选出的官员。提希亚茨基，或“千人”，最初是镇民兵的首领，但后来是一个商业和司法官员，也由维切选举产生。另一位重要的地方官员是诺夫哥罗德大主教，他与博雅家族分享权力。大主教由维切人或通过抽签选举产生，选举后，他们被送往大都会进行献祭。[第2段]虽然可以起草各种官员和维切人的基本大纲，但城邦的确切政治宪法仍不得而知。博雅尔和大主教一起统治着这座城市，尽管一位官员的权力在哪里结束，另一位官员的权力在哪里开始还不确定。尽管王子的权力从12世纪中叶左右开始下降，但他的代表是他的名字，即中尉，仍然扮演着军事指挥官、立法者和法学家的重要角色。维切河的确切组成也不确定，一些历史学家，如瓦西里・克柳切夫斯基，声称它是民主的，而后来的学者，如马克思主义者瓦伦丁・亚宁和亚历山大霍罗谢夫，则认为它是由统治精英控制的“假民主”，虽然不是汉萨同盟的成员，但它是同盟最东端的康托或转口港，是大量奢侈品（貂皮、貂皮、狐狸皮、旱獭皮）和非奢侈品毛皮（松鼠皮）的来源。在挖掘中发现了大量的桦树皮字母，这可能暗示了广泛的文化，尽管这还不确定（一些学者认为是一位神职人员或抄写精英代表一个基本上不识字的民众写的）。正是在诺夫哥罗德出土了诺夫哥罗德法典，这是在马其顿北部书写的最古老的斯拉夫语书籍，也是最古老的芬兰语铭文（第292号桦树皮字母）。一些最古老的俄罗斯编年史（Novgorod First Chronicle）是在大主教的记事本中写成的，他们还提倡肖像画和赞助教堂建设。诺夫哥罗德商人萨德科成为俄罗斯民间传说中一位受欢迎的英雄。[第2段]在蒙古人入侵罗斯期间，诺夫哥罗德从未被蒙古人征服。蒙古军队在离城市200公里（120英里）的地方掉头，不是因为城市的实力，而是因为蒙古指挥官不想陷入城市周围的沼泽地。然而，莫斯科的王子们，作为金色部落汗国的税务员，确实在诺夫哥罗德收集贡品，尤其是尤里・丹尼洛维奇和他的兄弟伊万・卡利塔（Ivan Kalita）[第2段]1259年，成群结队的税务员和人口普查员来到这座城市，导致了政治动乱，迫使亚历山大・涅夫斯基惩罚许多镇上的官员（他砍掉了鼻子）因为他们蔑视他为弗拉基米尔的大王子（不久将成为可汗在俄罗斯的收税人）和他的蒙古霸主。在14世纪，诺夫哥罗德海盗的袭击，或乌什奎尼基，把恐惧撒到喀山和阿斯特拉罕，协助诺夫哥罗德与莫斯科大公国打仗，诺夫哥罗德是伏尔加贸易路线北端和第聂伯河流域“从瓦兰吉安人到希腊人的路线”的贸易中心。大量的货物沿着这些路线运输，并与当地的诺夫哥罗德商人和其他商人交换。哥德兰的农民在12世纪就保留了圣奥洛夫贸易大厦。后来德国商人也在诺夫哥罗德建立了贸易中心。斯堪的纳维亚皇室成员将与俄罗斯王子和公主通婚。[第2段]在大分裂之后，诺夫哥罗德从13世纪初开始与瑞典、丹麦和德国十字军作战。在瑞典诺夫哥罗德战争期间，瑞典人入侵了一些人早先曾向诺夫哥罗德致敬的土地。自12世纪末以来，德国人一直试图征服波罗的海地区。诺夫哥罗德26次与瑞典开战，11次与利沃尼亚剑兄弟开战。1240-1242年，德国骑士与丹麦和瑞典封建领主一起发动了一系列不协调的攻击。诺夫哥罗德的消息来源提到，一支瑞典军队在1240年的涅瓦河战役中战败。1242年冰上战役后，波罗的海德国战役以失败告终。1293维堡城堡建成后，瑞典人在Karelia站稳脚跟。1323年8月12日，瑞典和诺夫哥罗德签署了内堡条约，第一次对他们的边界进行了调整。[第2段]该市的垮台部分是由于无法养活大量人口，使其粮食依赖于弗拉基米尔苏兹达尔地区。该地区的主要城市莫斯科和特维尔利用这种依赖性控制了诺夫哥罗德。最终，伊万三世于1478年强行将这座城市并入莫斯科大公国。维切人被解散，诺夫哥罗德的大部分人口要么被杀，要么被驱逐出境。汉萨同盟康托于1494年关闭，那里储存的货物被莫斯科军队没收。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Novgorod -->
  <!-- Civilization Prussia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Prussians</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>普鲁士文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Prussia</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>普鲁士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Prussian:Prussians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>普鲁士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[表]在组成德国的数百个国家中，普鲁士王国最终会成功地将它们结合在一起。从波罗的海沿岸的一个小公国开始，普鲁士统治者通过战争和婚姻协议的结合，逐渐积累了越来越多的领土。腓特烈国王威廉一世（1713-1710）训练普鲁士军队成为欧洲最优秀的军队之一，他的儿子腓特烈二世（1740-1746）也被称为腓特烈大帝，用它赢得了一系列对奥地利和俄罗斯等大国的军事胜利。弗雷德里克也被称为艺术赞助人，他的宫廷吸引了来自欧洲各地的伏尔泰等知识分子。作为一个开明的独裁者，腓特烈同样擅长于击败俄国的侵略和吹笛子。[第2段]在法国大革命和拿破仑战争中的屈辱和失败之后，普鲁士设法恢复元气，按照更现代的路线重新组织自己。受1848年德国革命期间发生的民众起义的困扰，普鲁士的威廉一世（1861-1888）考虑退位，以支持他的儿子，据信，他的政治观点接近自由反对派。然而，他被说服考虑组建一个由普鲁士驻巴黎大使奥托・冯・俾斯麦（Otto von Bismarck）领导的新政府。1862年9月，一个以保守主义、民族主义和（现实政治）著称的政治家成为普鲁士总理的消息震惊了欧洲。俾斯麦被证明是一位杰出的战略家，1871年1月，在对丹麦、奥地利和法国进行了三次短暂而决定性的战争之后，新德意志帝国宣告成立。在十年的时间里，俾斯麦统一了德国，或者，正如一些人所说，普鲁士征服了德国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Prussia -->
  <!-- Civilization Aragon -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Aragonese</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉贡文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Aragon</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉贡</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Aragonese</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>阿拉贡人</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Crown of Aragon was a composite monarchy, also nowadays referred to as a confederation of individual polities or kingdoms ruled by one king with a personal and dynastic union of the Kingdom of Aragon and the county of Barcelona. At the height of its power in the 14th and 15th centuries, the Crown of Aragon was a thalassocracy (a state with primarily maritime realms) controlling a large portion of present-day eastern Spain, parts of what is now southern France, and a Mediterranean "empire" which included the Balearic Islands, Sicily, Corsica, Sardinia, Malta, Southern Italy (from 1442) and parts of Greece (until 1388). The component realms of the Crown were not united politically except at the level of the king, who ruled over each autonomous polity according to its own laws, raising funds under each tax structure, dealing separately with each cortes. Put in contemporary terms, it has sometimes been considered that the different lands of the Crown of Aragon functioned more as a confederacy of cultures rather than as a single country. In this sense, the larger Crown of Aragon must not be confused with one of its constituent parts, the Kingdom of Aragon, from which it takes its name.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1469, a new dynastic familial union of the Crown of Aragon with the Crown of Castile by the Catholic Monarchs, joining what contemporaries referred to as "the Spains" led to what would become the Kingdom of Spain under King Philip II. The Crown existed until it was abolished by the Nueva Planta decrees issued by King Philip V in 1716 as a consequence of the defeat of Archduke Charles in the War of the Spanish Succession.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[表]阿拉贡王国是一个复合君主政体，现在也被称为由一个国王统治的各个政治或王国的联邦，阿拉贡王国和巴塞罗那郡是个人和王朝的联盟。在14世纪和15世纪的鼎盛时期，阿拉贡王国是一个地中海国家（一个主要拥有海洋王国的国家），控制着现在西班牙东部的大部分地区，现在法国南部的部分地区，以及一个地中海“帝国”，包括巴利阿里群岛、西西里岛、科西嘉岛、撒丁岛、马耳他，意大利南部（1442年起）和希腊部分地区（1388年以前）。除了国王一级之外，皇室的各个组成领域在政治上并不统一，国王根据自己的法律统治每个自治政体，在每个税收结构下筹集资金，分别处理每个议会。用当代的话来说，人们有时认为阿拉贡王冠的不同土地更多地发挥着文化联盟的作用，而不是作为一个单一的国家。在这个意义上，更大的阿拉贡王冠不应与它的组成部分之一阿拉贡王国混淆，阿拉贡王国就是从这个王国得名的，加入同时代人所说的“斯宾斯”导致了在菲利普二世统治下的西班牙王国。王位一直存在，直到1716年菲利普五世国王颁布的努埃瓦・普拉塔法令废除王位，这是查尔斯大公在西班牙继承战争中失败的结果。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Aragon -->
  <!-- Civilization Morocco -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Moroccans</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>摩洛哥文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Morocco</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>摩洛哥</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Moroccan:Moroccans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>摩洛哥</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In 670 AD, the first Islamic conquest of the North African coastal plain took place under Uqba ibn Nafi, a general serving under the Umayyads of Damascus. The Umayyad Muslims brought their language, their system of government, and Islam to Morocco. Many of the Berbers slowly converted to Islam, mostly after Arab rule had receded. The first independent Muslim state in the area of modern Morocco was the Kingdom of Nekor, an emirate in the Rif Mountains. It was founded by Salih I ibn Mansur in 710, as a client state to the Rashidun Caliphate. After the outbreak of the Great Berber Revolt in 739, the Berbers formed other independent states such as the Miknasa of Sijilmasa and the Barghawata.[PARAGRAPH:2]According to medieval legend, Idris ibn Abdallah had fled to Morocco after the Abbasids' massacre of his tribe in Iraq. He convinced the Awraba Berber tribes to break their allegiance to the distant Abbasid caliphs in Baghdad and he founded the Idrisid Dynasty in 788. The Idrisids established Fes as their capital and Morocco became a centre of Muslim learning and a major regional power. The Idrissids were ousted in 927 by the Fatimid Caliphate and their Miknasa allies. After Miknasa broke off relations with the Fatimids in 932, they were removed from power by the Maghrawa of Sijilmasa in 980.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the 11th century onwards, a series of powerful Berber dynasties arose. Under the Almoravid dynasty and the Almohad dynasty, Morocco dominated the Maghreb, much of present-day Spain and Portugal, and the western Mediterranean region. In the 13th and 14th centuries the Merinids held power in Morocco and strove to replicate the successes of the Almohads by military campaigns in Algeria and Spain. They were followed by the Wattasids. In the 15th century, the Reconquista ended Muslim rule in central and southern Spain and Portugal and many Muslims and Jews fled to Morocco.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portuguese efforts to control the Atlantic sea trade in the 15th century did not greatly affect the interior of Morocco even though they managed to control some possessions on the Moroccan coast but not venturing further afield inland.[PARAGRAPH:2]On another note and according to Elizabeth Allo Isichei, "In 1520, there was a famine in Morocco so terrible that for a long time other events were dated by it. It has been suggested that the population of Morocco fell from 5 to under 3 million between the early sixteenth and nineteenth centuries."[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1549, the region fell to successive Arab dynasties claiming descent from the Islamic prophet, Muhammad: first the Saadi dynasty who ruled from 1549 to 1659, and then the Alaouite Dynasty, who remained in power since the 17th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under the Saadi Dynasty, the country repulsed Ottoman incursions and a Portuguese invasion at the battle of Ksar el Kebir in 1578. The reign of Ahmad al-Mansur brought new wealth and prestige to the Sultanate, and a large expedition to West Africa inflicted a crushing defeat on the Songhay Empire in 1591. However, managing the territories across the Sahara proved too difficult. After the death of al-Mansur the country was divided among his sons.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1666 Morocco was reunited by the Alaouite Dynasty, who have been the ruling house of Morocco ever since. Morocco was facing aggression from Spain and the Ottoman Empire lies pressing westward. The Alaouites succeeded in stabilizing their position, and while the kingdom was smaller than previous ones in the region, it remained quite wealthy. Against the opposition of local tribes Ismail Ibn Sharif (1672-1727) began to create a unified state. With his Jaysh d'Ahl al-Rif (the Riffian Army) he seized Tangier from the English in 1684 and drove the Spanish from Larache in 1689.[PARAGRAPH:2]Morocco was the first nation to recognize the fledgling United States as an independent nation in 1777. In the beginning of the American Revolution, American merchant ships in the Atlantic Ocean were subject to attack by the Barbary pirates. On 20 December 1777, Morocco's Sultan Mohammed III declared that American merchant ships would be under the protection of the sultanate and could thus enjoy safe passage. The Moroccan-American Treaty of Friendship, signed in 1786, stands as the U.S.'s oldest non-broken friendship treaty.</English>    
     <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>公元670年，在大马士革倭玛亚人手下的一位将军乌克巴・伊本・纳菲（Uqba ibn Nafi）领导下，第一次伊斯兰征服北非沿海平原。倭玛亚穆斯林把他们的语言、政府制度和伊斯兰教带到摩洛哥。许多柏柏尔人慢慢皈依伊斯兰教，主要是在阿拉伯统治消退之后。现代摩洛哥地区第一个独立的穆斯林国家是尼科尔王国，一个位于里夫山脉的酋长国。它是由萨利伊本曼苏尔于710年建立的，作为拉希敦哈里发的一个客户端国家。公元739年伯伯大起义爆发后，伯伯人成立了其他独立国家，如西吉尔马萨的米克纳萨和巴沙瓦。[第2段]根据中世纪的传说，在阿巴斯人屠杀他在伊拉克的部落后，伊德里斯・伊本・阿卜杜拉逃到了摩洛哥。他说服了奥拉巴-伯伯部落，让他们不再效忠巴格达遥远的阿巴斯哈里发，并于788年建立了伊德里希王朝。伊德里斯人建立了Fes作为他们的首都，摩洛哥成为穆斯林学习的中心和一个主要的地区强国。伊德里西斯在927年被法蒂玛哈里发和他们的米卡萨同盟驱逐。公元932年，米克纳沙与法蒂玛王朝断绝关系后，他们于980年被西吉尔玛萨的玛格拉瓦（Maghrawa of Sijilmasa）夺去了权力。[第2段]从11世纪开始，一系列强大的柏柏尔王朝出现。在阿尔莫拉维德王朝和阿尔莫哈德王朝统治下，摩洛哥统治了马格里布，现今西班牙和葡萄牙的大部分地区，以及西地中海地区。13世纪和14世纪，梅里尼王朝在摩洛哥掌权，并努力通过在阿尔及利亚和西班牙的军事行动复制阿尔摩哈德王朝的成功。他们后面跟着瓦塔西德人。在15世纪，在西班牙中部和南部以及葡萄牙，收复失地结束了穆斯林的统治，许多穆斯林和犹太人逃到摩洛哥。[第2段]葡萄牙在15世纪控制大西洋贸易的努力并没有对摩洛哥的内陆造成太大的影响，尽管他们设法控制了摩洛哥海岸的一些领地，但没有冒险另一方面，根据伊丽莎白・阿洛・伊希奇的说法，“1520年，摩洛哥发生了严重的饥荒，很长一段时间以来，其他的事件都是由它造成的。有人认为，摩洛哥的人口在16世纪初至19世纪期间从500万下降到300万以下。”[第2段]1549年，该地区相继沦为声称是伊斯兰先知穆罕默德后裔的阿拉伯王朝：首先是统治1549年至1659年的萨阿迪王朝，然后是阿劳伊特王朝，自17世纪以来一直掌权的萨阿迪王朝（Saadi Dynasty）统治下，该国在1578年的凯比尔战役中击退了奥斯曼帝国的入侵和葡萄牙的入侵。艾哈迈德・曼苏尔（Ahmad al-Mansur）的统治给苏丹国带来了新的财富和声望，1591年对西非的一次大规模远征使宋海帝国惨败。然而，事实证明，管理整个撒哈拉的领土太困难了。曼苏尔死后，这个国家被他的儿子们瓜分了。[第2段]1666年，摩洛哥被阿拉乌王朝重新统一，阿拉乌王朝从此成为摩洛哥的统治者。摩洛哥正面临来自西班牙的侵略，而奥斯曼帝国正向西推进。阿拉乌人成功地稳定了他们的地位，虽然王国比该地区以前的王国要小，但它仍然相当富有。反对当地部落的伊斯梅尔伊本谢里夫（1672-1727）开始创建一个统一的国家。1684年，他用自己的杰什・达赫勒・利夫（Jaysh d'Ahl al-Rif）军队从英国手中夺取了丹吉尔（Tangier），1689年，他把西班牙人从拉腊切赶走。[第2段]1777年，摩洛哥是第一个承认美国是一个独立国家的国家。美国大革命初期，大西洋上的美国商船遭到野蛮海盗的袭击。1777年12月20日，摩洛哥苏丹穆罕默德三世宣布，美国商船将受到苏丹国的保护，因此可以安全通行。1786年签署的《摩洛哥-美国友好条约》是美国历史最悠久的非破坏性友好条约。</Chinese>
    </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Morocco -->
  <!-- Civilization Papal States -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Papal States</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>教宗国</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Papal States</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>教宗国</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Papal</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>教宗</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Papal States emerged from the ashes of the Western Roman Empire. As Christianity grew, wealthy Roman patrons donated large tracts of land to the Church, and soon the Bishop of Rome (the title of "Pope" was not instituted until later) was the largest landholder in Italy, giving him a good deal of economic and political power in the region, along with his growing spiritual might. During the sixth century AD, the Eastern Roman Empire (based in Constantinople), launched a reconquest of Italy, taking much of the southern part of the peninsula. They took Rome as well, but proved unable to protect her from the growing Lombardian menace to the north.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thus the protection of Rome largely devolved upon the Bishop of Rome, by then the most powerful person in the region. Of necessity he had to raise armies and build fortifications to defend the Holy City from the Lombards, who were tightening their stranglehold on Rome. Over time the Bishops began to chafe under Constantinople's rule and sought to become fully independent from the Eastern Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Popes found their champion in Pepin the Short, who in return for Pope Stephen II's support of his deposing the last of the Merovingian kings and assuming control of all of the Frankish lands, invaded Italy and drove the Lombardians from the areas around Rome. He gave these liberated lands to the Pope, officially creating the Papal States.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Papal States would exist for another ten centuries. It was finally dismantled during the Italian unification struggles which took place in the 1860s and '70s.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>教皇国从西罗马帝国的灰烬中崛起。随着基督教的发展，富有的罗马赞助人向教会捐赠了大片土地，不久，罗马主教（直到后来才设立“教皇”的头衔）成为意大利最大的土地拥有者，给了他在该地区大量的经济和政治权力，以及他日益增长的精神力量。公元六世纪，东罗马帝国（位于君士坦丁堡）对意大利进行了重新征服，占领了半岛南部的大部分地区。他们也占领了罗马，但证明无法保护她免受北部伦巴第人日益增长的威胁。[第2段]因此，对罗马的保护主要移交给罗马主教，当时是该地区最有权势的人。为了保护圣城免受伦巴第人的侵扰，他不得不增兵筑垒。随着时间的推移，主教们开始在君士坦丁堡的统治下愤怒起来，并寻求完全独立于东方帝国。[第2段]教皇们在佩宾找到了他们的冠军，作为回报，教皇斯蒂芬二世支持他罢免最后一位梅罗文吉国王，并接管了所有法兰克土地，入侵意大利，驱赶伦巴第人离开罗马周边地区。他把这些解放的土地交给了教皇，正式建立了教皇国。在19世纪60年代和70年代发生的意大利统一斗争中，它最终被拆除。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Papal States -->
  <!-- Civilization Independent -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Independent Cities</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Independents</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Independent</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]I will survive</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[TAB]我要活下去</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Independent -->
</Civ4GameText>
