<?xml version='1.0' encoding='GBK'?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by XMLSPY 2004 Professional Ed. Release 2, Installed Multi + SMP for 3 users (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - RFCE Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CATHOLIC_MISSIONARY</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Missionary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>天主教神父</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ORTHODOX_MISSIONARY</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Missionary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>东正教司祭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PROTESTANT_MISSIONARY</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Missionary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>新教牧师</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ISLAMIC_MISSIONARY</Tag>
    <English>Islamic Missionary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>穆斯林阿訇</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPEARMAN</Tag>
    <English>Spearman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>矛兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPEARMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Since a Medieval spear required only a small amount of steel along the sharpened edges, it was an economical weapon. Quick to manufacture, and needing less smithing skill than a sword, it became the common weapon of the peasantry in many parts of the world. With the rise of heavy cavalry, spear shafts began to be planted against the ground to deter charging cavalry. Spears morphed into different pole-arms as mounted knights became more important on the battlefields of Europe and a means to counter them was needed.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]由于中世纪的长矛在锋利的边缘只需要少量的钢，所以它是一种经济的武器。它制造速度快，比剑更不需要锻造技术，在世界许多地方成为农民的常用武器。随着重装骑兵的兴起，长矛开始靠在地上，以阻止冲锋骑兵。当骑兵在欧洲战场上变得越来越重要时，长矛变成了不同的杆臂，需要一种手段来对抗它们。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUISARME</Tag>
    <English>Guisarmier</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>长柄刀兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUISARME_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A guisarme was a pole weapon used in Europe to dismount knights and horsemen, primarily between 1000-1400. Like most polearms it was developed by peasants by combining hand tools with long poles: in this case by putting a pruning hook onto a spear shaft. Later designs implemented a small reverse spike on the back of the blade, increasing the weapon's stopping power. Eventually hooks were incorporated into a variety of different polearms and guisarme became a catch-all for any weapon that included a hook on the blade.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]guisarme是欧洲用来下马的杆状武器，主要在1000-1400年之间。像大多数的polearms一样，它是由农民通过手工工具和长杆相结合而发展起来的：在这种情况下，把修剪钩放在矛杆上。后来的设计在刀刃背面实现了一个小的反向尖峰，增加了武器的阻止力。最终，钩子被合并到各种不同的polearms和guisarme成为一个捕获所有的武器，包括一个钩子在刀片上。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PIKEMAN</Tag>
    <English>Pikeman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>长枪兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PIKEMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Early in the middle ages, the pike was only useful on defense; its length made it difficult for untrained soldiers to use in formation. The Swiss brought a renaissance to pike warfare in the 15th century, with strong training regimens and drummers to aid coordination. Now pike blocks could both rise to the attack and go into an impenetrable defensive formation when attacked by cavalry. The deep pike attack column remained an essential part of infantry combat for several hundred years.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]中世纪早期，长矛只用于防御；它的长度使未经训练的士兵很难在队形中使用。瑞士在15世纪带来了枪战的复兴，强大的训练方案和鼓手帮助协调。现在，当被骑兵攻击时，长矛拦网既能发动攻击，又能进入无法穿透的防御队形。深矛攻击纵队几百年来一直是步兵战斗的重要组成部分。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARBALEST</Tag>
    <English>Arbalestier</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>钢弩手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARBALEST_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The arbalest was a late variation of the medieval European crossbow. A larger weapon, the arbalest had a steel prod ("bow"). Since an arbalest was much larger than earlier crossbows, and because of the greater tensile strength of steel, it had a greater force and range. A skilled arbalestier could shoot two bolts per minute. Arbalests were sometimes considered inhumane or unfair weapons, since an inexperienced arbalestier could use one to kill a knight who had a lifetime of training.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]阿尔巴莱斯特弓是中世纪欧洲弩的晚期变体。一种更大的武器，阿贝莱斯特有一个钢制的尖头（“弓”）。因为一把弩比早期的弩大得多，而且由于钢的抗拉强度更大，所以它有更大的力量和射程。熟练的仲裁员每分钟可以射两发。仲裁员有时被认为是不人道或不公平的武器，因为一个没有经验的仲裁员可以使用一个杀死一个骑士谁有一辈子的训练。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER</Tag>
    <English>Horse Archer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>弓骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A horse archer is a cavalryman armed with a bow. Because using a bow requires a horseman to let go of the reins with both hands, horse archers need superb equestrian skills and horse archery is typically associated with steppe nomads. The weapon of choice for horse archers was the recurve bow, which is compact enough to shoot from a horse yet retained sufficient range and penetrating power. Mounted archers needed little or no armor and could ride light, fast mounts.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]骑兵弓箭手是带弓的骑兵。因为用弓需要骑手双手放开缰绳，射马者需要高超的马术技巧，而射马通常与草原游牧民族有关。弓箭手选择的武器是下弯弓，它紧凑到可以从马身上射出，但保留了足够的射程和穿透力。骑兵不需要盔甲也不需要盔甲，可以骑轻快的骑兵。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOUNTED_SERGEANT</Tag>
    <English>Mounted Sergeant</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>骑马军士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOUNTED_SERGEANT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A sergeant, or rather serjeant in medieval Europe, was a man of lesser rank and wealth to a knight, but with comparable equipment and training. Serjeants could fight either as heavy or light cavalry, and here fulfill that secondary role. Serjeants ranked above the common man-at-arms on the social scale. Although the social structure of the Norman society of England was generally static, the easiest manner for a man to attain social rank and improve his standing was through military service, as the Norman states, unlike the Germanic ones, believed in knighting men of common birth who demonstrated nobility and courage on the field.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]中士，或者更确切地说，中世纪欧洲的中士，是一个地位和财富不如骑士的人，但有相当的装备和训练。军士既可以作为重骑兵也可以作为轻骑兵作战，在这里完成第二个角色。在社会上，牧师比普通人更擅长武装。尽管英国诺曼社会的社会结构大体上是静态的，但一个人获得社会地位和提高地位的最简单方式是服兵役，因为诺曼国家不同于日耳曼国家，他们相信在战场上能授予贵族和勇敢的普通出身的骑士。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOUNTED_INFANTRY</Tag>
    <English>Mounted Infantry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>骑马步兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOUNTED_INFANTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Mounted Infantry soldiers use horses to get to the battlefield, but once there they dismount and fight on foot. They rarely take part in charges or other horseback maneuvers, and they tend to suffer badly when engaged in such against trained cavalry units. On the other hand, when fortified on a hill, Mounted Infantry can do serious damage to an attacking Horse Archer or Light Cavalry unit.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]骑兵用马到达战场，但一旦到了战场，他们就下马步行作战。他们很少参加冲锋或其他马背演习，而且在对抗训练有素的骑兵部队时，他们往往会受到严重的伤害。另一方面，当骑兵在山上设防时，骑兵可以对进攻的骑兵或轻骑兵部队造成严重伤害。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LANCER</Tag>
    <English>Lancer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>枪骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LANCER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Carolingians of early medieval France relied heavily on mounted warriors in their conquests. Inventions such as the stirrup and high-backed saddle are sometimes identified as the key element driving the shift from infantry to cavalry. Although these technologies were certainly useful in fighting from horseback, strategic considerations are just as likely to have driven the shift; the extended Carolingian empire required a mobile army. These early cavalry were protected with a byrnie (probably long scale armor) and fought primarily with lance and sword.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]中世纪早期法国的加洛林人在征服过程中非常依赖骑兵。马镫和高背鞍等发明有时被认为是推动步兵向骑兵转变的关键因素。尽管这些技术在骑马作战中确实很有用，但战略考虑同样可能推动了这一转变；加洛林帝国的扩张需要一支机动部队。这些早期的骑兵受到拜尼（可能是长甲）的保护，主要用长矛和剑作战。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_LANCER</Tag>
    <English>Armored Lancer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>重装枪骑</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_LANCER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Increasing armor weight required new breeds of heavier horses to carry mounted warriors. The most highly prized type of war-horse was the destrier, bred specifically for battles or jousts. In the wet climates of Europe, these new breeds required horseshoes to protect their hoofs. All of these developments required a fairly wealthy and advanced civilization, but the price was well worth it: few lighter units could hope to stand against the determined charge of a fully armored lancer.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]增加装甲重量需要新品种更重的马携带骑兵。最珍贵的战马是德雷斯特马，专门为战斗或格斗而培育。在欧洲潮湿的气候中，这些新品种需要马蹄铁来保护它们的蹄。所有这些发展都需要一个相当富裕和先进的文明，但代价是非常值得的：几乎没有轻武器部队能够希望对抗一个全副武装的骑兵的坚决指控。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TREBUCHET</Tag>
    <English>Trebuchet</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>抛石机</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TREBUCHET_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The trebuchet was a medieval siege weapon designed to throw a projectile a great distance through the air. The trebuchet originated in China sometime between the fifth and third centuries BC. From there it spread to the west, reaching Europe around 500 AD. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Although it is usually thought of as a type of catapult, the trebuchet is in fact a gigantic sling attached to a lever. The shorter arm of the lever carries a counterweight, while the longer arm carries the sling that throws the projectile. In operation the sling end is pulled towards the ground (lifting the counterweight in the process) and held in place by a trigger while a projectile is loaded into the sling. When the trigger is released, the counterweight falls and the sling flies up and above the machine, releasing the projectile at the top of its arc. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Constructed properly, trebuchets could fire very heavy loads. In modern reconstructions using trebuchets built with the original tools and materials, trebuchets have been able to throw projectiles weighing as much as 300 kilograms. Aiming the trebuchet was difficult and required some practice and knowledge of engineering - both of which were usually in short supply for medieval operators. Trebuchets were also extremely heavy and almost immobile; this, combined with their slow rate of their fire, made them impractical for anything except siege operations. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Although the Chinese were the first to develop the trebuchet, by the time of the Mongol invasions the Chinese had fallen behind other parts of the world in siege technology. This was due to the fact that China had been politically united for long periods of time, preventing the formation of strong fortresses across the country, and the traditional enemies of the Chinese were nomadic warriors - not fortified city-dwellers. Nevertheless, the Chinese were still far more advanced in siege warfare than the Mongols, and it was not until the Mongols adopted Chinese practices that they began to have success capturing enemy fortifications. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Late in the conquest of Song China, Mongol leader Kublai Khan brought in Arab engineers from the Mongol holdings in Persia to build hinged counterweight trebuchets, which were more advanced than anything yet seen in China. With the aid of these powerful weapons, Kublai was able to take the previously-impenetrable fortress of Xiangyang in 1273, and from there rapidly take the rest of Song China's cities, completing his conquest of the Song Empire in 1279. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>投石机是中世纪的一种攻城武器，设计用来在空中投掷一个很长的距离。投石机起源于公元前5至3世纪的中国。它从那里向西传播，大约在公元500年到达欧洲。[段落：2:1]虽然人们通常认为它是一种弹射器，但投石机实际上是一个巨大的吊索，与杠杆相连。杠杆较短的臂上有一个配重，而较长的臂上有一个抛投弹丸的吊索。在操作中，当弹丸装入吊索时，吊索端部被拉向地面（在过程中提升配重），并由扳机固定到位。当扳机松开时，配重落下，吊带在机器上方上下飞舞，在弧线顶端释放弹丸。[段落：2:1]投石机结构合理，可以发射非常重的弹药。在使用原始工具和材料建造的投石机进行现代重建中，投石机已经能够投掷重达300公斤的弹丸。瞄准投石机是困难的，需要一些实践和工程知识-这两个通常是缺乏中世纪操作员。投石机也非常重，几乎不能移动；这加上它们的射击速度很慢，使得它们除了围城行动外，在任何事情上都不切实际。[第2段：1]虽然中国人是最早发展投石机的，但到蒙古入侵时，中国人的围攻技术已经落后于世界其他地区。这是因为中国在政治上长期团结一致，阻止了全国形成强大的堡垒，中国人的传统敌人是游牧武士――而不是设防的城市居民。尽管如此，中国人在围攻战中仍然比蒙古人先进得多，直到蒙古人采取中国的做法，才开始成功地攻占敌人的防御工事。[段落：2:1]在征服宋中国的后期，蒙古领导人忽必烈从波斯的蒙古控股公司请来阿拉伯工程师来建造铰链式对重投石机，这种投石机比中国任何地方都先进。在这些强大武器的帮助下，忽必烈于1273攻占了以前难以攻破的襄阳要塞，并从那里迅速占领了宋朝其他城市，于1279完成了对宋朝帝国的征服。[第2:1段]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOMBARD</Tag>
    <English>Bombard</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>臼炮</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOMBARD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A bombard is a medieval cannon or mortar, used chiefly in sieges for throwing heavy stone balls. This weapon was usually used during sieges to hurl various forms of missile into enemy fortifications. Projectiles such as stone or metal balls, burning materials and weighted cloth soaked in quicklime or Greek fire are documented.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]轰炸是中世纪的一种大炮或迫击炮，主要用于围攻投掷沉重的石球。这种武器通常在围攻时用来向敌人的防御工事投掷各种形式的导弹。弹丸如石头或金属球、燃烧材料和浸在生石灰或希腊火中的加重布都被记录在案。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FIELD_ARTILLERY</Tag>
    <English>Field Artillery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>野战炮</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FIELD_ARTILLERY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Field artillery is a type of mobile artillery used to suppport armies in the field, offering mobility, tactical proficiency and specializing in long or short range bombardment. Until the 19th century they were known as foot artillery, for while the guns were pulled by beasts of burden (often horses), their crews marched on foot providing fire support for the infantry, unlike the later horse artillery, with their emphasis on speed. who supported cavalry units with their lighter guns and their crews travelling on horseback. Early artillery were unsuited to the battlefield, as the extremely massive pieces could not be easily moved except in areas under friendly control. Thus their principal role was limited to functions like breaking seiges.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first field artillery were developed with advances in metallurgy which allowed thinner barrels able to withstand explosive forces without bursting, thus making them considerably lighter. But there was always the risk that constant changes on the battlefield would leave slow-moving artillery units behind. making them vulnerable to enemy cavalry who often specialized in seeking them out and destroying them. It was only with invention of the limber, pulled by horses hitched to a wheeled artillery piece, in the 18th century, that the concept of field artillery become truly established.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]野战炮兵是一种机动炮兵，用于支援野战部队，提供机动性、战术熟练性，擅长远程或短程轰炸。直到19世纪，他们一直被称为步兵炮，因为当炮兵被猛兽（通常是马）牵引时，他们的士兵步行行进，为步兵提供火力支援，不像后来的马炮，他们强调速度。他们用轻武器支持骑兵部队和骑兵。早期的火炮不适合在战场上使用，因为除了在友军控制的区域外，这些巨大的炮弹很难移动。因此，它们的主要作用仅限于破坏围城之类的功能。[第2段]第一野战炮兵是随着冶金技术的进步而发展起来的，这种技术使较薄的炮管能够承受爆炸力而不爆裂，从而使它们相当轻。但总有一种风险，那就是战场上不断的变化会让行动缓慢的炮兵部队掉队。使他们易受敌军骑兵的攻击，而敌军骑兵往往专门寻找并摧毁他们。只有在18世纪发明了用马拉着的软木车，用轮子的炮弹，野战炮兵的概念才真正确立下来。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUSSAR</Tag>
    <English>Hussar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>轻骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUSSAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Frederick the Great was instrumental in spreading the irregular light cavalry of Hungary (huszars) to the battlefields of Europe. By dropping metal body armor, these light hussars became ideal for reconnaissance and raiding. In battle, they were used in such light cavalry roles as harassing enemy skirmishers, overrunning artillery positions, and pursuing fleeing troops. Following the Prussian example, hussar regiments were introduced across Europe, often maintaining the colorful uniforms a reputation for recklessness in battle of Frederick's original hussars.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]腓特烈大帝帮助匈牙利非正规轻骑兵（Hussars）向欧洲战场扩张。通过投掷金属防弹衣，这些轻骑兵成为侦察和突袭的理想武器。在战斗中，他们被用于轻骑兵的角色，如骚扰敌人的散兵，占领炮兵阵地，并追捕逃跑的部队。以普鲁士为例，在欧洲各地引入了轻骑兵团，经常保持着在弗雷德里克最初的轻骑兵战斗中鲁莽的名声。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PISTOLIER</Tag>
    <English>Pistolier</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>手枪骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PISTOLIER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Pistols were the first gunpowder weapons developed for cavalry, and the pistoliers was one of the new cavalry types to develop which signaled the end of the lance-charging heavy cavalry. Pistoliers were expected to be able to engage their opponents both with firearms and sword; they formed up in deep blocks and used their firearms in a caracole attack to disrupt enemy infantry formations before charging home and engaging in hand-to-hand combat. German mercenary cavalry called Reiters or "Black Riders" were some of the most prominent pistoliers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]手枪是最早为骑兵研制的火药武器，手枪兵是新发展的骑兵类型之一，标志着长矛冲锋重骑兵的终结。手枪手被期望能够用枪械和剑与对手交战；他们在很深的街区内集结，用枪械进行一次卡拉科尔攻击，扰乱敌人的步兵编队，然后冲向家乡，进行肉搏战。德国雇佣兵骑兵雷特或“黑骑士”是一些最著名的手枪手。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGOON</Tag>
    <English>Dragoon</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>龙骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGOON_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The word "dragoon" is derived from the French Army designation dragon which was originally the name of a type of firearm (whose name means dragon) carried by French dragoons. In French, Portuguese and Spanish there is no distinction between the words dragoon and dragon.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dragoons were originally infantrymen deployed by horse, but later became cavalry. They were therefore trained in horse riding as well as infantry fighting skills. Dragoon regiments were established in most European armies during the late 17th and early 18th centuries. Originally dragoons were considered as separate from regular cavalry, but during the 18th century they evolved into conventional mounted troops trained to fight from horseback.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
    <Chinese>[表]龙骑兵一词来源于法国军队的名称“龙”，最初是法国龙骑兵携带的一种火器（龙的意思是龙）的名称。在法语、葡萄牙语和西班牙语中，龙骑兵和龙没有区别。因此，他们接受了骑马和步兵战斗技能的训练。在17世纪末和18世纪初，大部分欧洲军队都建立了龙骑兵团。最初，龙骑兵被认为是独立于正规骑兵的，但在18世纪，他们演变成了传统的骑兵，接受过骑马作战的训练。</Chinese>   
    </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARQUEBUSIER</Tag>
    <English>Arquebusier</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>火绳枪兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARQUEBUSIER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The arquebus is an early muzzle-loaded firearm. They were used against enemies that were often protected by steel-plate armor, which a bullet could pierce only at close range. The arquebus was unable to match the accuracy of a bow in the hands of a highly-skilled archer. However, it had a faster rate of fire than the most powerful crossbow, and a much shorter learning curve than a longbow. Once the methods were developed, powder and shot were relatively easy to mass-produce, while arrow making was a genuine craft requiring highly skilled labor.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]arquebus是一种早期的枪口式武器。它们被用来对付通常由钢板装甲保护的敌人，这种装甲只有在近距离才能被子弹穿透。在一位技艺高超的弓箭手手中，这架火箭炮的精度无法与弓媲美。然而，它的射速比最强大的弩快，学习曲线比长弓短得多。一旦这些方法被开发出来，粉末和子弹就相对容易大量生产，而制箭是一项真正的工艺，需要高度熟练的劳动力。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LINE_INFANTRY</Tag>
    <English>Line Infantry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>线列步兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LINE_INFANTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Line infantry refers to those regiments that historically fought in linear formations, unlike light troops who fought in loose order. Generally speaking, line infantry were so named because they made up the line of battle rather than because they necessarily fought in lines. The 17th.C saw the expansion of the roles of the infantry as the improvement of gunpowder weapons made the mixed pike and shot formations like the Spanish Tercios increasingly effective. Fighting in close order squares these disciplined combined arms units were feared on the battlefield throughout Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Increasingly in the 18th century line infantry units became wholly equiped with accurate long-range firearms and were deployed as integrated units. Typically, specialist companies were deployed on the flanks of the main body of musket-armed infantry with a company of light infantry trained as skirmishers to operate independently on the battlefield and a company of grenadiers, who were usually the biggest and strongest men in the regiment, deployed in advance as the lead assault troops. Regiments of these line infantry remained the mainstay of all European armies until the beginning of the 20th century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]线步兵是指那些历史上以直线队形作战的团，而不是轻装部队以松散的顺序作战。一般来说，线列步兵之所以这样命名，是因为他们组成了一条战线，而不是因为他们必须排成一行。公元17世纪，随着火药武器的改进，像西班牙特西奥那样的混合长矛和射击队形变得越来越有效，步兵的作用也在扩大。这些训练有素的联合兵种部队在欧洲战场上的战斗是令人恐惧的。[第2段]在18世纪，步兵部队越来越多地完全装备了精确的远程武器，并被部署为综合兵种。通常情况下，专家连部署在步枪武装步兵主体的侧翼，一个轻步兵连作为散兵接受训练，在战场上独立作战，一个榴弹兵连通常是该团最大和最强壮的人，作为先头突击部队提前部署。在20世纪初以前，这些步兵团一直是欧洲所有军队的中流砥柱。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SWORDSMAN</Tag>
    <English>Swordsman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>剑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SWORDSMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Swords in antiquity and classical times tended to be relatively short, at first because they were made of bronze and later because they were rarely called upon to penetrate armor. The blade of the classic Roman stabbing sword, the gladius, was only some two feet long, though in the twilight years of the empire the gladius gave way to the spatha, the long slashing sword of the barbarians and forerunner of the great broadswords of medieval Europe. During the Early Middle Ages, European swords tended to be long and straight, with no crossguard to protect the wielder's hand.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]古代和古典时期的剑往往比较短，最初是因为它们是青铜制成的，后来因为很少要求它们穿透盔甲。古典罗马刺刀格拉迪斯的刀刃只有两英尺长，尽管在帝国的暮年，格拉迪斯让位给了斯巴达，野蛮人的长刀和中世纪欧洲大刀的先驱。在中世纪早期，欧洲的剑往往是长而直的，没有护手来保护持剑者的手。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LONG_SWORDSMAN</Tag>
    <English>Longswordsman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>长剑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LONG_SWORDSMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Longsword is a type of European sword used during the late medieval period. Made to counter the increasingly strong armor of the time, the longsword was commonly held in combat with both hands, though some may be used single-handed. A man-at-arms or dismounted knight fighting with a longsword would also have worn substantial other armor, such as a mail hauberk and helm. The terms "hand-and-a-half sword", "greatsword", and "bastard sword" are used colloquially to refer to longswords in general.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]长剑是中世纪晚期使用的一种欧洲剑。为了对抗当时日益强大的盔甲，长剑通常用双手握在战斗中，尽管有些可能是单手握着的。一个持枪的人或者一个骑着长剑的骑士也会穿着其他的盔甲，比如一个盔甲和头盔。“手半剑”、“巨剑”和“私生子剑”通俗地用来指长剑。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SCOUT</Tag>
    <English>Skirmisher</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>散兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SCOUT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Light cavalry have been employed as scouts and skirmisher from ancient times. The only real requirement for these units is that they be able to cover great distances and escape from situations in which they would be killed. Specially trained or bred horses are not required, and the unit needs to be only minimally armored. Before the development of the stirrup and other equestrian technology, it took years to learn to fight from horseback effectively, not a worthwhile investment for scouting units.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>轻骑兵自古以来就被用作童子军和散兵。对这些部队的唯一真正要求是，他们能够覆盖很远的距离，逃离他们将被杀害的情况。不需要特别训练或繁殖的马，部队只需要最低限度的装甲。在马镫和其他马术技术发展之前，花了好几年时间才学会有效地骑马作战，这对侦察部队来说是不值得的投资。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COGGE</Tag>
    <English>Cog</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>柯克战船</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COGGE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The cog (or cogge) was a type of ship which first appeared in Northern Europe and was widely used from the 12th century onwards. Cogs were generally made of oak, an abundant timber in the Baltic region, and were fitted with a single mast and square-rigged sail. Even though this rigging prevented them sailing into the wind, cogs between associated with sea going trade in the northern waters of Medieval Europe. They were generally flat-bottomed and employed a stern-mounted rudder with fore and stern castles as defense against pirates, enabling them to often used as warships. By the late 15th century they were replaced by the carrack which was more sea-worthy and suitable for sailing in the open ocean over longer distances.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]齿轮是一种最早出现在北欧的船舶，从12世纪开始广泛使用。齿轮通常由橡树制成，这是波罗的海地区一种丰富的木材，装有一根桅杆和方形帆。尽管这种索具阻止了它们乘风航行，但中世纪欧洲北部水域的海上贸易也产生了齿轮。它们通常是平底的，并使用一个安装在船尾的舵和船首和船尾的城堡作为防御海盗，使他们经常被用作军舰。到了15世纪晚期，它们被卡拉克号所取代，卡拉克号更适合在公海航行更长的距离。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUN_GALLEY</Tag>
    <English>Gun Galley</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>帆桨舰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUN_GALLEY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A galley is a type of ship that can be propelled entirely by human oarsmen and used for warfare and trade, but usually had masts and sails for use when the wind was favourable. Various types of galleys dominated naval warfare in the Meditteranean Sea from the 8th century BC to the 16th century. Many medieval states, notably Venice, Genoa, the Byzantines, Arabs and the Ottoman Turks depended largely on heavily-armed galleys until the introduction of the ocean-going "man-of-war". The Battle of Lepanto, in 1571, was one of the largest and last sea battles in which galleys played the principal part.[PARAGRAPH:2]Galleys remained in regular use in the Meditteranean until the introduction of broadside sailing ships in the 17th century. While war galleys originally carried archers and slingers for offensive operations and defence, the advent of gunpowder weapons saw the development of early cannons mounted on ships. In fact, medieval war galleys pioneered the use of naval guns, with the typical Venetian gun galley or "laterna" mounting high calibe guns in the bow and stern with various lighter swivel guns deployed throughout the ship. However, with the development of the high-sided carrack and galleass capable of powerful broadside cannonfire, the usefulness of these gun galleys eventually came to an end.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]帆船是一种完全由人用桨推动的船舶，用于战争和贸易，但通常有桅杆和帆，在风好的时候使用。从公元前8世纪到16世纪，各种类型的军舰在地中海海战中占据主导地位。许多中世纪国家，特别是威尼斯、热那亚、拜占庭、阿拉伯人和奥斯曼土耳其人，在引进远洋的“战争人物”之前，主要依靠全副武装的大帆船。1571年的莱潘托战役是最大的也是最后一次以帆船为主体的海战之一。当战舰最初携带弓箭手和投弹手进行进攻和防御时，火药武器的出现见证了早期舰载大炮的发展。事实上，中世纪的战舰率先使用了舰炮，典型的威尼斯炮舰或“拉特纳”在船头和船尾安装了高口径火炮，各种较轻的旋转炮部署在整艘船上。然而，随着高边卡拉克和大帆船的发展，能够强大的宽边炮，这些大帆船的用处最终结束了。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HOLK</Tag>
    <English>Holk</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>霍克战船</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HOLK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A holk (or hulk) was a type of sea craft similiar to the cog and was one of the technological forerunners of the carrack and caravel. Like cogs, they were generally flat-bottomed and square-sailed with overlapping "strakes" or planks at each end and full lapstrakes covering the sides. Their keels were shallow and their sternpost straight and long with a stern-mounted central rudder similiar to those in the cog. Improvements in wood-working techniques allowed a transition from smaller cogs to holks of greater capacity until both were overtaken by the development of the carrack and caravel in the late 14th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]The holk was probably a fairly minor type of boat and largely confined to the Low Countries and the Baltic where it was used originally as a river or canal boat with a limited potential for sea cruising. Even so, for a period in the 14th century holks began to evolve into larger examples which exceeded the cog in both size and capacity, if not in ocean-going sea-worthiness and the holk remained a major load carrier in the medieval economy well into the 16th century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]霍尔克（或绿巨人）是一种类似于齿轮的海船，是卡拉克和克拉维尔的技术先驱之一。像齿轮一样，它们通常是平底的方形帆，每端都有重叠的“边条”或木板，两边都有完整的搭接边条。它们的龙骨很浅，船尾柱又直又长，有一个安装在船尾上的中央舵，与船齿上的舵相似。木材加工技术的改进使其从较小的齿轮过渡到更大容量的孔，直到14世纪晚期卡拉克和克拉维尔的发展超过了两者。[第2段]孔可能是一种相当小的船型，主要局限于低地国家和使用它的波罗的海地区最初作为一条河流或运河船，在海上航行的潜力有限。即便如此，在14世纪的一段时间里，霍尔克开始演变成规模和容量都超过cog的更大的例子，如果不是在远洋适航性方面，而且霍尔克在中世纪经济中一直是一个主要的载货船，一直到16世纪。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WAR_GALLEY</Tag>
    <English>War Galley</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>军用帆桨舰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WAR_GALLEY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Galleys, propelled by banks of oarsmen and equiped with masts and sails, have been employed in warfare throughout history since the ancient Greeks and Phoenicians. While the use of war galleys was largely confined to the Meditteranean, the early Norsemen developed the longship, a clinker-built narrow, sleek galley of shallow draught capable of travelling on inland rivers as well as being extremely seaworthy on the open ocean under sail. Longships became the epitome of Norse naval power and remained dominant in Northern Europe until the introduction of the cog and the carrack in the 14th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]War galleys, as employed in the Meditteranean, were less capable of ocean voyages but ideal for shallow waters and near-shore navigation and soon grew considerably in size and firepower. The largest examples were rowed by nearly 300 men and carried a further 400 crew and fighting soldiers as well as dozens of cannons of all sizes. By the late 16th century the large war galleys became mostly obsolete by the man-of-war although they remained the mainstay of the North African "corsair" pirate fleets and continue to play a significant role in the Meditteranean until the beginning of the 19th century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]自古希腊人和腓尼基人以来，帆船就一直被用于战争，由一排排排的桨手推动，配备桅杆和帆。虽然战舰的使用在很大程度上局限于地中海地区，但早期的北欧人发展出了长桅帆船，这是一种用水泥建造的窄而光滑的浅吃水的战舰，既能在内陆河流上航行，又能在开敞的海上航行。长桅帆船成为挪威海军力量的缩影，并一直在北欧占主导地位，直到14世纪引入了cog和carrack。[第2段]军舰，如在地中海使用的，不太适合远洋航行，但非常适合浅海和近岸航行，很快在尺寸和火力。最大的例子是有近300人划船，另外还有400名船员和战斗士兵，以及数十门各种大小的大炮。到了16世纪晚期，大型战舰基本上已被战争人士淘汰，尽管它们仍然是北非海盗舰队的主力，并在地中海地区继续发挥重要作用，直到19世纪初。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PROSECUTOR</Tag>
    <English>Religious Prosecutor</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>宗教裁判官</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PROSECUTOR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]While Missionaries often focus on extolling the glories of their respective gods to spread their religion, the Prosecutors focuses instead on pointing out the fallacies of all religions but his own. Ardent in the belief that all other religions are wrong, the Prosecutor lives to destroy the beliefs of others. If the Prosecution convicted a person of heresy, the personal property of a condemned person was confiscated and places of worship were destroyed; based on medieval and feudal laws. Usually the confiscated property was divided three ways: by the Prosecution members, the church officials, and the state treasury. The Church and state kept strict accounts of the prisoner's incarceration, trial and execution costs. If the value of his confiscated property was not enough to cover these costs, then his heirs had to pay the difference. Records show many women and children were left penniless from such confiscation. You may expend a Prosecutor inside a city to remove all religions from that city except your own.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]虽然传教士经常把注意力放在颂扬各自神的荣耀来传播他们的宗教，但检察官却把注意力放在指出除他自己的宗教以外的所有宗教的谬误上。检察官坚信所有其他宗教都是错误的，他活着就是为了摧毁他人的信仰。如果检方判定某人犯有异端罪，则根据中世纪和封建法律没收被判刑人的个人财产并摧毁礼拜场所。通常被没收的财产分为三种方式：检方成员、教会官员和国库。教会和国家对囚犯的监禁、审判和处决费用都有严格的记录。如果没收财产的价值不足以支付这些费用，那么他的继承人必须支付差额。记录显示，许多妇女和儿童因这种没收而身无分文。你可以在一个城市里聘请一名检察官，把除你自己的宗教以外的所有宗教从这个城市除名。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Unique Units -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARABIA_GHAZI</Tag>
    <English>Ghazi</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>加齐战士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARABIA_GHAZI_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Ghazi warriors were fierce Arabic light/medium cavalry armed with sword and lance, who raided deep into enemy territory to make war on unbelievers. Depending largely on plunder for their livelihood they were organized in bands similiar to mercenary companies which attracted religious zealots and adventurers of every kind. Within the context of Islamic jihad warfare, they struck fast and hard inside enemy borders to destroy war materials and morale, then withdrawing with all the loot they could carry. As flexible and highly mobile border defenders and raiders they often preceeded the deployment of much larger armies during the early Arab invasions of Persia, Egypt and North Africa.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>加齐战士是凶猛的阿拉伯轻/中型骑兵，手持长剑和长矛，深入敌方领土，向不信者发动战争。他们主要依靠掠夺为生，组织成类似于雇佣兵公司的团伙，吸引各种宗教狂热分子和冒险家。在伊斯兰圣战的背景下，他们在敌人的边界内迅速而猛烈地打击，以摧毁战争物资和士气，然后带着他们所能携带的所有战利品撤退。作为灵活和高度机动的边境保卫者和袭击者，他们经常在阿拉伯入侵波斯、埃及和北非的早期部署更大规模的军队。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BURGUNDIAN_PALADIN</Tag>
    <English>Paladin</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>帕拉丁圣骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BURGUNDIAN_PALADIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Paladins (often called Chevaliers) were Medieval knights who followed the code of chivalry or knightly conduct, which emphasized courage, honour and service. The Paladin was adept at the art of war, trained in fighting in armour on horses with lances, swords and shields. They were expected to show courage, be gallant to women, defend the Church and swear off cowardice and baseness. Their origins lie with the first mounted infantry in the armies of the Emperor Charlemagne as some elite warriors who wore armour and fought on horseback were rewarded with grants of land called "benefices" and became powerful captains with feudal fiefs that soon became hereditary and powerful, both in political influence and economic wealth.[PARAGRAPH:2]These knights became the mainstay of governing power under the King, raising their own armies in time of war and often rivalled the Church in wealth and influence. But chivalry and the Church remained closely entwined and the Crusades helped to reinforce the moral code of chivalry as it related to religion. Thus Christian armies were encouraged to devote their efforts to sacred purposes and the Paladins were expected to use their weapons for the protection of the weak and defenceless, to women and children, and above all to the defence of churches and pilgrims, giving rise to the religious military orders like the Templars, the Hospitallers and the Teutonic Knights. Some knightly orders, like the English "Order of the Bath" or the "Order of the Garter" remain day as honorary associations whose membership is granted by the Monarch for meritorious achievement.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>圣骑士（通常被称为骑士）是中世纪的骑士，他们遵循骑士或骑士行为准则，强调勇气、荣誉和服务。圣骑士擅长战争艺术，受过骑兵、长矛、长剑和盾牌的盔甲训练。人们期望他们表现出勇气，对妇女英勇，捍卫教会，发誓不再懦弱和卑鄙。它们起源于查理曼大帝军队中的第一批骑兵，因为一些身穿盔甲、骑马作战的精锐战士获得了称为“恩赐”的土地，并成为封建封地的强大首领，这些封地很快就世袭而强大，无论是在政治上还是在经济上，这些骑士都成为国王统治权力的中流砥柱，他们在战争时期组建自己的军队，在财富和影响力上经常与教会抗衡。但骑士精神和教会仍然紧密相连，十字军东征有助于加强骑士精神的道德准则，因为它与宗教有关。因此，鼓励基督教军队致力于神圣的目的，并期望圣骑士使用他们的武器来保护弱者和手无寸铁的人，保护妇女和儿童，尤其是保护教堂和朝圣者，从而产生像圣殿骑士那样的宗教军事命令，医院管理员和条顿骑士。一些骑士勋章，如英国的“浴勋章”或“吊袜带勋章”，作为荣誉协会保留一天，其成员资格由君主授予功勋。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BULGARIAN_KONNIK</Tag>
    <English>Konnik</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>骁骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BULGARIA_KONNIK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Bulgars were highly skilled in the equestrian arts. Their army mainly consisted of horseman because of their high skill. Every Bulgar horseman had high discipline and had several horses. However, only a single horse could be used for wartime matters, and it was forbidden to do anything else with it. It is believed that the Bulgars were the first who brought the stirrups to Europe. This gave them advantages above the other European armies of this time. The Bulgars could use bows still mounted on horses. Swords and spears were also used in war. The stirrups also increased the stability and speed of the rider.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>保加利亚人在马术方面技艺高超。由于技艺高超，他们的军队主要由骑兵组成。每一个保加利亚骑手都有很高的纪律和几匹马。然而，只有一匹马可以用于战时事务，禁止用它做任何其他事情。人们相信保加利亚人是第一个把马镫带到欧洲的人。这使他们比当时的其他欧洲军队有优势。保加利亚人可以使用仍然骑在马上的弓。战争中也使用剑和矛。马镫也增加了骑手的稳定性和速度。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORDOBAN_BERBER_CAVALRY</Tag>
    <English>Berber Cavalry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>柏柏尔骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORDOBAN_BERBER_CAVALRY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Following the Muslim conquest of North Africa in the 7th century, the Berber peoples of the Maghreb and Morocco largely adopted Islam and became the mainstay of Arab armies in the West. Skilled with bow and javelin and mounted on camels, they soon mastered the horse and became adept as scouting and raiding light cavalry. The Arab conquest of Iberia initiated by the Berber general, Tarik ibn-Zihad consisted of about 300 elite Arabian cavalry and a mixed Berber army of about 1800-2000 bowmen, spearmen and light cavalry. Later Andalusian armies were largely comprised of a core of Arabian noble horsemen and a majority of Berber voluteers and mercenaries who fought both on foot and on horseback.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]7世纪穆斯林征服北非后，马格里布和摩洛哥的柏柏尔人基本上信奉伊斯兰教，成为西方阿拉伯军队的中流砥柱。他们精通弓和标枪，骑在骆驼上，很快就掌握了马的技能，成为侦察和突袭轻骑兵的能手。阿拉伯征服伊比利亚由柏柏尔将军塔里克・伊本・齐哈德发起，由大约300名阿拉伯精锐骑兵和大约1800-2000名弓箭手、长矛手和轻骑兵组成的柏柏尔混合军队组成。后来的安达卢西亚军队主要由阿拉伯贵族骑兵的核心组成，还有大部分的柏柏尔蜗牛兵和雇佣兵，他们步行和骑马作战。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPANISH_TERCIO</Tag>
    <English>Tercio</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>大方阵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPANISH_TERCIO_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Tercio ("one third"), also known as Tercio Espaol, was a Renaissance era military formation similar to and derivative of the Swiss pike square and was a term used to describe a mixed infantry formation of about 3,000 pikemen, swordsmen and arquebusiers in a mutually supportive formation; it was also sometimes referred to by other nations as a Spanish Square after its introduction by the Spanish army, and was widely adopted across international lines and dominated formalized field warfare for more than a century.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Tercio Espaol was the product of the Italian Wars in which the Spanish general, Gonzalo Fernndez de Crdoba, would reorganize the Spanish army throughout a series of conflicts at the end of the 15th and early 16th centuries, into a tactically unique combination of modern and medieval combined arms centered around armored infantry. This emphasis on the infantry was the result of Spain's great dependence on mules in daily life, which in turn resulted in an inability to raise large cavalry forces. It marked the transformation of medieval military institutions into the early modern combined-arms army. (See: Pike and Shot for an excellent description of the eventual formation.) Gonzalo Fernndez, developed the Tercio to further increase the effectiveness of Spanish infantry against every manner of opposing infantry while remaining impervious to the dangers of a cavalry charge.[PARAGRAPH:2]At first the army consisted of units of around 6000 men, called coronelias, which by 1534 had been reduced into the Tercios of 3000 for increased mobility on the offensive.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]Tercio（“三分之一”）又称Tercio Espaol，是文艺复兴时期的一种军事编队，类似于瑞士派克广场，是瑞士派克广场的衍生物，是一个术语，用于描述一个由大约3000名射击兵、剑客和弓箭手组成的相互支持的混合步兵编队；它有时也被其他国家称为西班牙广场，在西班牙军队引入后，它被广泛地应用于国际战线，并主导了一个多世纪的正规化野战Crdoba将在15世纪末和16世纪初的一系列冲突中重组西班牙军队，形成以装甲步兵为中心的现代和中世纪联合兵种的独特战术组合。这种对步兵的重视是西班牙在日常生活中严重依赖骡子的结果，而骡子反过来又导致了西班牙无法提高大型骑兵部队的兵力。它标志着中世纪军事机构向早期现代联合兵种的转变。（见：长矛和射击，以获得对最终编队的完美描述。）冈萨洛・弗恩・德兹开发了Tercio，以进一步提高西班牙步兵对抗各种敌对步兵的效能，同时不受骑兵冲锋危险的影响。[第2段]起初，这支军队由大约6000人组成，被称为coronelias，到1534年，由于在进攻中增加了机动性，它已经减少到3000个。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VENICE_GALLEAS</Tag>
    <English>Galleass</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>威尼斯炮舰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VENICE_GALLEAS_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The galleass or "galliass" developed from large merchant galleys converted for military use they were higher and larger than regular ("light") galleys. They had up to 32 oars, each worked by up to 5 men. They usually had three masts and a forecastle and aftcastle. Much effort was made in Venice to make these galleasses as fast as possible to compete with regular galleys. The gun-deck usually ran over the rowers' heads, but there are also pictures showing the opposite arrangement.[PARAGRAPH:2]Galleasses usually carried more sails than true galleys, and were far deadlier; a galley caught broadside lay all but helpless, but coming broadside to a galleass, as with a ship of the line, exposed an attacker to her gunfire. The galleass exemplified an intermediate type between the galley and the true man-of-war. Relatively few galleasses were built - one disadvantage was that, being more reliant on sails, their position at the front of the galley line at the start of a battle could not be guaranteed - but they were used at the Battle of Lepanto (7 October 1571), their firepower helping to win victory for the Christian fleet, and some sufficiently seaworthy galleasses accompanied the Spanish Armada in 1588 (e.g. La Girona). In the 15th century a type of light galleass, called the frigate, was built in southern European countries to answer the increasing challenge posed by the north African based Barbary pirates in their fast galleys.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the Mediterranean, with its shallower waters, less dangerous weather and fickle winds, both galleasses and galleys continued in use, particularly in Venice and Turkey, long after they became obsolete elsewhere. Later, "round ships" and galleasses were replaced by galleons and ships of the line which originated in Atlantic Europe. The first Venetian ship of the line was built in 1660.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]大帆船或“Gallaass”是由大型商用大帆船改装而成的，它们比普通的（“轻型”）大而高。他们有多达32个桨，每个桨由多达5个人操作。他们通常有三个桅杆，一个前舱和一个后舱。在威尼斯，人们尽了很大的努力使这些大帆船尽可能快地与普通的大帆船竞争。枪械甲板通常在赛艇手的头顶上，但也有相反的排列方式的图片。[第2段]帆船通常比真正的帆船载着更多的帆，而且要致命得多；一艘被捕获的帆船横着躺着，几乎无助，但却横着向一艘帆船靠近，就像一艘划船一样，把袭击者暴露在她的枪声中。厨房是厨房和真正的战争人物之间的中间类型。建造的帆船相对较少――一个缺点是，由于更加依赖帆船，它们在战斗开始时在帆船线上的位置无法得到保证――但它们被用于莱潘托战役（1571年10月7日），它们的火力有助于为基督教舰队赢得胜利，1588年，西班牙无敌舰队（如拉吉罗纳）也有一些足够适合航海的帆船。在15世纪，一种叫做护卫舰的轻型帆船在南欧国家建造，以应对北非的野蛮海盗在他们的快速帆船上提出的日益严峻的挑战，厨房和厨房继续使用，特别是在威尼斯和土耳其，它们在其他地方早已过时。后来，起源于大西洋欧洲的“圆船”和“帆船”被“线船”取代。这条线的第一艘威尼斯船建于1660年。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUNGARIAN_HUSZAR</Tag>
    <English>Huszr</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>胡萨尔轻骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUNGARIAN_HUSZAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A type of irregular light horsemen was already well established by the 15th century in medieval Hungary. Etymologists are divided over the derivation of the word 'hussar'. Many scholars believe the word that was passed into Hungarian by way of the Croatians originates from the Latin word 'cursus' meaning 'raid'. According to Webster's the word hussar stems from the Hungarian huszr, which in turn originates from the Serbian husar or gusar, meaning pirate, from the Medieval Latin cursarius (cf. the English word corsair). A variant of this theory is offered by Byzantinist scholars, who argue the term originated in Roman military practice, and the cursarius--a group of fast moving horsemen used for scouting or raiding-came to be called tsanarioi in Greek or the Armenian Chosarioi. Through Byzantine Army operations in the Balkans in the 10th and 11th centuries, the word was thus reintroduced to Western European military practice after its original usage had been lost with the collapse of Rome in the west. According to another theory, the word is derived from the Hungarian word of hsz meaning twenty, suggesting that hussar regiments were originally composed of twenty men. Or the term huszr probably signified 'one in twenty' as selected for service by ballot.[PARAGRAPH:2]The hussars reportedly originated in bands of Hungarian and Serbian warriors crossing into southern Hungary after the Turkish invasion of Serbia at the end of the 14th century. The Governor of Hungary, Hunyadi Jnos - John Hunyadi, created mounted units inspired by his enemy the Ottoman Turks. His son, Hunyadi Mtys Matthias Corvinus, later king of Hungary, is unanimously accepted as the creator of these troops. Initially they fought in small bands, but were reorganized into larger, trained, formations during the reign of King Matthias I Corvinus of Hungary. So the first Hussar regiments were the light cavalry of the Black Army of Hungary. Under his command the hussars took part in the war against the Ottoman Empire in 1485 and proved successful against the Turkish Spahis as well as against Bohemians and Poles. After the king's death in 1490, hussars remained the preferred form of cavalry in Hungary. The Habsburg emperors hired Hungarian hussars as mercenaries to serve against the Ottoman Empire and on various battlefields throughout Europe. The "father" of the US cavalry in 1777 was a Hungarian hussar named Kovts Mihly - Michael de Kovats.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]一种不规则的轻骑兵在15世纪时就已经在中世纪的匈牙利建立起来了。词源学家对“侯赛尔”一词的词源有分歧。许多学者认为克罗地亚人传入匈牙利语的单词来源于拉丁语单词“cursus”，意思是“raid”。根据韦伯斯特的说法，hussar一词源于匈牙利huszr，而匈牙利huszr又源于塞尔维亚husar或gusar，意思是海盗，源于中世纪拉丁语cursarius（参见英语单词corsair）。拜占庭学者提出了这一理论的一种变体，他们认为这个术语起源于罗马的军事实践，而库萨里乌斯（cursarius）――一组用于侦察或突袭的快速移动的骑兵，在希腊语或亚美尼亚语中被称为tsanarioi。通过10世纪和11世纪拜占庭军队在巴尔干半岛的行动，这个词在最初的用法随着西方罗马的崩溃而消失之后，重新被引入西欧的军事实践中。根据另一种理论，这个词来源于匈牙利语hsz的单词，意思是20，这表明侯赛尔兵团最初由20人组成。或者“丈夫”这个词可能意味着“二十分之一”是通过投票选出的。[第2段]据报道，这些侯赛尔人起源于14世纪末土耳其入侵塞尔维亚后，匈牙利和塞尔维亚的勇士们穿越匈牙利南部。匈牙利总督胡尼亚迪Jnos-John Hunyadi受其敌人奥斯曼土耳其人的启发，创建了骑兵部队。他的儿子Hunyadi MtysMatthias Corvinus，后来的匈牙利国王，被一致接受为这些军队的创造者。最初，他们以小规模战斗，但在匈牙利国王马蒂亚斯一世科维努斯统治时期重组为更大、训练有素的阵型。因此，第一批轻骑兵团是匈牙利黑军的轻骑兵。在他的指挥下，轻骑兵于1485年参加了对奥斯曼帝国的战争，并证明了对土耳其斯帕伊以及对波希米亚人和波兰人的战争是成功的。1490年国王去世后，在匈牙利，骑兵仍然是首选的骑兵形式。哈布斯堡皇帝雇佣匈牙利骑兵作为雇佣兵，对抗奥斯曼帝国和欧洲各地的战场。1777年，美国骑兵部队的“父亲”是一位匈牙利轻骑兵，名叫科夫斯・米希・迈克尔・德科瓦茨（Kovts Mihly-Michael de Kovats）。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_POLISH_WINGED_HUSSAR</Tag>
    <English>Winged Hussar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>波兰翼骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_POLISH_WINGED_HUSSAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The first hussar units in the Kingdom of Poland were formed by the Sejm, the Polish Parliament, in 1503 which hired three banners of Hungarian mercenaries. Soon, recruitment also began among Polish and Lithuanian citizens. The Hussars proved vital to Poland because they were more maneuverable than the previously used lancers. But the reign of King Stefan Batory, the hussars formed the bulk of the Polish and Lithuanian cavalry. Over many years, hussars in Hungary became heavier. When Stefan Batory was elected king of Poland, he reorganized the Polish-Lithuanian hussars of his Royal Guard making them a heavy formation, and equipping lancers as their main weapon. These Polish 'heavy' hussars were known in their homeland as "husaria"[PARAGRAPH:2]With the Battle of Lubiszew in 1577, the "Golden Age" of the hussar began. Until the Battle of Vienna, Polish-Lithuanian hussars rarely lost in battle. Throughout many battles the Polish-Lithuanian hussars would prove to be an important factor against overwhelming odds.[PARAGRAPH:2]The primary battle tactic of the Polish-Lithuanian hussars was the charge. They also tended to repeat the charge until the enemy formation broke. The hussars fought with a long lance, a szabla, one or two pistols, and a carbine or arquebus, known in Polish as a "bandolet". Polish hussars were also famous for the wings they wore on their backs. According to some theories, they were designed to foil attacks by Tatar lassos, another theory being that the vibrating of feathers made a strange sound that frightened enemy horses. However, experiments carried out by re-enactors and movie-makers since the 1970s and more recently by Polish historians in 2001 contradict such ideas. Possibly the wings were worn only during parades and not during combat, but this explanation is also disputed.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>波兰王国的第一批轻骑兵部队是1503年由波兰议会组成的，议会雇佣了匈牙利雇佣兵的三面旗帜。不久，波兰和立陶宛公民也开始招募。事实证明，轻骑兵对波兰至关重要，因为他们比以前使用的骑兵更具机动性。但是在斯特凡・巴托里国王统治时期，大部分波兰和立陶宛骑兵都是由轻骑兵组成的。多年来，匈牙利的轻骑兵变得更重了。当斯特凡・巴托里当选波兰国王时，他重组了皇家卫队中的波兰-立陶宛轻骑兵，使其成为一个重型编队，并以装备骑兵为主要武器。这些波兰重骑兵在他们的祖国被称为“husaria”[第2段]随着1577年卢比索战役的爆发，轻骑兵的“黄金时代”开始了。直到维也纳战役，波兰立陶宛轻骑兵很少在战斗中失败。在许多战斗中，波兰-立陶宛轻骑兵将证明是对抗压倒性优势的一个重要因素。[第2段]波兰-立陶宛轻骑兵的主要作战战术是冲锋。他们也倾向于重复冲锋，直到敌军编队溃退。轻骑兵们用长矛、一支萨布拉手枪、一两支手枪、一支卡宾枪或一支arquebus进行战斗，波兰人称之为“bandolet”。波兰轻骑兵也以他们背上的翅膀而闻名。根据一些理论，它们被设计用来抵御鞑靼套索的攻击，另一种理论是羽毛的振动发出一种奇怪的声音，吓坏了敌人的马。然而，自20世纪70年代以来，由改版者和电影制作者进行的实验，以及最近由波兰历史学家在2001年进行的实验，都与这些想法相矛盾。可能翅膀只是在阅兵时才戴，而不是在战斗中，但这个解释也有争议。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOSCOW_BOYAR</Tag>
    <English>Boyar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>贵族骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOSCOW_BOYAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A boyar was a member of the highest rank of the feudal Bulgarian, Kievan Rus and Moscovian aristocracies, second only to the ruling dukes. Boyars weilded considerable power through their military support of the Moscovian princes and state, their traditions of family service and their ownership of land. Very similiar to Western knights, they were armed with swords and bows and equiped with chain or plate armour, and commanded their own personal armies of peasant levies and mercenaries. They continued to occupy the highest state offices, after repelling the Mongol invasions of the 13th century, throughout the 14th and 15th centuries until their power was eroded by the Czars, chiefly Ivan IV, during the 16th century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]博雅尔是保加利亚封建贵族、基辅罗斯贵族和莫斯科维亚贵族中最高等级的成员，仅次于执政的公爵。博雅尔通过对莫斯科维亚王子和国家的军事支持，他们的家庭服务传统和土地所有权，获得了相当大的权力。与西方骑士非常相似，他们手持剑和弓，装备链甲或板甲，指挥自己的农民征兵和雇佣兵的私人军队。他们在击退13世纪的蒙古入侵之后，在整个14世纪和15世纪继续占据最高的国家职位，直到他们的权力在16世纪被沙皇（主要是伊凡四世）侵蚀。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GENOA_BALESTRIERI</Tag>
    <English>Balestrieri</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>热那亚弩手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GENOA_BALESTRIERI_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Genoese crossbowmen were a famous military formation both in the defence of Genoa and as mercenaries for other Italian and European powers during the Middle Ages. Fighting on both land and in naval battles, they were outfitted with a dagger, light metal helmet, gorget and a large shield called a "pavese" which protected them while loading the crossbow. The presence of balestieri companies on the battlefield was highly feared due to the efficiency of their weapons and their organization, and even often enough to lead an opponent to alter his battle plans. The balestrieri remained feared and respected military formations into the late 16th century even after the introduction of black powder weapons into Europe.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>【TAB】热那亚弩手是中世纪著名的军事编队，既保卫热那亚，又充当意大利和欧洲其他强国的雇佣军。在陆战和海战中，他们都装备了匕首、轻金属头盔、蛇怪和一个叫做“铺路石”的大盾牌，在装载弩时保护他们。由于武器和组织的效率，巴列斯蒂里公司在战场上的存在是非常令人担心的，甚至常常足以导致对手改变他的作战计划。巴列斯特里人直到16世纪末，甚至在欧洲引进黑火药武器之后，仍然对军事编队感到恐惧和尊敬。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ENGLISH_LONGBOWMAN</Tag>
    <English>English Longbowman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>英格兰长弓手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ENGLISH_LONGBOWMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Longbows were tall, powerful bows employed to penetrate all but the best of Medieval armour. Their use by English armies reached a peak during the Hundred Years War when the use of massed longbowmen was highly effective against the French at the battles of Crecy (1346), Poitiers (1356) and at Agincourt in 1415. The longbow combined long range and high accuracy but not both at the same time. Most longbow shooting involved launching volleys of arrows at enemy armies at long range from protected positions. The longbow was the machine gun of the Middle Ages, accurate, deadly and more rapid-firing than the crossbow or even early firearms though with the development of the latter the longbow gradually fell into disuse.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>长弓是一种高而有力的弓，用来穿透中世纪最好的盔甲。在百年战争中，英国军队使用长弓的次数达到了顶峰，当时在克里西（1346年）、普瓦捷（1356年）和阿金库尔（1415年）战役中，大量使用长弓对法国人非常有效。长弓结合了远距离和高精度，但不是同时。大多数长弓射击都是从受保护的阵地向敌军发射射箭。长弓是中世纪的机枪，比弩、甚至早期的火器射击准确、致命、快速，但随着后者的发展，长弓逐渐被废弃。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AUSTRIAN_KURASSIER</Tag>
    <English>Kurassier</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>奥地利胸甲骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AUSTRIAN_KURASSIER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Curassiers were mounted cavalry with armour and firearms which first appeared on the battlefields of late 15th century as the successors to the medieval armoured knights. The first curassiers wore three-quarter armour which covered the upper body and a close helm or "lobster-tail" pot helmet with the torso protected by breast and back plates, worn above long riding boots. Weapons included a pair of pistols in saddle holsters, a short sword or sabre and often a light mace or war hammer.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first curassiers were formed as a regiment of Austrian kurassiers (or "kyrissers") recruited from Croatia in 1484 to serve the future Holy Roman Emperor, Maximilian. Austrian Kurassiers also fought the Swedes and their allies at Lutzen in 1632, killing their king Gustavus Adolphus during the battle. The armour worn by the Kurassiers gradually decreased throughout the 18th century until the Napoleonic Wars so that the Kurassiers, like other curassiers, wore little more than helmets and breast plates. Kurassiers played a prominent role in the armies of Austria during the campaigns of Frederick the Great and remained the senior members of the mounted branch of the army, retaining their status as "big men on horses" throughout the 19th century and beyond.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>馆长是骑兵，装备有盔甲和火器，最初作为中世纪装甲骑士的继承者出现在15世纪晚期的战场上。第一任馆长身穿覆盖上身的四分之三盔甲，头戴一顶紧身头盔或“龙虾尾”壶形头盔，躯干由胸板和背板保护，穿在长靴上方。武器包括一对装在鞍形枪套中的手枪、一把短剑或军刀，通常还有一个轻锤或战锤。[第2段]第一批馆长是由1484年从克罗地亚招募来的奥地利库拉西耶（或“基里塞尔”）兵团组成的，他们是为未来的神圣罗马皇帝马克西米利安服务的。1632年，奥地利的库拉西人也在卢岑与瑞典人及其盟友作战，在战斗中杀死了他们的国王古斯塔夫斯・阿道夫。整个18世纪，库拉西耶人所穿的盔甲逐渐减少，直到拿破仑战争，所以库拉西耶人和其他馆长一样，只戴着头盔和胸甲。在腓特烈大帝的战役中，库拉西耶在奥地利军队中发挥了重要作用，仍然是军队骑兵支队的高级成员，在整个19世纪及以后都保持着“骑马大侠”的地位。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OTTOMAN_GREAT_BOMBARD</Tag>
    <English>Great Bombard</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>巨型臼炮</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OTTOMAN_GREAT_BOMBARD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Although gunpowder weapons were used in China in the early 10th century, the Arabs first acquired gunpwder about 1240AD and it is believed that the first cannon in history was used by the Mamluks against the Mongols in 1260. The Ottoman Empire became the first in Europe to put gunpowder into widespread use in both hand weaponry and seige cannons. The army of Mehmet I which conquered Constantinople in 1453 included foot soldiers armed with matchlock muskets and bombard artillery of various sizes. The barrage of Ottoman cannon fire, from 69 guns firing over 19,000 times, is said to have lasted for at least 40 days.[PARAGRAPH:2]Amongst these were a number of extremely large and powerful seige bombards. Bombards had been deployed by many European armies since the late 1300's but the Ottoman siege guns were especially massive and powerful "superguns", like the "Dardanelles Gun" or Great Turkish Bombard, weighing over 18 tons and firing huge stone or iron projectiles of over 2 feet in diameter. This famous gun along with many others, remained in use by the Ottomans until the early 19th century, even causing serious damage to British naval operations against the Ottomans in 1807.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[附]虽然中国在10世纪初使用火药武器，但阿拉伯人在公元1240年左右首先获得了火药，据信历史上第一门大炮是1260年马穆鲁克人用来对付蒙古人的。奥斯曼帝国成为欧洲第一个将火药广泛应用于手武器和围城大炮的国家。1453年征服君士坦丁堡的迈赫迈特一世军队包括手持火柴枪的步兵和各种规模的炮火。奥斯曼帝国的炮火从69门炮火中发射了19000多次，据说至少持续了40天。自13世纪末以来，许多欧洲军队都部署了轰炸，但奥斯曼帝国的攻城炮是特别巨大和强大的“超级大炮”，如“达达尼尔大炮”或土耳其大轰炸，重达18吨以上，发射直径超过2英尺的巨大石头或铁弹。这把著名的枪和其他许多枪一起，一直被奥斯曼人使用到19世纪初，甚至在1807年对奥斯曼人的英国海军行动造成严重损害。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SWEDISH_KAROLIN</Tag>
    <English>Karolin</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>卡洛林火枪手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SWEDISH_KAROLIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Karolins were soldiers of the Swedish kings Charles XI and Charles XII. They were part of the yearly Swedish allotment system. The Karolins' tactics were to attack fiercely and remain unafraid. The soldiers also sustained stern discipline, which over the extensive course of a twenty-year-long war would prove vital. The Swedish army tactics of the time did not teach retreat, so the soldiers were known to never withdraw from battle.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>卡罗琳一家是瑞典国王查理十一世和查理十二世的士兵。它们是瑞典年度分配制度的一部分。卡罗琳一家的战术是猛烈进攻，无所畏惧。士兵们还保持着严格的纪律，在长达20年的战争中，这是至关重要的。当时的瑞典军队战术并没有教退却，所以大家都知道士兵们从不退却。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NETHERLANDS_GRENADIER</Tag>
    <English>Gardist</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>精英掷弹兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NETHERLANDS_GRENADIER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A grenadier (from the word "grenade") was originally a specialized soldier who threw explosive grenades and sometimes took part in assault operations on the field of battle. From the 17th century grenadiers were chosen from the largest and strongest soldiers and often led the storming of breaches in seige warfare, a role later performed by sappers and pioneers. Grenades were small iron spheres, the size of a baseball or cricket ball, filled with gunpowder and fused by a slow match. The wide hats worn by grenadiers were gradually replaced by tall caps shaped like a bishop's mitre which permitted the grenadier greater ease in throwing the grenade overhand.[PARAGRAPH:2]Grenade usage declined in the late 18th century although the need for elite assault troops remained and grenadiers were retained for this purpose and specially selected for their strength, experience and steadiness under fire. All the major European armies continued to employ elite grenadier companies until the early 19th century. Their use was particularly marked in the battles of the Dutch Republic from 1648 to the 1790s as Dutch grenadiers wearing their distinctive guilded "bishop's mitres" saw action in numerous battles during the Anglo-Dutch wars. Grenadiers remained prominent on the battlefield until the invasion and occupation of the Netherlands by Revolutionary France in 1795.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]手榴弹兵（来源于“手榴弹”一词）最初是一名专门投掷爆炸性手榴弹的士兵，有时参加战场上的突击行动。从17世纪开始，掷弹兵从最大最强壮的士兵中挑选出来，经常在围城战中领导攻破缺口的攻势，这一角色后来由工兵和先驱者扮演。手榴弹是一个小铁球，有棒球或板球那么大，里面装满火药，通过一场缓慢的比赛熔化。手榴弹兵戴的宽大的帽子逐渐被主教帽形状的高帽所取代，这使得手榴弹兵更容易把手榴弹扔到头顶上。[第2段]手榴弹的使用在18世纪后期有所减少，尽管仍需要精锐的突击部队，而且手榴弹兵也为此而保留，特别是因为他们在烈火下的力量、经验和稳定性而被选中。直到19世纪初，欧洲所有主要军队都继续雇佣精锐的掷弹连。在1648年至1790年代的荷兰共和国战争中，他们的使用尤为明显，因为在英荷战争中，荷兰掷弹兵戴着他们独特的盾形“主教帽”在许多战斗中都有行动。在1795年法国革命军入侵和占领荷兰之前，掷弹兵在战场上一直很突出。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PORTUGAL_FOOT_KNIGHT</Tag>
    <English>Knight of Aviz</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>阿维什骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PORTUGAL_FOOT_KNIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Military Order of Aviz, originally the "Knights of St. Benedict of Aviz" was a Catholic military order formed during the early 14th century which gave their name and arms to the Aviz Dynasty which ruled Portugal between 1385 and 1580. The Kingdom of Portugal, founded in 1128, not only participated in the Crusades but conducted one of its own against the Moors of Iberia and North Africa with the help of existing military orders like the Templars. A native order of this kind was established in Portugal in 1146 and Afonso Henriques gave it the town of Evora captured from the Moors in 1166. After the conquest of Aviz a castle was erected there and the order became known as the Knights of St. Benedict of Aviz. Like the Knights of Calatrava in Castille, these Portugese Knights were indebted to the Cistercian abbots for their rule and their habit, a white mantle with a green fleur-de-lysed cross. Although nominally remaining as a branch of the Calatravan Order, they never ceased to have a Portugese Grand Master and be subject to the Kings of Portugal.[PARAGRAPH:2]The mission of the Knights of Aviz did not end with the overthrow of Muslim domination as Portugese expeditions across the sea opened new opportunities for them. The first landings of Europeans in Africa, the conquest of Ceuta by King Joao I in 1415 and the Portugese attacks on Tangier in 1437 were seen as crusades, in which the Knights of Aviz and the Knights of Christ (local successors to the disbanded Templars) played a leading part. By the 16th century however, their crusades in Africa had lost their religious zeal and their efforts were reduced to vulgar money-making enterprises. The Order of the Knights of Aviz became increasingly secular and commercial and after the institution of liberal government in the 19th century it evolved into the largely charitable foundation and symbolic order of merit it remains to this day.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]阿维兹的军事秩序，最初的“阿维兹圣本笃骑士”是一个天主教军事秩序，形成于14世纪初，把他们的名字和武器给了统治葡萄牙的阿维兹王朝在1385年至1580年。葡萄牙王国成立于1128年，它不仅参加了十字军东征，而且在圣殿骑士团等现有军事命令的帮助下，对伊比利亚和北非的摩尔人进行了自己的十字军东征。1146年，葡萄牙建立了这种本土秩序，阿丰索・亨利克斯（Afonso Henriques）于1166年将从摩尔人手中夺取的埃沃拉城（Evora）交给了它。征服阿维兹后，在那里建立了一座城堡，并被称为阿维兹圣本笃骑士团。像卡斯蒂利亚的卡拉特拉瓦骑士一样，这些葡萄牙骑士也感谢西多会修道院院长的统治和他们的习惯，一件白色的披风和一个绿色的十字架。尽管名义上仍然是卡拉特拉万教团的一个分支，但他们从未停止过拥有一位葡萄牙的大师，并受制于葡萄牙国王。[第2段]阿维兹骑士团的使命并没有随着推翻穆斯林统治而结束，因为葡萄牙远征海对岸为他们打开了新的机遇。欧洲人在非洲的首次登陆、1415年若昂一世国王对休达的征服以及1437年葡萄牙对丹吉尔的进攻都被视为十字军东征，其中阿维兹骑士和基督骑士（被解散的圣殿骑士的当地继承人）起了主导作用。然而到了16世纪，他们在非洲的十字军东征失去了他们的宗教热情，他们的努力沦为庸俗的赚钱企业。阿维兹骑士的秩序日益世俗化和商业化，在十九世纪的自由政府制度之后，它演变成了慈善事业的基础和象征性的功勋顺序。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KIEV_DRUZHINA</Tag>
    <English>Druzhina</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>俄罗斯公国卫队</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KIEV_DRUZHINA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The name is derived from the Slavic word drug with the meaning of "companion, friend". It is a cognate of the Germanic drottin meaning "war band".[PARAGRAPH:2]Druzhina was in the history of early East Slavs a detachment of select troops in personal service of a Knyaz (A Slavic title). It's main functions were bodyguarding, raising tribute from conquered territories and serving as the core of the army during war campaigns. Equipped as heavy cavalry wearing padded and mail armour and armed with lance and sword, the "Druzinniks" served freely and could leave one knyaz and join another. Druzyna varied in size, but usually numbered several hundred. They served as the nucleus of the army which was otherwise largely recruited as peasant levies. Druznya were paid by the knyaz and were able to share a portion of any military loot while on campaign.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]这个名字来源于斯拉夫语单词drug，意思是“同伴，朋友”。德鲁日纳是日耳曼drottin的同源词，意思是“战争乐队”。[第2段]德鲁日纳在早期东斯拉夫人的历史上是一支为克尼亚兹（斯拉夫人的头衔）个人服务的精选部队。它的主要职能是保镖，向被征服的领土进贡，在战争中充当军队的核心。德鲁津尼克骑兵装备有重型骑兵，身穿软垫甲和盔甲，手持长矛和长剑，可以自由服役，可以离开一个克尼亚兹，加入另一个克尼亚兹。德鲁兹纳大小不一，但通常有几百个。他们是军队的核心，而军队在其他方面主要被征募为农民税。德鲁兹尼娅由克尼亚兹人支付报酬，并能在作战期间分享任何军事战利品的一部分。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITHUANIA_BAJORAS</Tag>
    <English>Bajoras</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>贵族卫队</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITHUANIA_BAJORAS_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Prior to the creation of the Lithuanian state by Mindaugas, lesser members of the nobility were called bajorai (singular - bajoras). They evolved from tribal leaders, and were chiefly responsible for waging wars and organizing raids operations into enemy's territory. After the establishment of a unified state they gradually became subordinates to greater Dukes, and later to the King of Lithuania. After Mindaugas death all Lithuanian rulers held the title Grand Duke, or king. In the late 14th century Grand Dukes Jogaila and Skirgaila began forming professional forces. Instead of calling all men to war, a class of professional warriors - bajorai (future nobles) - was formed. In the early 15th century, Vytautas the Great reformed the army of the Grand Duchy of Lithuania further: as there were not enough warriors, Vytautas relieved soldiers from taxes and labour on the land by granting them veldamai, dependent peasants. At first the land was given to the serving men until death (benefice), but during the 14th and 15th centuries most of it became patrimony, granted by privileges of the monarch. Whilst during the 14th century the Grand Duke owned about 2/3 of the Duchy's land, by 1569 he was a direct owner of only 1/3.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 15th century, the noble social class was already formed in Lithuania; for quite a long time it remained open and anyone could be ennobled for services to the Grand Duke. In time, the influence of lesser nobles decreased and greater nobles acquired increasingly more power, especially during the interregnum fights following Vytautas' death.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>【TAB】在迈达戈斯建立立陶宛国之前，贵族中较次要的成员被称为巴乔拉（单数巴乔拉）。他们由部落首领演变而来，主要负责发动战争和组织突袭行动进入敌人的领土。统一国家建立后，他们逐渐成为大公爵的下属，后来又成为立陶宛国王的下属。明多加死后，立陶宛所有统治者都拥有大公或国王的头衔。14世纪晚期，大公爵乔盖拉和斯基尔吉拉开始形成专业力量。他们没有号召所有人参战，而是组建了一个职业战士阶层――巴乔莱（未来的贵族）。15世纪初，维塔塔塔斯大帝进一步改革了立陶宛大公国的军队：由于没有足够的战士，维塔塔塔斯授予士兵维达迈（veldamai）独立的农民，免除了士兵在土地上的税收和劳动。起初，这块土地是给服侍者的，直到他们去世（实益），但在14世纪和15世纪，大部分土地变成了遗产，由君主的特权授予。14世纪时，大公爵拥有公爵领地的2/3，而到1569年，他只直接拥有1/3的土地。[第2段]15世纪时，立陶宛已经形成了贵族社会阶层；很长一段时间以来，这一阶层一直开放，任何人都可以被尊为大公爵的服务。随着时间的推移，小贵族的影响力逐渐减弱，大贵族获得越来越多的权力，特别是在维塔塔斯死后的间隙战斗中。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VIKING_BERSERKER</Tag>
    <English>Berserker</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>狂暴战士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VIKING_BERSERKER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Berserks (or berserkers) were Viking warriors who worked themselves up into terribles rage before going into battle. The word berserker comes from the Norse words "bjorn" (meaning bear) or "bare" (meaning naked) and "serkr" (meaning shirt); a berserk was either someone who went into battle wearing the "shirt" of a bear (i.e. someone who was bear-like in rage and strength) or someone who went into battle naked. Berserks thought that by wearing the fur of a bear they would be possessed by the spirit of the animal and possibly even shift into its form. Berserks were also known to have sworn allegiance to the Norse sky god Odin, and they believed that he would protect them and give them superhuman strength. The Vikings also believed that if death came while fighting as a berserk, the deceased would travel straight to the warrior paradise of Valhalla. [PARAGRAPH:2]No one is exactly sure how berserks induced the crazed state of violence described by contemporaries. Some theories speculate that the wild behavior was prompted by the taking of various hallucinogenic drugs, or was caused by mild epilepsy, or even a genetic disorder that caused overly large skull growth. Perhaps the most likely explanation is that before going into battle the berserks simply worked themselves into frenzies by painting their faces, howling like animals, beating helmets and drums - and drinking large quantities of alcohol. [PARAGRAPH:2]All stories about berserks agree that they fought with crazed strength and were immune to pain until battle was ended. Berserks were often portrayed as villains, slaying anything that moved - including their own family members. In battle even the Berserks' allies usually chose to keep them at arm's length and were never comfortable in their presence. Scandinavian kings refused to employ them as bodyguards for fear that they would forget who to protect in the fighting. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1015, Berserks were outlawed in Norway, and Grgs, the medieval Icelandic law code, sentenced berserk warriors to exile. After the widespread adoption of Christianity across Scandinavia, in 1100 AD the organization of berserk warbands disappeared. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>狂暴者（或狂暴者）是维京人的战士，他们在投入战斗前把自己变成了一个狂暴的人。狂暴者一词来源于北欧语“bjorn”（意为熊）或“bare”（意为裸体）和“serkr”（意为衬衫）；狂暴者要么穿着熊的“衬衫”参战（即，像熊一样愤怒和强壮），要么就是裸体参战。狂暴者认为，穿上熊的皮毛，他们就会被动物的灵魂附身，甚至有可能转变成它的形态。狂暴者也被认为宣誓效忠挪威天空之神奥丁，他们相信他会保护他们，给他们超人的力量。维京人还相信，如果死亡是作为一个狂暴的战斗来的，死者将直接前往战士天堂瓦尔哈拉。[第2段]没有人确切地知道狂暴者是如何引起同时代人所描述的疯狂暴力状态的。一些理论推测，这种野生行为是由服用各种致幻剂引起的，或者是由轻度癫痫引起的，甚至是一种导致头骨生长过大的遗传病。也许最有可能的解释是，在投入战斗之前，狂暴者只是通过画他们的脸，像动物一样嚎叫，敲打头盔和鼓，喝大量的酒精，使自己陷入疯狂。[第2段]所有关于狂暴者的故事都认为，他们以疯狂的力量战斗，并且在战斗结束前对疼痛免疫。狂暴者经常被描绘成恶棍，杀死任何移动的东西――包括他们自己的家人。在战斗中，即使是狂战士的盟友也常常选择与他们保持距离，在他们面前也不会感到舒服。斯堪的纳维亚国王拒绝雇用他们作为保镖，因为他们害怕忘记在战斗中保护谁。[第2段]1015年，挪威宣布狂暴者为非法，中世纪冰岛法典Grgs，判处狂暴战士流放。公元1100年，基督教在斯堪的纳维亚广泛传播后，狂暴的战争组织消失了。[第2段]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DENMARK_HUSKARL</Tag>
    <English>Huskarl</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>近卫军</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DENMARK_HUSKARL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Housecarls were household troops, personal warriors and equivalent to a royal bodyguard to Scandinavian kings. The anglicized term comes from the Old Norse term huskarl or huscarl (literally, 'house man', i.e., armed man in the service of a specific house.) They were also called hirth ('household') that referred to household troops. The term later came to cover armed soldiers of the household. They were often the only professional soldiers in the kingdom, the rest of the army being made up of militia, peasant levy, and occasionally mercenaries. They were usually armed with long Danish axe. A kingdom would have fewer than 2000 Housecarls.[PARAGRAPH:2]The term entered the English language when Canute the Great conquered and occupied Anglo-Saxon England.[PARAGRAPH:2]In England, there may have been as many as 3000 royal housecarls, and a special tax was levied to provide pay in coin. They were housed and fed at the king's expense. They formed a standing army of professional soldiers, and also had some administrative duties in peacetime as the Kings representatives. The term was often used in contrast to the non-professional fyrd.[PARAGRAPH:2]Certainly the vast majority of English housecarls died at the Battle of Hastings. Survivors, along with King Harold's thegns, crossed to Continental Europe as mercenary troops. Some of these reached Byzantium and along with other Saxons joined the Varangian Guard. By the 12th century, the Varangian Guard contained so many Saxons that the entire unit was sometimes called "the English Guard."</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]豪斯卡尔是家庭军队、个人战士，相当于斯堪的纳维亚国王的皇家保镖。英国化的术语来源于古挪威语中的huscarl或huscarl（字面意思是“宅男”，即为特定房屋服务的武装人员）。他们也被称为hirth（“家庭”），指的是家庭军队。这个词后来被用来指家庭中的武装士兵。他们往往是王国里唯一的专业士兵，其余的军队由民兵、农民和偶尔雇佣兵组成。他们通常手持丹麦长斧。一个王国只有不到2000辆房车。[第2段]这个词是在伟大的克努特征服并占领盎格鲁撒克逊英格兰时进入英语的。[第2段]在英国，可能有多达3000辆皇家房车，并且征收特别税以提供硬币支付。他们由国王出资安置和喂养。他们组成了一支由职业军人组成的常备军，平时作为国王的代表也有一定的行政职责。这个词经常被用来与非专业的fyrd形成对比。[第2段]当然，绝大多数英国豪斯卡尔人死于黑斯廷斯战役。幸存者，连同哈罗德国王的军队，以雇佣兵的身份穿越欧洲大陆。其中一些到达拜占庭，与其他撒克逊人一起加入了瓦兰吉安卫队。到了12世纪，瓦兰吉安卫队包含了太多撒克逊人，以至于整个部队有时被称为“英国卫队”</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARAGON_ALMOGAVAR</Tag>
    <English>Almogavar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>重装民兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARAGON_ALMOGAVAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Almogavars were a class of soldiers from the Crown of Aragon, well-known during the Christian Reconquista (reconquest) of the Iberian Peninsula. They were much employed as mercenaries in Italy, Latin Greece and the Levant during the 13th and 14th centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Almogavars came mainly from the mountain regions of Aragon, Catalonia and, to a lesser extent, from Navarre. They were frontiersmen and foot-soldiers who wore no armour, dressed in skins, were shod with brogues (abarcas), and carried the arms similar to those of Roman legionaries: two heavy javelins, or azconas in Spanish language, and a short stabbing sword.[PARAGRAPH:2]They were professional soldiers, and served kings, the Roman Catholic Church, nobles, or towns for pay; eventually they also hired themselves out to the Byzantine Empire. When Peter III of Aragon made war on Charles of Anjou after the Sicilian Vespers of March 30, 1282 for the possession of Naples and Sicily, the Almogavars formed the most effective element of his army. Their discipline and ferocity, the force with which they hurled their javelins, and their activity, made them very formidable to the heavy cavalry of the Angevin armies. They fought against cavalry by attacking firstly horses instead of knights. Once the knight was on the ground he was an easy victim for the Almogavar.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the Peace of Caltabellotta in 1302 ended the war in southern Italy, the Almogavars, under the leadership of Roger de Flor ("Roger Blum", a former Knight Templar), formed the Catalan Company in the service of the emperor of the East, Andronicus II Palaeologus, to fight against the Turks. Both kings of Aragon and Sicily agreed with the idea since peace had been reached and it was viable alternative to having the Almogavar standing army unemployed in their realms.[PARAGRAPH:2]Their campaign in Asia Minor during 1303 and 1304 was a series of military victories, but alongside widespread looting of Byzantine civilians, so when they insisted in receiving the agreed payment, the Emperor refused. Thereafter the Almogavars turned to violence, making their presence intolerable to the Byzantine population. Roger de Flor and his lieutenants were assassinated by orders of the Emperor in 1305 while meeting to discuss terms on their compensation, presumably on the instigation of Genoese merchants, who were conspiring to keep their own position of influence and power and keep the Catalans out of the loop. This betrayal resulted in the Almogavars ravaging the neighbourhood of Constantinople.[PARAGRAPH:2]Subsequently they marched against the Duchy of Athens, under the rule of the French House of Brienne. Duke Walter V of Brienne was defeated and slain by the Almogavars with all his knights at the Battle of the Cephissus, or Orchomenus, in Boeotia in March 1310. They then divided the wives and possessions of the Frenchmen by lot, and summoned a prince of the house of Aragon to rule over them.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>阿尔摩加瓦人是来自阿拉贡皇冠的一类士兵，在基督教重新征服伊比利亚半岛期间很有名。13世纪和14世纪，他们在意大利、拉丁希腊和黎凡特被雇佣为雇佣兵。[第2段]阿尔莫加瓦尔人主要来自阿拉贡、加泰罗尼亚的山区，在较小程度上来自纳瓦拉。他们是拓荒者和步兵，没有穿盔甲，穿着皮衣，穿着长袍（abarcas），手臂与罗马军团相似：两支重标枪，或西班牙语的azconas，一把短刺剑，贵族或城镇；最终他们也受雇于拜占庭帝国。公元1282年3月30日，西西里晚祷之后，阿拉贡的彼得三世为了夺取那不勒斯和西西里，向安茹的查尔斯开战，阿尔莫加瓦尔一家成为了他军队中最有效的一支。他们的纪律和凶猛，他们投掷标枪的力量和他们的活动，使他们对安格文军队的重骑兵非常可怕。他们先攻击马匹而不是骑士来对抗骑兵。当骑士在地面上时，他很容易成为阿尔莫加瓦尔人的牺牲品。[第2段]1302年卡尔塔贝洛塔的和平结束了意大利南部的战争，阿尔莫加瓦尔人在罗杰・德弗洛尔（Roger de Flor，前圣殿骑士罗杰・布鲁姆）的领导下，成立了加泰罗尼亚连队，为东边的皇帝服务，安德洛尼卡二世帕里奥洛格斯，与土耳其人作战。阿拉贡国王和西西里国王都同意这一想法，因为和平已经达成，除了让阿尔莫加瓦尔常备军在他们的领地失业之外，这是一个可行的选择。[第2段]他们在1303年和1304年在小亚细亚的战役是一系列的军事胜利，但同时也对拜占庭平民进行了广泛的掠夺，因此，当他们坚持要接受约定的付款时，皇帝拒绝了。此后，阿尔摩加瓦人转向暴力，使他们的存在无法容忍拜占庭人民。罗杰・德弗洛尔和他的副手在1305年被皇帝的命令刺杀，当时他们正在开会讨论赔偿条款，大概是在热那亚商人的煽动下，他们密谋保持自己的影响力和权力地位，并将加泰罗尼亚人排除在外。这一背叛导致阿尔莫加瓦人蹂躏君士坦丁堡附近地区。[第2段]随后，他们在法国布里恩宫的统治下，游行反对雅典公爵领地。1310年3月，在波奥蒂亚的西斐苏战役中，布里恩公爵沃尔特五世和他的所有骑士被阿尔摩加瓦人打败并杀害。他们就拈阄分给法国人的妻子和财物，召了一个亚拉贡家的首领来管理他们。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOROCCO_BLACK_GUARD</Tag>
    <English>Black Guard</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>黑近卫</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOROCCO_BLACK_GUARD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Black Guard were the corps of African slave-soldiers assembled by sultan Moulay Ismail of Morocco. The Black Guard descended from black captives brought to Morocco from sub-Saharan Africa, who were settled in a special colony and given wives; their male offspring would be pressed into military careers at the age of sixteen. Considered more reliable than Arab or Berber warriors because of their lack of tribal loyalties, Ismail's black soldiers formed the bulk of his standing army and numbered 150,000 at their peak.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Black Guard were charged with fighting Ismail's campaigns against the European-controlled fortress enclaves dotting his empire's coast and with patrolling Morocco's unstable countryside: They crushed rebellions against Ismail's rule not only by Moroccan Berber clans but also by Ismail's seditious sons, who defected from service as his provincial governors to insurrection as would-be usurpers of his throne.[PARAGRAPH:2]Moulay Ismail always went about his court surrounded by a bodyguard of eighty black slave-soldiers, with muskets and scimitars at the ready in case of any attempt on the sultan's life. At his throne, Ismail was attended by a slave charged with twirling a parasol above the sultan at all times (a legend says that on at least one occasion, Ismail pulled out his sword and murdered an attendant who had allowed the sun to briefly fall upon his skin). Two more slaves fanned the flies away from his face, while a third held a napkin beneath his chin to collect his spittle. Though the Black Guard were fiercely loyal, they remained just as vulnerable to their commander's fits of rage as his European slaves and Moorish subjects.[PARAGRAPH:2]Despite endless civil wars and civil slaughter, the Black Guard remained brutally loyal and disciplined through the turmoil of Ismail's reign. More than any other factor did they enable the sultan to remain on Morocco's throne for half a century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]黑卫兵是摩洛哥苏丹穆莱・伊斯梅尔组建的非洲奴隶士兵军团。黑卫兵是从撒哈拉以南非洲被带到摩洛哥的黑人俘虏的后代，他们定居在一个特殊的殖民地，并有妻子；他们的男性后代在16岁时将被迫从事军事生涯。由于缺乏部落的忠诚，伊斯梅尔的黑人士兵被认为比阿拉伯或柏柏尔的战士更可靠，他们组成了他的常备军的大部分，在他们的鼎盛时期有15万人。[第2段]黑人卫队被指控打击伊斯梅尔对遍布其帝国海岸的欧洲控制的要塞飞地的战役在摩洛哥不稳定的乡村巡逻：他们镇压了反抗伊斯梅尔统治的叛乱，不仅有摩洛哥柏柏尔家族，还有伊斯梅尔的煽动性儿子，他从省长的职位上叛变为暴动的篡位者。[第2段]穆莱・伊斯梅尔总是在他的宫廷里到处走动，身边有80名黑奴士兵的保镖，随时准备着步枪和弯刀，以防苏丹的生命受到任何企图。在伊斯梅尔的王位上，有一个奴隶一直被指控在苏丹上空旋转阳伞（传说至少有一次，伊斯梅尔拔出剑，杀死了一个让太阳短暂落在他皮肤上的侍从）。又有两个奴隶用扇子把苍蝇从他脸上赶走，而第三个奴隶则用餐巾纸夹在下巴下面收集他的唾沫。尽管黑人卫队忠心耿耿，但他们仍然像他的欧洲奴隶和摩尔臣民一样容易受到指挥官暴怒的伤害。[第2段]尽管内战和内战无休止，但黑人卫队在伊斯梅尔统治的混乱中仍然保持着残忍的忠诚和纪律。它们比任何其他因素都能使苏丹在摩洛哥的王位上保持半个世纪。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SCOTLAND_SHELTRON</Tag>
    <English>Sheltron</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>高地贵族方阵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SCOTLAND_SHELTRON_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A sheltron (also sceld-trome, schiltrom or shiltron) is a compact body of troops forming a battle array, shield wall or phalanx. The term is most often associated with Scottish pike formations during the Wars of Scottish Independence in the late 13th and early 14th centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]The term dates from at least 1000 AD and derives from Old English roots expressing the idea of a "shield-troop". Some researchers have also posited this etymological relation may show the schiltron is directly descended from the Anglo-Saxon shield wall, and still others give evidence "schiltron" is a name derived from a Viking circular formation (generally no less than a thousand fighters) in extremely close formation, intended to present an enemy's cavalry charge with an "infinite" obstacle (that is, a perimeter horses refuse to breach). Matters are confused by the fact that the term in Middle English could clearly refer to a body of soldiers without reference to formation, including cavalry and archers. The first mention of the schiltron as a specific formation of spearmen appears to be at the Battle of Falkirk in 1297. There is, however, no reason to believe this is the first time such a formation was used and, indeed, may have had a long previous history in Scotland, as the Picts used to employ spears in block formation as the backbone of their armies.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]谢尔特龙（也叫“谢尔特龙”、“席尔特龙”或“席尔特龙”）是一个紧凑的部队，组成一个战斗阵列、盾牌墙或方阵。在13世纪末和14世纪初苏格兰独立战争期间，这个词最常与苏格兰长矛编队联系在一起。[第2段]这个词至少起源于公元1000年，源于表达“盾牌部队”概念的古英语词根。一些研究人员还假设这种词源关系可能表明，迅龙是盎格鲁撒克逊盾墙的直接后裔，还有一些人提供证据，“迅龙”是一个名字，来源于一个非常接近的维京人圆形编队（通常不少于一千名战士），旨在呈现敌人的骑兵用一个“无限”的障碍物冲锋（也就是说，周围的马拒绝冲破）。令人困惑的是，中英文中的这个词可以清楚地指代一个士兵的身体，而不涉及编队，包括骑兵和弓箭手。第一次提到斯希尔特伦作为一个特殊的矛兵编队似乎是在1297年的福克战役。然而，没有理由相信这是第一次使用这样的编队，事实上，在苏格兰可能有很长的历史，因为皮克特人曾经使用长矛作为他们军队的骨干部队。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRUSSIA_DEATHS_HEAD_HUSSAR</Tag>
    <English>Totenkopfhusar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>黑骷髅轻骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRUSSIA_DEATHS_HEAD_HUSSAR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Use of the symbol as a military insignia began with the cavalry of the Prussian army under Frederick the Great. Frederick formed Husaren-Regiment Nr. 5 (von Ruesch), a Hussar regiment commanded by Colonel von Ruesch. These Hussars adopted a black uniform with a Totenkopf emblazoned on the front of their mirlitons and wore it on the field in the War of Austrian Succession and in the Seven Years' War.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1808, when the regiment was reformed into Leib-Husaren Regiments Nr.1 and Nr.2, the Totenkopf remained a part of the uniform. During the Napoleonic Wars, when Frederick William, Duke of Brunswick-Wolfenbttel, was killed in battle, his troops changed the colour of their uniforms to black or apple green, with a Totenkopf on their shakos in mourning their dead leader. Other sources claim that the "Black Brunswickers" were so equipped while Friedrich Wilhelm of Brunswick lived, as a sign of revenge on the French.[PARAGRAPH:2]The skull continued to be used throughout the Prussian and Brunswick Armed forces until 1918, and some of the stormtroopers that led the last German offensives on the Western Front in 1918 used skull badges.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>使用这个符号作为军事徽章始于腓特烈大帝统治下的普鲁士军队的骑兵。弗雷德里克组建了第5胡萨林团（冯鲁切），这是一个由冯鲁切上校指挥的轻骑兵团。在奥地利继承战争和七年战争中，这些骠骑兵采用了一种黑色制服，并在战场上穿着这种制服。[第2段]1808年，当该团改为莱布・胡萨雷团1号和2号时，托登科夫仍然是制服的一部分。拿破仑战争期间，不伦瑞克・沃尔芬贝尔公爵弗雷德里克・威廉（Frederick William）在战斗中阵亡，他的军队把制服的颜色改成了黑色或苹果绿，在他们的棚屋上放了一个图腾科夫（Totenkopf）以悼念死去的领袖。其他消息称，布伦瑞克的弗里德里希・威廉（Friedrich Wilhelm）在世时，“黑色布伦瑞克”装备精良，是对法国人复仇的标志。[第2段]直到1918年，普鲁士和布伦瑞克武装部队一直在使用这个头骨，1918年，一些领导德国最后一次进攻西线的冲锋队使用了骷髅徽章。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NOVGOROD_USHKUINIK</Tag>
    <English>Ushkuinik</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>维京劫掠者</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NOVGOROD_USHKUINIK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The ushkuiniks were medieval Novgorodian pirates who led the Viking-like life of fighting, killing, and robbery. Their name derives from "ushkui", a type of flat-bottom medieval Finnic ship uisk (literally a 'snake'), which could be easily transported over portages between the rivers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although the Novgorodians took part in the Tsargrad expeditions of the 10th century and mounted pillaging raids to Finland in the 12th century, the ushkuiniks first appear as an organized force in the 1320s. Arranged in squadrons which could number several thousand, the ushkuiniks enjoyed the patronage of influential boyar families of Novgorod, who used them to demonstrate Novgorod's military clout to its neighbours and to advance its trade interests in the Volga region.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the famous campaign of 1360, the ushkuiniks sailed from Novgorod by the portages to the Volga river. Under command of boyar Anfal Nikitin, they gained possession of Zhukotin, a trade emporium in Volga Bulgaria. A ruler of the Golden Horde, which controlled Zhukotin, was furious and ordered Grand Prince Dmitry Konstantinovich to capture the ushkuiniks and to bring them to the Horde for trial, but Dmitry's punitive expedition failed.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1363 the pirates launched the first Novgorodian raid along the Ob River in western Siberia. Three years later, without consulting their superiors in Novgorod, they approached Nizhny Novgorod and, wishing to punish Dmitry for his hostile action, massacred Armenian and Tatar merchants trading there. This led to a diplomatic row, when Dmitry demanded apologies from Novgorod Republic.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1371, the ushkuiniks sacked Yaroslavl, Kostroma and other Upper Volga cities. Three years later, they sailed with upwards of ninety ships to pillage the Vyatka region. In 1375, they defeated the militia of Kostroma and burnt the city to the ground. The destruction was so severe that Kostroma had to be rebuilt elsewhere. After that, they looted Nizhny Novgorod and sailed down the Volga to Astrakhan, where they were annihilated by a Tatar general.[PARAGRAPH:2]By 1391, the ushkuiniks had recovered from this reverse and felt strong enough to resume their activities. At that period their patrons included Narimantas and Patrikas, the overlords of the Korela district that later became known as Ingria. In 1391 the pirates sacked both Zhukotin and Kazan. With Muscovy's power on the ascendant, however, Novgorod Republic was pressed into putting down their filibustering activities in the first decades of the 15th century.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>

    <Chinese>乌斯库伊人是中世纪的诺夫哥罗德海盗，他们过着海盗般的战斗、杀戮和抢劫的生活。他们的名字来源于“ushkui”，一种平底的中世纪芬兰船只uisk（字面意思是“蛇”），它可以很容易地通过河流之间的港口运输。[第2段]尽管诺夫哥罗德人参加了10世纪的沙格勒远征，并在12世纪对芬兰发动了掠夺性袭击，但Ushkuini人首先在13世纪20年代，乌什库因人作为一支有组织的部队出现在诺夫哥罗德。乌什库因人被安排在数千人的中队中，享受着诺夫哥罗德有影响力的博雅家族的庇护，在1360年著名的战役中，乌什库因人从诺夫哥罗德出发，通过港口前往伏尔加河。在博亚尔・安法尔・尼基廷的指挥下，他们获得了保加利亚伏尔加的一个商业商场朱科廷的所有权。一个控制着朱科廷的黄金部落的统治者非常愤怒，命令大王子德米特里・康斯坦丁诺维奇（Dmitry Konstantinovich）抓捕乌什库尼人并将他们带到部落接受审判，但德米特里的惩罚性探险失败了。[第2段]1363年，海盗沿着西伯利亚西部的奥布河发动了第一次诺夫哥罗德人的突袭。三年后，在没有咨询他们在诺夫哥罗德的上级的情况下，他们找到了下诺夫哥罗德，希望惩罚德米特里的敌对行动，屠杀了在那里交易的亚美尼亚和鞑靼商人。这导致了一场外交争端，1371年，德米特里要求诺夫哥罗德共和国道歉。三年后，他们带着90多艘船只去掠夺维亚特卡地区。1375年，他们打败了科斯特罗马的民兵，并将该城夷为平地。破坏如此严重，科斯特罗马不得不在别处重建。在那之后，他们抢劫了下诺夫哥罗德，沿着伏尔加河航行到阿斯特拉罕，在那里他们被鞑靼将军歼灭。[第2段]到1391年，乌斯库伊人已经从这一倒转中恢复过来，感到足够强大，可以恢复他们的活动。在那个时期，他们的赞助人包括纳里曼塔斯和帕特里卡斯，科雷拉地区的霸主，后来被称为英格利亚。1391年，海盗洗劫了朱克丁和喀山。然而，随着莫斯科政权的崛起，诺夫哥罗德共和国被迫在15世纪的头几十年停止了他们的阻挠活动。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Unique Units -->
  <!-- Company Units -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KNIGHT_OF_ST_JOHNS</Tag>
    <English>Knight of St. John's</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>圣约翰骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TEMPLAR_KNIGHT</Tag>
    <English>Templar Knight</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>圣殿骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TEUTONIC_KNIGHT</Tag>
    <English>Teutonic Knight</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>条顿骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_KNIGHT</Tag>
    <English>Knight of the Dragon</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>龙骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CALATRAVA_KNIGHT</Tag>
    <English>Calatrava Knight</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>卡拉特拉瓦骑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Company Units -->
  <!-- Barbarian Units -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MONGOL_KESHIK</Tag>
    <English>Keshik</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>怯薛</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MONGOL_KESHIK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The equestrian skill of a Mongol was notoriously keen. Having been taught to ride on horseback from the age of three, and by five given bow and arrows to use from horseback for hunting and war, it was a natural way for the Mongols to conduct war. The Mongol's harsh, nomadic lifestyle prepared them well for the rigors of war; they often thrived in conditions that would be considered intolerable by any other troops of its time. When the need arose, Mongol horsemen could go up to ten days at a time without cooking food, during which they would sustain themselves by drinking the blood and milk of their horses.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>一个蒙古人的马术是出了名的敏锐。蒙古人从三岁起就学会骑马，五岁时就学会了用马背上的弓箭打猎和打仗，这是蒙古人打仗的自然方式。蒙古人严酷的游牧生活使他们做好了应付战争的准备；他们经常在当时任何其他军队都认为无法忍受的条件下茁壮成长。当需要的时候，蒙古骑兵可以一次上十天不做饭，在这期间，他们可以通过喝马的血和奶来维持自己的生活。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_LANCER</Tag>
    <English>Seljuk Lancer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>塞尔柱枪骑兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_CROSSBOWMAN</Tag>
    <English>Seljuk Crossbowman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>塞尔柱弩手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_SWORDSMAN</Tag>
    <English>Seljuk Swordsman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>塞尔柱剑士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_HEAVY_FOOTMAN</Tag>
    <English>Seljuk Heavy Footman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>塞尔柱重步兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_GUISARME</Tag>
    <English>Seljuk Heavy Spearman</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>塞尔柱重枪兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SELJUK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Seljuk Turks were a Turco-Persian tribe with its origins in the Turcoman clans of Central Asia who migrated into Persia in the 10th century, adopting Sunni Islam and Persian culture and language and are considered to be the cultural ancestors of today's modern Turks of Central Asia and Anatolia. By the mid 11th century they built up a vast nomadic empire including most of Western Asia and Persia and the Caucasus. During the 1060's, The Seljuk hordes, along with their Turkic and Kurdish allies, invaded Armenia, Georgia and Asia Minor, conquering the Armenian capitol in 1064 and Caesarea in 1067.[PARAGRAPH:2]Their victory at Manzikert in 1071 was a decisive defeat for the Byzantine Empire and soon all of Syria and Anatolia came under Seljuk control. Seljuk petty kingdoms were set up throughout the region, notably the Sultanate of Rum in eastern Anatolia which remained in existence until the 14th century. Their fractured states, however, were more concerned with consolidating their territories and conquering their neighbours than cooperating against the First Crusade. Although they easily defeated the untrained "Peoples Crusade" in 1096 they could not prevent the main Crusader army from seizing important cities like Nicaea, Iconium and Antioch, capturing the Holy Land in 1099 and setting up the first of the Crusader kingdoms.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]塞尔柱土耳其人是一个土耳其人波斯部落，起源于中亚土耳其人部落，他们于10世纪移居波斯，采用逊尼派伊斯兰教和波斯文化和语言，被认为是当今中亚和安纳托利亚现代土耳其人的文化祖先。到11世纪中叶，他们建立了一个庞大的游牧帝国，包括西亚大部分地区、波斯和高加索地区。在1060年代，塞尔柱部落连同他们的突厥和库尔德盟友入侵亚美尼亚、格鲁吉亚和小亚细亚，在1064年征服了亚美尼亚国会大厦，在1067年征服了凯撒利亚。[第2段]1071年他们在曼齐克特的胜利是拜占庭帝国的决定性失败，很快整个叙利亚和安纳托利亚都被塞尔柱控制。塞尔柱王国建立在整个地区，尤其是在安纳托利亚东部的朗姆酒苏丹国，一直存在到14世纪。然而，他们分裂的国家更关心的是巩固他们的领土和征服他们的邻国，而不是合作反对第一次十字军东征。尽管他们在1096年轻易击败了未经训练的“人民十字军”，但他们无法阻止主要十字军占领尼西亚、伊科纽姆和安提俄克等重要城市，在1099年占领圣地，建立了十字军的第一个王国。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TURCOMAN_HORSE_ARCHER</Tag>
    <English>Turcoman Horse Archer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>土库曼骑射手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TURCOMAN_HORSE_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Horse archers may be either light, such as Scythian, Hun, Parthian, Cuman or Pecheneg horsemen, or heavy, such as Byzantine kavallarioi, Turkish timariots, Russian druzhina and Japanese samurai. Heavy horse archers typically fought as disciplined units. Instead of harassing without ever making contact, they shot in volleys, weakening the enemy before they charged. In addition to bows, they often also carried close combat weapons, such as lances or spears. Some nations, like medieval Mongols, Hungarians and Cumans fielded both light and heavy mounted archers. In some armies, such as those of the Parthians, Palmyrans, and the Teutonic Order of Knights, the mounted troops consisted of both super-heavy troops (cataphracts, knights) without bows, and light mounted archers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]射马者可以是轻骑兵，如斯基台骑兵、匈奴骑兵、帕提亚骑兵、卡曼骑兵或佩切涅格骑兵，也可以是重骑兵，如拜占庭骑兵、土耳其提摩略骑兵、俄罗斯德鲁日纳骑兵和日本武士。重骑兵通常作为纪律部队作战。他们没有在没有接触的情况下进行骚扰，而是截击，在冲锋前削弱敌人。除了弓，他们还经常携带近战武器，如长矛或长矛。一些国家，如中世纪的蒙古人、匈牙利人和库曼人都有轻型和重型弓箭手。在一些军队中，如帕提亚人、帕尔米拉人和日耳曼骑士团，骑兵既包括没有弓的超重型部队（卡塔夫雷茨，骑士），也包括轻型弓箭手。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STEPPE_HORSE_ARCHER</Tag>
    <English>Steppe Horse Archer</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>草原骑射手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STEPPE_HORSE_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Horse archers may be either light, such as Scythian, Hun, Parthian, Cuman or Pecheneg horsemen, or heavy, such as Byzantine kavallarioi, Turkish timariots, Russian druzhina and Japanese samurai. Heavy horse archers typically fought as disciplined units. Instead of harassing without ever making contact, they shot in volleys, weakening the enemy before they charged. In addition to bows, they often also carried close combat weapons, such as lances or spears. Some nations, like medieval Mongols, Hungarians and Cumans fielded both light and heavy mounted archers. In some armies, such as those of the Parthians, Palmyrans, and the Teutonic Order of Knights, the mounted troops consisted of both super-heavy troops (cataphracts, knights) without bows, and light mounted archers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]射马者可以是轻骑兵，如斯基台骑兵、匈奴骑兵、帕提亚骑兵、卡曼骑兵或佩切涅格骑兵，也可以是重骑兵，如拜占庭骑兵、土耳其提摩略骑兵、俄罗斯德鲁日纳骑兵和日本武士。重骑兵通常作为纪律部队作战。他们没有在没有接触的情况下进行骚扰，而是截击，在冲锋前削弱敌人。除了弓，他们还经常携带近战武器，如长矛或长矛。一些国家，如中世纪的蒙古人、匈牙利人和库曼人都有轻型和重型弓箭手。在一些军队中，如帕提亚人、帕尔米拉人和日耳曼骑士团，骑兵既包括没有弓的超重型部队（卡塔夫雷茨，骑士），也包括轻型弓箭手。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BEDOUIN</Tag>
    <English>Bedouin</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>骆驼骑射手</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BEDOUIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Historically, the Bedouin engaged in nomadic herding, agriculture and sometimes fishing. A major source of income was the taxation of caravans, and tributes collected from non-Bedouin settlements. They also earned income by transporting goods and people in caravans across the desert. Scarcity of water and of permanent pastoral land required them to move constantly.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Moroccan traveller, Ibn Battuta, reported that in 1326 on the route to Gaza, the Egyptian authorities had a customs post at Qatya on the north coast of Sinai. Here bedouin were being used to guard the road and track down those trying to cross the border without permission.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Early Medieval grammarians and scholars seeking to develop a system of standardizing the contemporary Classical Arabic for maximal intelligibility across the Arabophone areas, believed that the Bedouin spoke the purest, most conservative variety of the language. To solve irregularities of pronunciation, the Bedouin were asked to recite certain poems, whereafter consensus was relied on to decide the pronunciation and spelling of a given word.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>历史上，贝多因人从事游牧、农业，有时还从事渔业。收入的一个主要来源是对大篷车征税，以及从非贝多因人定居点征收的贡品。他们还通过在沙漠中用大篷车运送货物和人员赚取收入。由于缺水和永久性的牧场，他们必须不断迁移。[第2段]摩洛哥旅行者伊本・巴图塔（Ibn Battuta）报告说，在1326年前往加沙的途中，埃及当局在西奈北部海岸的Qatya设立了一个海关哨所。贝多因人在这里被用来守卫道路，追踪那些未经允许试图越境的人。[第2段]中世纪早期的语法学家和学者试图开发一个标准化当代古典阿拉伯语的系统，以便在阿拉伯文地区实现最大的可懂度，相信贝多因人说的是最纯正、最保守的语言。为了解决发音不规则的问题，贝多因人被要求背诵某些诗歌，然后根据一致意见来决定给定单词的发音和拼写。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Barbarian Units -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BARBONLY_HELP</Tag>
    <English>Barbarian only</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>野蛮人</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OTTOMAN_JANISSARY</Tag>
    <English>Janissary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>苏丹亲兵</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OTTOMAN_JANISSARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Janissaries were an elite fighting force of infantry raised by the Ottoman sultans. They formed the sultan's household troops and bodyguard, eventually rising to a position of enormous influence before being disbanded in the nineteenth century. Murad I founded the Janissary corps around 1330; the troops were made up of non-Muslim boys who were captured in battle or bought as slaves and brought up as warriors. This was very similar to the Mameluk slave soldiers of Egypt, who may have been the inspiration for the Janissaries. Janissaries became the first infantry units in the Ottoman military forces, because at the time no free man would consent to fighting on foot. [PARAGRAPH:2]After 1380 the system for recruiting new soldiers into the Janissaries became standardized through a process called the "devshirmeh:" this was basically a "human tax" where each community had to contribute a certain number of young boys to the state. In practice these were almost always Christian slaves. [PARAGRAPH:2]The boys were sequestered in special barracks, where they would be converted to Islam and trained to become elite soldiers (a process very similar to that practiced by the Spartans of ancient Greece). Although slaves, the Janissaries received special privileges, including the right to bear weapons and higher pay than other soldiers. Although the Janissaries began their existence as a small bodyguard for the sultan, in time they came to comprise much of the Ottoman army, topping out at over 200,000 men at some points. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Janissaries originally were trained to be expert archers, but once firearms were invented they quickly adopted the new weapons, becoming fiercely proficient with muskets. They usually used axes or sabres for melee combat. Janissaries were present at all of the major battles in the early history of the Ottoman Empire, including the Siege of Constantinople in 1453. [PARAGRAPH:2]The very success of the Janissaries would eventually destroy them. Realizing their importance, they began demanding higher pay, threatening rebellion if their demands were refused. Their first rebellion took place in 1449, and it was followed by many more. By the eighteenth century, the Janissaries dominated the government. Through frequent palace coups they changed sultans as they wished, and they blocked much-needed modernization reforms in the Ottoman army. Many of the Janissaries became corrupted, no longer training for battle but instead pursuing commercial ventures or political office, and the weakness of the Ottomans in the face of Russian and Austrian expansion soon became obvious to all. Desperate to regain control of their country, the Ottoman rulers made determined efforts to eradicate them. [PARAGRAPH:2]Finally, in 1826 Mahmud II was able to form a non-Janissary army strong enough to challenge the Janissaries. The Janissaries did not go down peacefully, and Mahmud II had to use artillery to shell the Janissaries' barracks and batter them into submission. This event - known as the "Auspicious Incident," ended the Janissaries. Their characteristic marching music is the only trace of them that remains today.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]禁卫军是奥斯曼苏丹培养的一支精锐步兵战斗部队。他们组成了苏丹的家庭军队和保镖，最终在19世纪解散之前，上升到一个具有巨大影响力的地位。穆拉德一世在1330年左右建立了“Janissary军团”；这支部队由非穆斯林男孩组成，他们在战斗中被俘虏，或被当作奴隶收买，然后被当作战士抚养长大。这与埃及的马梅鲁克奴隶士兵非常相似，他们可能是Janissaries的灵感来源。日军成为奥斯曼帝国军队的第一批步兵，因为当时没有一个自由人愿意步行作战。[第2段]1380年后，通过一个称为“devshirmeh”的程序，在Janissaries招募新士兵的制度变得标准化：这基本上是一种“人类税”，每个社区都必须向国家贡献一定数量的男孩。实际上，这些人几乎都是基督教奴隶。[第2段]这些男孩被隔离在特殊的营房里，在那里他们将皈依伊斯兰教，并接受训练成为精英士兵（这一过程与古希腊斯巴达人的做法非常相似）。虽然是奴隶，但是日本的卫戍区享有特殊的特权，包括携带武器的权利和比其他士兵更高的薪水。尽管禁卫军最初是作为苏丹的一个小保镖而存在的，但后来他们组成了奥斯曼帝国的大部分军队，在某些时候超过了20万人。[第2段]Janissaries最初被训练成弓箭手专家，但一旦发明了火器，他们很快就采用了新武器，对步枪变得非常熟练。他们通常使用斧头或刀进行近战。在奥斯曼帝国早期历史上的所有重大战役中，包括1453年对君士坦丁堡的围攻中，都曾出现过禁卫军。[第2段]一月的成功最终会摧毁他们。意识到自己的重要性，他们开始要求更高的工资，威胁说如果他们的要求被拒绝，他们就会造反。他们的第一次叛乱发生在1449年，随后又发生了更多的叛乱。到了18世纪，政府由禁卫军统治。通过频繁的宫廷政变，他们如愿以偿地更换苏丹，并阻止了奥斯曼军队急需的现代化改革。许多禁卫军变得腐败，不再为战斗训练，而是追求商业冒险或政治职位，奥斯曼帝国在俄罗斯和奥地利扩张面前的弱点很快就变得显而易见。奥斯曼统治者急于夺回对自己国家的控制权，决心铲除他们。[第2段]最后，在1826年，马哈茂德二世组建了一支强大到足以挑战一月制的非一月制军队。卫戍军并没有和平地倒下，马哈茂德二世不得不用大炮炮击卫戍军的军营，并将他们击溃投降。这一事件被称为“吉祥事件”，结束了一月。他们特有的行军音乐是他们今天仅存的踪迹。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NEW_JANISSARY</Tag>
    <English>A new Janissary unit reports for service in</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>一个新的单位报到</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
