<?xml version='1.0' encoding='GBK'?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by XMLSPY 2004 Professional Ed. Release 2, Installed Multi + SMP for 3 users (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - RFCE Buildings -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
  <!-- Unique Buildings -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VENICE_ARSENAL</Tag>
    <English>Arsenal</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>军械库</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VENICE_ARSENAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Venetian Arsenal is a shipyard and naval depot that played a leading role in Venetian empire-building. It was one of the most important areas of Venice, lying in the Castello sestiere.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Byzantine-style establishment may have existed as early as the 8th century, though the present structure is usually said to have been begun in 1104, although there is no evidence for such a precise date. It definitely existed by the early thirteenth century and is mentioned in Dante's Inferno. The name probably comes from Arabic Dar al Sina'a ("Dockyard") and the concept was clearly Islamic as much as Byzantine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Initially the state dockyard worked merely to maintain naval ships built privately, but in 1320 the Arsenal Nuovo was built, much larger than the original. It enabled all the state's navy and the larger merchant ships to be both constructed and maintained in one place. The Arsenal incidentally became an important centre for rope manufacture, while housing for the arsenal workers grew up outside its walls.[PARAGRAPH:2]Venice developed methods of mass-producing warships in the Arsenal, including the frame-first system to replace the Roman hull-first practice. The new system was much faster and required less wood. At the peak of its efficiency in the early 16th century, the Arsenal employed some 16,000 people who apparently were able to produce nearly one ship each day, and could fit out, arm, and provision a newly-built galley with standardized parts on a production-line basis not seen again until the Industrial Revolution.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]威尼斯兵工厂是一个造船厂和海军基地，在威尼斯帝国的建设中发挥了主导作用。这是威尼斯最重要的地区之一，位于塞斯蒂埃城堡（Castello sestiere）[第2段]拜占庭式的建筑可能早在8世纪就已经存在，尽管目前的建筑通常被认为是在1104年开始的，尽管没有证据表明确切的日期。它肯定存在于十三世纪早期，并在但丁的《地狱》中提到。这个名字可能来源于阿拉伯语Dar al-Sina'a（“船坞”），这个概念显然和拜占庭语一样伊斯兰。[第2段]最初，国家船坞只是为了维护私人建造的海军舰艇，但在1320年，建造了兵工厂Nuovo，比原来的要大得多。它使该州所有的海军和更大的商船都能在一个地方建造和维护。顺便说一句，这座兵工厂成了一个重要的绳索制造中心，而兵工厂工人的住房则是在它的围墙外成长起来的。[第2段]威尼斯在兵工厂里开发了大量生产军舰的方法，包括用框架优先系统取代罗马船体优先的做法。新系统速度快得多，所需木材少。在16世纪早期的效率巅峰时期，兵工厂雇佣了大约16000人，他们显然能够每天生产近一艘船，并且能够装配、武装和提供一个新建造的厨房，在生产线基础上配备标准化零件，直到工业革命才再次出现。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BULGARIAN_STAN</Tag>
    <English>Stan</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>斯坦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BULGARIAN_STAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Stan means Camp in Bulgarian. The building is a reference to the early Bulgarians' highly developed horsemanship and their traditions associated with it, especially in warfare. The usage of mounted warriors in the Bulgarian armies was remarkable.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Byzantine historian Pseudo-Simeon stated that Krum sent a 30,000 strong cavalry, "the whole armoured with iron", which devastated Thrace. According to inscriptions found in the region of Pliska, Preslav, Madara and Shabla in north-eastern Bulgaria, armaments for 1,713 heavy riders were available. Assuming that the surviving inscriptions are around 1/10 of the total number, that makes 17,130 men only in the so called "inner region" of Bulgaria. After comparison with the data of Pseudo-Simeon, it can be assumed that the heavy cavalry component of the Bulgarian army numbered between 17-20,000 and 30,000 men, depending on the level of mobilization. During the end of the 9th and the beginning of the 10th centuries, Emperor Simeon the Great was able to lead in battle more than 60,000 soldiers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]斯坦是保加利亚人的营地。这座建筑是对保加利亚早期高度发展的骑术及其相关传统的参考，尤其是在战争中。保加利亚军队中骑兵的使用非常显著。[第2段]拜占庭历史学家伪西门（Pseudo Simeon）说，克鲁姆派出了一支30000人的骑兵，“全是铁甲骑兵”，摧毁了色雷斯。根据在保加利亚东北部的普利斯卡、普雷斯拉夫、马达拉和沙布拉地区发现的铭文，有1713辆重型骑手的武器。假设幸存的碑文约占总数的1/10，那么只有17130名男子在所谓的保加利亚“内陆地区”。与伪西缅的资料比较后，可以认为保加利亚军队的重骑兵部分根据动员程度，人数在17-20万至30万之间。在9世纪末和10世纪初，西门大帝能够领导超过6万名士兵作战。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KIEV_VECHE</Tag>
    <English>Veche Hall</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>集会厅</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KIEV_VECHE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The word "veche" refers to popular assemblies in medieval Slavic countries. The east slavic veche is thought to have originated in the tribal assemblies of Eastern Europe, thus predating the Rus' state. The earliest mentions of veches in Russian chronicles refer to examples in Belgorod, a city on the Dnieper in 977, the Novgorod Republic in 1016, and in Kiev in 1068. The assemblies discussed matters of war and peace, adopted laws, and called for and expelled rulers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]一些著名的热那亚家庭参与了银行的建立和管理，包括格里马尔迪和塞拉的房屋。在当时，这家银行不同寻常地利用了一些犹太代理人，包括管理黑海周边某些财产的戈伊索菲家族（Ghisolfi clean）。[第2段]这家银行由四位执政官管理，他们负责管理银行的财务和指导投资。由于共和国的统治寡头通常在银行政治中很突出，因此很难确定银行的影响力在哪里结束，共和国从哪里开始。[第2段]热那亚的许多海外领土直接或间接由银行管理。1453年，共和国将科西嘉岛、加扎里亚岛和其他一些领地的管理权移交给了银行官员，尽管在15世纪，共和国逐渐从银行控制中收回了许多领土。塔曼半岛仍由德戈伊索菲家族控制，但该家族的王子现在向世行报告。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNGARIAN_STRONGHOLD</Tag>
    <English>Vgvr</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>匈牙利堡垒</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HUNGARIAN_STRONGHOLD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]After the Turks conquered much of southern Hungary, a new defensive line inside the country was strongly needed. Out of castles, mansions, churches and monasteries a new defensive line was built with the efforts of the bondsmen of the surrounding area within a short time. A new system of castles was created, which began at the Adriatic Sea, ended at the lower Danube River and enclosed the area that was controlled by the Turks. The most important functions of these Vgvrs were to defend the borders, secure the roads and the river crossings, the prevention of the enemy troop supplies and the security of the people and their goods in the surrounding area.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]土耳其人占领匈牙利南部大部分地区后，迫切需要在匈牙利境内建立新的防线。在城堡、豪宅、教堂和修道院之外，在周围地区的奴隶们的努力下，在短时间内建立了一条新的防线。一个新的城堡体系开始于亚得里亚海，结束于多瑙河下游，包围了土耳其人控制的地区。这些VgVrs最重要的职能是保卫边界、保卫道路和河流过境点、防止敌军补给和周围地区人民及其货物的安全。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POLISH_FOLWARK</Tag>
    <English>Folwark</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>大庄园</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POLISH_FOLWARK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Folwarks are giant Polish farms that were operated in the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth from the 14th century into the 20th. They were used to produce a surplus of food. The first folwarks were created on church and monastery owned grounds, but were later adopted by nobility and rich peasants. The creation of folwarks was boosted by a growing demand for grain and its high profit. Folwark-based grain export was an important part of the economy of the Polish-Lithuanian commonwealth.[PARAGRAPH:2]The fall of agriculture goods prices in the end of the 17th century marked the start of a crisis for the folwark related economy. The noble's attempt to increase use of folwarks only hurt the economic crisis more. Until the 18th century, folwarks remained the basis for Polish noble's economic and political power. After the abolition of serfdom in Poland, folwarks used paid labor. Folwarks were abolished by the People's Republic of Poland with the PKWN decree of 6 September 1944 about agricultural reform</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]一些著名的热那亚家庭参与了银行的建立和管理，包括格里马尔迪和塞拉的房屋。在当时，这家银行不同寻常地利用了一些犹太代理人，包括管理黑海周边某些财产的戈伊索菲家族（Ghisolfi clean）。[第2段]这家银行由四位执政官管理，他们负责管理银行的财务和指导投资。由于共和国的统治寡头通常在银行政治中很突出，因此很难确定银行的影响力在哪里结束，共和国从哪里开始。[第2段]热那亚的许多海外领土直接或间接由银行管理。1453年，共和国将科西嘉岛、加扎里亚岛和其他一些领地的管理权移交给了银行官员，尽管在15世纪，共和国逐渐从银行控制中收回了许多领土。塔曼半岛仍由德戈伊索菲家族控制，但该家族的王子现在向世行报告。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITHUANIAN_VOIVODESHIP</Tag>
    <English>Vaivadija</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>将军领地</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITHUANIAN_VOIVODESHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A voivodeship, also spelled voivodship, voivodina or vojvodina, is the area administrated by a voivode or governor in several countries of central and east Europe. Voivodeships have existed since medieval times in Poland, Hungary, Lithuania, Latvia, Ukraine, Russia, Wallachia and Serbia. The administrative level of a voivodeship resembles a western duchy, much as the title of voivode was equivalent to that of a duke. The voivode (literally, "leader of warriors") was originally the military commander next to the ruler.[PARAGRAPH:2]Contemporary, the term is used for the "provinces" (wojewdztwa) of Poland, of which there are currently 16. There is also an autonomous province of Vojvodina in Serbia (historic part of Medieval Hungary up to the end of WW1, today with a mixed Hungarian-Serbian population)[PARAGRAPH:2]Also, the word "voivodeship" appears in some of the larger English dictionaries, such as the OED and Webster's Third New International Dictionary, though it is not in common usage. Depending on the context, historic voivodeships may also be referred to as "duchies," "provinces," "palatinates," "administrative districts" or "regions".</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]一些著名的热那亚家庭参与了银行的建立和管理，包括格里马尔迪和塞拉的房屋。在当时，这家银行不同寻常地利用了一些犹太代理人，包括管理黑海周边某些财产的戈伊索菲家族（Ghisolfi clean）。[第2段]这家银行由四位执政官管理，他们负责管理银行的财务和指导投资。由于共和国的统治寡头通常在银行政治中很突出，因此很难确定银行的影响力在哪里结束，共和国从哪里开始。[第2段]热那亚的许多海外领土直接或间接由银行管理。1453年，共和国将科西嘉岛、加扎里亚岛和其他一些领地的管理权移交给了银行官员，尽管在15世纪，共和国逐渐从银行控制中收回了许多领土。塔曼半岛仍由德戈伊索菲家族控制，但该家族的王子现在向世行报告。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GENOA_BANK</Tag>
    <English>Genoan Bank</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>热那亚银行</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GENOA_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A number of prominent Genoese families were involved in the establishment and governance of the Bank, including the Houses of Grimaldi and Serra. Unusually for its time, the Bank made use of a number of Jewish agents, including the Ghisolfi clan that managed certain possessions around the Black Sea.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Bank was governed by four consuls who administered its finances and directed investments. Because the Republic's ruling oligarchs were normally prominent in Bank politics, it is often difficult to determine where the Bank's influence ended and the Republic's began.[PARAGRAPH:2]Many of Genoa's overseas territories were governed either directly or indirectly by the Bank. In 1453 the Republic handed over governance of Corsica, Gazaria, and a number of other possessions to Bank officials, though over the course of the fifteenth century the Republic gradually reclaimed many of its territories from Bank control. The Taman peninsula remained in the control of the de Ghisolfi family, but the princes of that clan now reported to the Bank.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]一些著名的热那亚家庭参与了银行的建立和管理，包括格里马尔迪和塞拉的房屋。在当时，这家银行不同寻常地利用了一些犹太代理人，包括管理黑海周边某些财产的戈伊索菲家族（Ghisolfi clean）。[第2段]这家银行由四位执政官管理，他们负责管理银行的财务和指导投资。由于共和国的统治寡头通常在银行政治中很突出，因此很难确定银行的影响力在哪里结束，共和国从哪里开始。[第2段]热那亚的许多海外领土直接或间接由银行管理。1453年，共和国将科西嘉岛、加扎里亚岛和其他一些领地的管理权移交给了银行官员，尽管在15世纪，共和国逐渐从银行控制中收回了许多领土。塔曼半岛仍由德戈伊索菲家族控制，但该家族的王子现在向世行报告。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUSTRIAN_OPERA_HOUSE</Tag>
    <English>Opera House</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>歌剧院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUSTRIAN_OPERA_HOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]An opera house is a theater building used for opera performances that consists of a stage, an orchestra pit, audience seating, and backstage facilities for costumes and set building. While some venues are constructed specifically for operas, other opera houses are part of larger performing arts centers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Because many operas call for large-scale productions, opera houses are usually large - generally more than 1,000 seats and often several thousand seats. Traditionally, Europe's major opera houses built in the 19th century contained between about 1,500 to 3,000 seats. Since the latter part of the nineteenth century, opera houses generally have an orchestra pit, where a large number of orchestra players may be seated at a level below the audience, so that they can play without overwhelming the singing voices.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Vienna Opera House (Staatsoper) has a world-wide reputation for its first-class opera performances and is also known because of the Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra. A night at the State Opera is one of the most impressive events any visitor to Vienna can experience.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]歌剧院是用于歌剧表演的剧院建筑，包括舞台、管弦乐池、观众席、后台服装设施和布景建筑。虽然有些场馆是专门为歌剧建造的，但其他歌剧院是大型表演艺术中心的一部分。[第2段]因为许多歌剧需要大规模的演出，歌剧院通常都是大型的，通常超过1000个座位，通常有几千个座位。传统上，建于19世纪的欧洲主要歌剧院大约有1500到3000个座位。十九世纪下半叶以来，歌剧院一般都有一个管弦乐池，许多管弦乐手可能坐在观众下面的水平面上，维也纳歌剧院（Staatsoper）以其一流的歌剧表演享誉世界，也因维也纳爱乐乐团而闻名。在国家歌剧院过夜是任何到维也纳的游客都能体验到的最令人印象深刻的活动之一。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SWEDISH_TENNANT</Tag>
    <English>Soldattorp</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>小农场</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SWEDISH_TENNANT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The allotment system (Swedish: indelningsverket) was a system used in Sweden for keeping a trained army at all times. This system came into use in around 1640, and was replaced in the early 1900s by the Swedish Armed Forces conscription system. Two different allotment systems have been in use in Sweden; they are the old allotment system (ldre indelningsverket) and the new allotment system (yngre indelningsverket), the latter often referred to as just "the allotment system". The soldiers who were part of these systems were known as "tenement soldiers" (indelta soldater, the Swedish term, does not have the same meaning) due to the small tenements or crofts allotted to them.[PARAGRAPH:2]Originally, the allotment system was a name for a system used to pay servants of the state, like officers and clergy. It was introduced because of an often felt shortage of money, and the allotment system tried to solve this by localizing taxes; meaning that payment consisted of an individual's right to collect certain taxes. Later on it referred to an organization created to provide soldiers to the armed forces, properly known as "det stndiga knektehallet" (literally "the permanent soldier household"). The reason for this development of the term is that a large part of the allotment system was used to support det stndiga knektehallet.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]配给制度（瑞典语：indelningsverket）是瑞典一直用来维持训练有素的军队的制度。这一制度于1640年左右开始使用，并在20世纪初被瑞典武装部队征兵制度所取代。瑞典采用了两种不同的分配制度，即旧的分配制度（德雷因丁斯韦克特）和新的分配制度（恩格雷因丁斯韦克特），后者通常被称为“分配制度”。作为这些制度一部分的士兵被称为“租房士兵”（indelta soldater，瑞典语，不具有相同的含义），因为分配给他们的是小的租房或小公寓。[第2段]最初，分配制度是一种用来支付国家公务员，如军官和神职人员的制度的名称。它的提出是因为人们经常感到资金短缺，分配制度试图通过将税收本地化来解决这一问题；也就是说，支付包括个人征收某些税款的权利。后来，它提到了一个为向武装部队提供士兵而成立的组织，即“det stndiga knektehallet”（字面意思是“永久士兵家庭”）。这一术语发展的原因是，分配制度的很大一部分用于支持det stndiga knektehallet。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FRENCH_CHATEAU</Tag>
    <English>Chateau</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>城堡庄园</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FRENCH_CHATEAU_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A chteau is a manor house or residence of the lord of the manor or a country house of nobility or gentry, with or without fortifications, originally-and still most frequently-in French-speaking regions. Where clarification is needed, a fortified chteau (that is, a castle) is called a chteau fort, such as Chteau fort de Roquetaillade. Care should be taken when translating the word chteau into English. It is not used in the same way as "castle", and most chteaux are described in English as "palaces" or "country houses" rather than "castles". For example, the Chteau de Versailles is so called because it was located in the countryside when it was built, but it does not bear any resemblance to a castle, so it is usually known in English as the Palace of Versailles.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]城堡是指庄园主的庄园或住所，或贵族或绅士的乡村宅邸，有或没有防御工事，最初和现在最常出现在法语地区。在需要澄清的地方，一座设防的城堡（即城堡）被称为一座城堡，例如罗克泰拉德城堡（chteau fort de Roquetaillade）。把“chteau”这个词译成英语时要小心。它的使用方式与“城堡”不同，而且大多数城堡在英语中被描述为“宫殿”或“乡间别墅”，而不是“城堡”。例如，凡尔赛宫之所以被称为“Chteau de Versailles”，是因为它在建造时位于乡村，但与城堡没有任何相似之处，因此在英语中通常被称为凡尔赛宫。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BURGUNDIAN_WINERY</Tag>
    <English>Winery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>葡萄酒厂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BURGUNDIAN_WINERY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Burgundy wine (French: Bourgogne or Vin de Bourgogne) is wine made in the Burgundy region in eastern France, in the valleys and slopes west of the Sane River, a tributary of the Rhne. The most famous wines produced here - those commonly referred to as "Burgundies" - are red wines made from Pinot Noir grapes or white wines made from Chardonnay grapes. Red and white wines are also made from other grape varieties, such as Gamay and Aligot?respectively. Small amounts of ros?and sparkling wine are also produced in the region. Chardonnay-dominated Chablis and Gamay-dominated Beaujolais are formally part of Burgundy wine region, but wines from those subregions are usually referred to by their own names rather than as "Burgundy wines".[PARAGRAPH:2]The status of Burgundy wines continued in the court of the House of Valois, which ruled as Dukes of Burgundy for much of the 14th and 15th centuries. It is from this era we have the first reliable reference to grape varieties in Burgundy. Pinot Noir was first mentioned in 1370 under the name Noirien, but it is believed that it was cultivated earlier than that, since no other grape variety associated with Medieval Burgundy is believed to have been able to produce red wines of a quality able to impress the papal court. On August 6, 1395, Duke Philip the Bold issued a decree concerned with safeguarding the quality of Burgundy wines. The duke declared Gamay, which was a higher-yielding grape than Pinot Noir in the 14th century as it is today, unfit for human consumption and banned the use of organic fertilizer (manure), which probably increased yields even further to the detriment of quality. High-quality white Burgundy wines of this era were probably made from Fromenteau, which is known as a quality grape in northeastern France in this time. Fromenteau is probably the same variety as today's Pinot Gris. Chardonnay is a much later addition to Burgundy's vineyards.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]勃艮第葡萄酒（法语：勃艮第或勃艮第酒）产于法国东部勃艮第地区，萨伊河以西的山谷和山坡上，勃艮第河的一条支流。这里出产的最著名的葡萄酒――通常被称为“勃艮第葡萄酒”――是由黑比诺葡萄酿制的红葡萄酒或由霞多丽葡萄酿制的白葡萄酒。红葡萄酒和白葡萄酒也是由其他葡萄品种制成的，比如加迈和阿里格？分别是。少量活性氧？该地区也生产起泡酒。以霞多丽为主的夏布利葡萄酒和以嘉美为主的博若莱葡萄酒正式成为勃艮第葡萄酒区的一部分，但这些次区域的葡萄酒通常以自己的名字命名，而不是“勃艮第葡萄酒”。[第2段]勃艮第葡萄酒的地位在瓦洛瓦家族的宫廷中继续存在，作为勃艮第公爵统治了14和15世纪。正是从这个时代开始，我们有了第一个可靠的勃艮第葡萄品种的参考。黑比诺于1370年首次以诺伊里恩的名字被提及，但人们相信，它的种植时间早于此，因为据信，没有其他与中世纪勃艮第葡萄酒有关的葡萄品种能够生产出能够给教皇宫廷留下深刻印象的优质红葡萄酒。1395年8月6日，菲利普公爵（Duke Philip the Bold）颁布了一项旨在保障勃艮第葡萄酒质量的法令。公爵宣布加迈是14世纪比现在的黑比诺产量更高的葡萄，不适合人类食用，并禁止使用有机肥料（肥料），这可能会进一步增加产量，损害质量。这个时代的优质勃艮第白葡萄酒很可能是用法国东北部的优质葡萄弗罗门托酿制的。弗洛门托可能和今天的灰比诺是同一品种。霞多丽是勃艮第葡萄园后来的新成员。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARABIC_CARAVAN</Tag>
    <English>Bazaar</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>巴扎</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARABIC_CARAVAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Arabian bazaars are lively and crowded places with hundreds of stalls, and the air is filled with the cries of merchants trying to entice wary customers to purchase their goods. Virtually anything imaginable can be found in markets, from food to clothing, rugs, perfume, furniture, and so forth. Such places can be perilous for the uninitiated, for the merchants will seek to wring out the largest sum possible for their wares, and a customer who is not versed in the fine art of haggling is very likely to get taken for every penny he or she has. Bazaars have existed virtually unchanged in Arabian cities for centuries. The Grand Bazaar in Istanbul, Turkey, covers some 60 streets and contains around 400 shops. The Grand Bazaar in Tehran, Iran, has been around in one form or another for over a thousand years: with over 10 km of corridors, it is the largest covered neighborhood in the world.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]阿拉伯集市是一个热闹而拥挤的地方，有数百个摊位，空气中充满了商家试图吸引谨慎的顾客购买商品的叫喊声。几乎所有可以想象的东西都能在市场上找到，从食物到衣服、地毯、香水、家具等等。对于外行来说，这样的地方可能是危险的，因为商人会设法为他们的商品榨取尽可能多的钱，而一个不精通讨价还价艺术的顾客很可能会被抢走每一分钱。几个世纪以来，集市在阿拉伯城市几乎没有改变。土耳其伊斯坦布尔的大集市覆盖了大约60条街道，有大约400家商店。伊朗德黑兰的大集市已经以这样或那样的形式存在了一千多年：它有超过10公里的走廊，是世界上最大的覆盖社区。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CORDOBAN_NORIA</Tag>
    <English>Noria</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>戽水车</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CORDOBAN_NORIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A noria is a machine for lifting water into a small aqueduct, either for the purpose of irrigation or, in at least one known instance, to feed seawater into a saltern.[PARAGRAPH:2]Muslim engineers used norias to discharge water into aqueducts which carried the water to towns and fields. Some of the norias used in the medieval Islamic world were as large as 20 meters in diameter, the one in Hama being a surviving example still used in modern times. It has 120 water collection compartments and could raise as much as 95 litres of water per minute.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]诺里亚是一种将水提升到小型渡槽中的机器，用于灌溉，或者至少在一个已知的例子中，将海水注入盐场。[第2段]穆斯林工程师使用诺里亚将水排放到将水输送到城镇和田地的渡槽中。中世纪伊斯兰世界使用的一些诺里亚斯直径高达20米，哈马的诺里亚斯是一个幸存的例子，至今仍在使用。它有120个水收集室，每分钟可增加多达95升水。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ENGLISH_ROYAL_EXCHANGE</Tag>
    <English>Royal Exchange</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>皇家证唤灰姿</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ENGLISH_ROYAL_EXCHANGE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]At the risk of dramatic oversimplification - a stock exchange is an organization which allows "brokers" to buy and sell "stocks" and "bonds." A stock represents part ownership in a company, and a bond is a loan to a company, which the company guarantees to repay with interest. If the company does well, the investors make money; if the company does poorly (or fails entirely) the investors lose money. [PARAGRAPH:2]The primary benefit of a stock exchange to society is that it allows companies to concentrate a large amount of wealth to accomplish something that no individual (or perhaps government) would be able to afford. In the nineteenth century, for example, construction of the United States' railroad network was in large part financed by individuals who purchased shares of railroad companies. Earlier in history, the great British and Dutch trading companies were similarly financed. [PARAGRAPH:2]For a long period of history, the English city of London was the financial center of the world. The London Stock Exchange is one of the largest exchanges in the world, as well as one of the oldest. Though officially founded in 1801, it can trace its origins to the late seventeenth century, when - the brokers having been expelled from the Royal Exchange for rowdiness - buying and selling stocks took place in London coffee houses. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]面临着严重的过分简单化的风险――证券交易所是一个允许“经纪人”买卖“股票”和“债券”的组织。股票代表公司的部分所有权，债券是对公司的贷款，公司保证偿还利息。如果公司做得好，投资者就赚钱；如果公司做得差（或完全失败），投资者就赔钱。[第2款]证券交易所对社会的主要好处是，它使公司能够集中大量财富，完成任何个人（或政府）都无法承担的事情。例如，在19世纪，美国铁路网的建设在很大程度上是由购买铁路公司股份的个人出资的。在历史早期，伟大的英国和荷兰贸易公司也得到了类似的融资。[第2段]在很长一段历史中，英国伦敦城是世界金融中心。伦敦证券交易所是世界上最大的交易所之一，也是最古老的交易所之一。虽然正式成立于1801年，但它的起源可以追溯到17世纪末，当时――经纪人因喧闹而被皇家交易所开除――买卖股票发生在伦敦的咖啡馆。[第2段]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOSCOW_KREMLIN</Tag>
    <English>Kremlin</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>克里姆林</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOSCOW_KREMLIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]"Kremlin" is a Russian word which denotes a fortified complex of buildings in the center of a city. It is most often used to refer to the Kremlin in the city of Moscow, a remarkable set of buildings which hold much of the Russian government. The Kremlin sits on a hill overlooking the Moskva River. In one form or the other, fortified structures have been in that location for almost 1000 years. The site was named "Kremlin" in the 14th century. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Kremlin is within a triangular, walled area about 68 acres in extent. The walls are of red brick, with pencil-like towers at the corners and entrances. Many of the buildings are painted white with yellow trim and green roofs that look quite cheerful from a distance. The Cathedral of the Dormition, constructed in the 1470s, is the oldest building in the complex. Two other cathedrals lie within its walls, as do a surprising number of palaces, the Kremlin Palace being the largest.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Kremlin has seen many great figures rise and fall within its walls. Ivan the Terrible built the Palace of Facets in the Kremlin. In the Great Patriotic War (WWII), Josef Stalin drove the German invaders from the gates of Moscow - perhaps the greatest service that any Russian ruler has ever performed for his country. (It was also here that Stalin planned the systematic extermination of millions of his own people.) It was here that Mikhail Gorbachev oversaw the dissolution of the Soviet Union. Today, the Kremlin holds the government of the Russian Federation.[PARAGRAPH:2]To whatever use it might be put in the future, the Kremlin will always stand as a mighty monument to Russia's past - for it has seen the best and the worst of that great nation.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]“克里姆林宫”是一个俄语单词，意思是城市中心的一个建筑群。它最常被用来指莫斯科市的克里姆林宫，这是一组引人注目的建筑，占据了俄罗斯政府的大部分。克里姆林宫坐落在一座小山上，俯瞰莫斯科河。无论是哪种形式，加固结构已经在那里存在了近1000年。该遗址在14世纪被命名为“克里姆林宫”。[第2段]克里姆林宫位于一个三角形的围墙内，面积约68英亩。墙是红砖砌的，角落和入口处有铅笔状的塔。许多建筑物被粉刷成白色，黄色的装饰和绿色的屋顶，从远处看很令人愉快。宿舍大教堂建于1470年代，是建筑群中最古老的建筑。另外两座大教堂和数量惊人的宫殿都坐落在城墙内，克里姆林宫是最大的宫殿。可怕的伊凡在克里姆林宫建造了一座刻面宫殿。在伟大的卫国战争（第二次世界大战）中，约瑟夫・斯大林把德国侵略者赶出了莫斯科的城门，这也许是任何一位俄罗斯统治者为他的国家所做的最伟大的贡献。（也正是在这里，斯大林计划有系统地消灭自己的数百万人民）米哈伊尔戈尔巴乔夫正是在这里监督苏联的解体。今天，克里姆林宫拥有俄罗斯联邦政府。[第2段]无论未来如何使用，克里姆林宫将永远作为俄罗斯过去的一座伟大的纪念碑屹立在那里，因为它看到了这个伟大国家的最好和最坏的一面。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DENMARK_RESEARCH_INSTITUTE</Tag>
    <English>Research Institute</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>研究所</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DENMARK_RESEARCH_INSTITUTE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A Research Institute is a establishment dedicated to science and research. Although the term often implies natural science research, there are also many research institutes in the social sciences as well, especially for sociological and historical research purposes.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the early medieval period, the several astronomic observatories in the Arab world served this purpose. A famous example is the 9th century Baghdad observatory built during the time of the Abbasid caliph al-Ma'mun, though the most famous were the 13th-century Maragheh observatory and the 15th-century Ulugh Beg Observatory. On Europe, the earliest recorded instance of a research institute would be Uraniborgn complex on the island of Hven(Denmark) of the 16th century, an astronomical laboratory set up to make highly accurate measurements of the stars led by Tycho Brahe.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Scientific Revolution brought an increase in the number and scope of such places. In France Louis XIV founded the Acadmie royale des sciences in 1666 to foster research, while in London the Royal Society was founded. On 28 January 1724 Peter the Great established an educational-research institute to be built in his newly created imperial capital, St Petersburg. His plan combined provisions for linguistic, philosophical and scientific instruction with a separate academy in which graduates could pursue further scientific researchm, unique for allowing to conduct scientific research within the structure of a university.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]研究所是专门从事科学研究的机构。虽然这个术语通常意味着自然科学研究，但在社会科学领域也有许多研究机构，特别是用于社会学和历史研究目的的研究机构。[第2段]在中世纪早期，阿拉伯世界的几个天文观测站就是这样做的。一个著名的例子是在阿巴斯哈里发al-Ma'mun时期建造的9世纪巴格达天文台，尽管最著名的是13世纪的马拉赫天文台和15世纪的乌鲁贝格天文台。在欧洲，最早有记录的研究机构是16世纪赫文岛（丹麦）上的乌拉尼博根综合设施，这是一个天文实验室，旨在对第谷布拉赫领导的恒星进行高度精确的测量。[第2段]科学革命增加了此类地点的数量和范围。1666年，路易十四在法国创立了皇家科学院（Acadmie royale des sciences），以促进研究，而在伦敦成立了皇家学会（Royal Society）。1724年1月28日，彼得大帝在他新创建的帝国首都圣彼得堡建立了一个教育研究所。他的计划将语言、哲学和科学教学的规定与一个单独的学院相结合，在这个学院里，毕业生可以从事进一步的科学研究，这是允许在大学结构内进行科学研究的独特做法。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOROCCO_KASBAH</Tag>
    <English>Kasbah</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>城堡</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOROCCO_KASBAH_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A Kasbah is a kind of medina, islamic city or citadel.[PARAGRAPH:2]It was a place for the local leader to live and a defense when a city was under attack. A kasbah has high walls, usually without windows. Sometimes, they were built on hilltops so that they could be more easily defended. Some were placed near the entrance to harbors.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ownership of a Kashab was a sign of wealth. When colonisation started in 1830, in northern Algeria, there were numerous kashabs that lasted over a century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Another use for the word is to describe the old part of a city, in which case its equivalent to a Medina. A Medina is a district of many north African cities that is typically walled, with narrow and maze-like streets. Many historical fountains, palaces and mosques tend to be here.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>卡斯巴是一种麦地那、伊斯兰城市或堡垒。[第2段]当一个城市受到攻击时，它是当地领导人居住和防御的地方。卡斯巴有高墙，通常没有窗户。有时，它们建在山顶上，这样就可以更容易地保护它们。有些被安置在港口入口附近。1830年，在阿尔及利亚北部开始殖民统治时，有许多卡沙布持续了一个多世纪。麦地那是北非许多城市的一个地区，通常有围墙，街道狭窄，迷宫般。许多历史悠久的喷泉、宫殿和清真寺往往就在这里。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARAGON_SEAPORT</Tag>
    <English>Consulate of the Sea</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>海事法庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARAGON_SEAPORT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Consulate of the Sea was a quasi-judicial body set up in the Crown of Aragon, later to spread throughout the Mediterranean basin, to administer maritime and commercial law. The term may also refer to a celebrated collection of maritime customs and ordinances in Catalan, also known in English as The Customs of the Sea, compiled over the 14th and 15th centuries and published at Barcelona in or before 1494.[PARAGRAPH:2]As the territories of the Crown of Aragon expanded, it was customary to establish new Consulates of the Sea in the major ports. One of the earliest was in Valencia (1283), where the charter of Peter III of Aragon makes it clear that disputes are to be settled "according to maritime customs, as these are accepted in Barcelona."[PARAGRAPH:2]The power of the Crown of Aragon is greatly merited from it's Thassalocratic nature, which was in turn based on the highly developed ports and the associated institutions in most of their cities.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]海洋领事馆是一个准司法机构，设在阿拉贡王国，后来扩展到整个地中海盆地，管理海事和商法。这一术语还可指加泰罗尼亚著名的海上海关和条例汇编，英文也被称为海洋海关，在14和15世纪编纂，1494年或之前在巴塞罗那出版。[第2段]随着阿拉贡王国领土的扩大，按照惯例，在主要港口设立新的海洋领事馆。最早的一次是在巴伦西亚（1283年），在那里阿拉贡彼得三世的宪章明确规定，争端要“按照海运习惯解决，因为这些习惯在巴塞罗那是被接受的。”[第2段]阿拉贡王冠的权力是非常有价值的，因为它的萨萨民主性质，这又是建立在高度发达的港口和大多数城市的相关机构的基础上。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PRUSSIA_PUBLIC_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>Volksschule</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>国民学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PRUSSIA_PUBLIC_SCHOOL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In 1717 King Frederick William I of Prussia decreed the compulsory education of children from the age of five to twelve. They had to be able to read and write and were obliged to memorise the Protestant catechism. In 1763 King Frederick the Great enacted a first Prussian general school law, elaborated by the theologian Johann Julius Hecker. This law saw the establishment of extensive public school networks across Prussia, and later the wider German states.[PARAGRAPH:2]State schools, also known as public schools outside of England and Wales, generally refer to primary or secondary schools mandated for or offered to all children without charge, funded in whole or in part by taxation. The term may also refer to public institutions of post-secondary education.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[注]1717年，普鲁士国王腓特烈威廉一世颁布了5至12岁儿童义务教育的法令。他们必须能够读和写，并且必须记住新教教义。1763年，腓特烈大帝颁布了第一部普鲁士普通学校法，由神学家约翰・朱利叶斯・赫克详细阐述。这项法律见证了在普鲁士和后来更广泛的德国各州建立广泛的公立学校网络。[第2款]公立学校，也被称为英格兰和威尔士以外的公立学校，一般是指为所有儿童授权或免费提供的小学或中学，全部或部分由税收供资。也可以指公立高等教育机构。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCOTTISH_SHIELING</Tag>
    <English>Shieling</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>牧场</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCOTTISH_SHIELING_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A Shieling is a hut or collection of huts once common in a wild or lonely place in the hills and mountains of Scotland and northern England. The word also refers to a mountain pasture used for the grazing of cattle in summer.[PARAGRAPH:2]During summer, farmers along with their families lived in shieling to have their livestock graze common land. Shielings were therefore associated with the transhumance system of agriculture, that being the seasonal movement of people along their livestock between fixed summer and winter pastures. The mountain huts generally fell out of use by the end of the 17th century, although in remote areas this system continued into the 18th.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]Shieling是苏格兰和英格兰北部山区的一个荒野或偏僻的地方曾经常见的一个小屋或一组小屋。这个词还指夏季用来放牧牛的山地牧场。[第2段]在夏季，农民和他们的家人住在石岭，让他们的牲畜在公共土地上吃草。因此，Shielings与农业的跨人类系统有关，即人们在固定的夏季和冬季牧场之间沿牲畜的季节性流动。尽管在偏远地区，这种系统一直持续到18世纪，但到17世纪末，这些山屋一般都已停止使用。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOVGOROD_KONETS</Tag>
    <English>Konets</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>仲裁庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOVGOROD_KONETS_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Kontsy literally means "ends", with Konets being it's singular form. Originally the Kontsy were the five boroughs into which medieval Novgorod the Great was divided. They were based on the three original settlements that combined to form the city toward the end of the tenth century, and two later additions. Many of these boroughs were highly specialized, even called like "Potters' End" or "Carpenters' End".[PARAGRAPH:2]Ingame the Konets building represents a specialized Guild, which dominates production and trade in the entire city.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]Kontsy字面意思是“结束”，Konets是它的单数形式。康茨最初是中世纪诺夫哥罗德大帝被分成的五个行政区。它们是建立在三个最初的定居点的基础上，这三个定居点在十世纪末形成了这座城市，后来又增加了两个定居点。这些行政区中的许多都是高度专业化的，甚至被称为“陶工区”或“木匠区”。[第2段]因加梅科内茨大厦代表着一个专业化的行会，主导着整个城市的生产和贸易。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Unique Buildings -->
  <!-- General Buildings -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DUNGEON</Tag>
    <English>Dungeon</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>地牢</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DUNGEON_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A dungeon is a room or cell in which prisoners are kept, especially underground. Dungeons are generally associated with medieval castles, though their association with torture probably belongs more to the Renaissance period. The image of dark, damp dungeons as the scene of lengthy incarceration and unspeakable cruelty is a powerful one in popular culture.[PARAGRAPH:2]In its original medieval usage, donjon meant a keep, the main tower of a castle which formed the final defensive position to which the garrison could retreat when outer fortifications were overcome. By association of a tower with a prison, its English meaning has evolved over time to mean an underground prison or oubliette, typically in a basement of a castle.[PARAGRAPH:2]In French the term donjon still refers to a "keep", and the term oubliette is a more appropriate translation of English "dungeon". Donjon is therefore a false friend to "dungeon".</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>地牢是囚禁犯人的房间或牢房，特别是在地下。地牢通常与中世纪城堡联系在一起，尽管它们与酷刑的联系可能更多地属于文艺复兴时期。黑暗潮湿的地下城是漫长的监禁和难以形容的残酷场面，这在流行文化中是一个强有力的形象。[第2段]在其最初的中世纪用法中，东戎指的是一个堡垒，城堡的主要塔楼，它形成了当外部防御工事被攻破时驻军可以撤退的最后防御阵地。通过将塔楼与监狱联系起来，它的英文意思随着时间的推移逐渐演变为地下监狱或城堡的地下室。因此，东戎是“地牢”的假朋友。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARCHERY_RANGE</Tag>
    <English>Archery Range</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>靶场</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARCHERY_RANGE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]An important technological innovation, bows were perhaps the first machines built to store energy slowly and then release it quickly. Bows and arrows have been in existence for 30,000 years. The original bows were made of springy wood - yew, bamboo, palm, and so forth. By 1300 BC, bows were made of composite material - wood, horn, and sinew. The first arrows were probably straight wooden sticks with one end sharpened and fire-hardened. Stone tips were added once man learned to sharpen flint.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]弓箭是一项重要的技术创新，它可能是第一台缓慢储存能量，然后迅速释放能量的机器。弓箭已经存在了三万年。原来的弓是由有弹性的紫杉木、竹子、棕榈木等制成的。到公元前1300年，弓是由复合材料制成的――木头、角和筋。第一支箭可能是直的木棍，一端削尖，火烧硬。一旦人们学会磨石，就加上了石尖。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WHARF</Tag>
    <English>Wharf</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>货运码头</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WHARF_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A wharf is a landing place or pier where ships may tie up and load or unload. A wharf commonly comprises a fixed platform, often on pilings. They often serve as interim storage areas with warehouses, since the typical objective is to unload and reload vessels as quickly as possible. Where capacity is sufficient a single quay constructed along the land adjacent to the water is normally used; where there is a need for more capacity many wharves will instead be constructed projecting into the water, as with the well known collection of wharves in San Francisco. A pier, raised over the water rather than within it, is one type of wharf, commonly used for cases where the weight or volume of cargos will be low.[PARAGRAPH:2]Smaller and more modern wharves are sometimes built on flotation devices (pontoons) to keep them at the same level to the ship even during changing tides.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]码头是船舶停靠、装卸的平台或码头。码头通常包括固定平台，通常在桩上。它们通常作为带有仓库的临时储存区，因为通常的目标是尽快卸载和重新装载船只。如果容量足够，则通常使用沿水边陆地建造的单个码头；如果需要更大的容量，则将建造许多突出水面的码头，如旧金山著名的码头群。码头是一种码头类型，通常用于货物重量或体积较低的情况。[第2款]更小、更现代化的码头有时建在浮式装置（浮筒）上，即使在潮汐变化时也能保持与船舶处于同一水平。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILD_HALL</Tag>
    <English>Guild Hall</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>市政厅</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILD_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A Guildhall is a building used by guilds for meetings. The town authorities were represented in the guild meetings and thus had a means of controlling the handicraft activities. This was important since towns very often depended on a good reputation for export of a narrow range of products, on which not only the guild's, but the town's, reputation depended.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]公会是公会用来开会的建筑物。镇政府有代表参加公会会议，因此有办法控制手工业活动。这一点很重要，因为城镇往往依赖于出口范围狭窄的产品的良好声誉，不仅依赖于行业协会，而且依赖于城镇的声誉。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TANNERY</Tag>
    <English>Tannery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>制革厂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TANNERY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Tanning is the process of making leather, which does not easily decompose, from the skins of animals, which do. Often this uses tannin, an acidic chemical compound. Coloring may occur during tanning. A tannery is the term for a place where these skins are processed.[PARAGRAPH:2]Tanning leather involves a process which permanently alters the protein structure of skin so that it cannot ever return to rawhide. Making rawhide does not require the use of tannin and is made simply by removing the flesh and fat and then the hair by way of soaking in an aqueous solution (often called liming when using lime and water or bucking when using wood ash (lye) and water), then scraping over a beam with a somewhat dull knife, and then leaving to dry, usually stretched on a frame so that it dries flat. The two aforementioned solutions for removing the hair also act to clean the fiber network of the skin and therefore allow penetration and action of the tanning agent.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[制革]制革是从动物的皮肤上制成不易分解的皮革的过程。通常使用单宁，一种酸性化合物。在鞣制过程中可能发生着色。制革厂是指加工这些皮革的地方。[第2段]制革涉及到一个永久改变皮肤蛋白质结构，使其不能再回到生皮的过程。制作生皮不需要使用单宁，制作方法很简单，先除去肉和脂肪，然后将头发浸泡在水溶液中（使用石灰和水时通常称为石灰，使用木灰（碱液）和水时称为打浆），然后用有点钝的刀在横梁上刮擦，然后晾干，通常在框架上拉伸使其干燥。上述两种脱毛解决方案也可用于清洁皮肤的纤维网络，从而允许鞣剂的渗透和作用。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NIGHT_WATCH</Tag>
    <English>Night Watch</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>守夜岗哨</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NIGHT_WATCH_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A night watch was a law enforcement formation found in some countries and historical periods, usually subordinate to the local municipal government. Historically many cities had their own guard formations, which doubled as police and military force in times of need.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]夜班是在一些国家和历史时期发现的一种执法队形，通常隶属于当地市政府。历史上，许多城市都有自己的警卫队伍，在需要的时候，他们的警力和军事力量翻了一番。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANOR_HOUSE</Tag>
    <English>Manor House</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>庄园</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANOR_HOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A manor house or fortified manor-house is a country house, which has historically formed the administrative centre of a manor, the lowest unit of territorial organization in the feudal system. The term is sometimes applied to relatively small country houses which belonged to gentry families, as well as to grand stately homes, particularly as a technical term for minor late medieval fortified country houses intended more for show than for defence.[PARAGRAPH:2]In general terms, the manor house was the dwelling house, or "capital messuage", of a feudal lord of a manor, which he occupied only on occasional visits if he held many manors. As such it was the place in which sessions of his "court baron", or manor court, were held. Sometimes a steward or seneschal was appointed by the seigneurial lord to oversee and manage his different manorial properties. The day-to-day administration was delegated to a bailiff, or reeve.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although not typically built with strong fortifications as castles were, many manor-houses were partly fortified: they were enclosed within walls or ditches that often included the farm buildings as well. Arranged for defence against robbers and thieves, it was often surrounded by a moat with a drawbridge, and equipped with small gatehouses and watchtowers; but was not provided with a keep or with large towers or lofty curtain walls so as to withstand a siege. The primary feature of the manor-house was its great hall, to which subsidiary apartments were added as the lessening of feudal warfare permitted more peaceful domestic life.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the beginning of the 16th century, manor-houses as well as small castles began to acquire the character and amenities of the residences of country gentlemen. This late 16th century transformation produced many of the smaller Renaissance chteaux of France and the numerous country mansions of the Elizabethan and Jacobean styles in England.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]庄园或设防庄园是一种乡村住宅，它在历史上形成了庄园的行政中心，是封建制度中领土组织的最低单位。这个术语有时适用于相对较小的乡间别墅，这些别墅属于贵族家庭，也适用于宏伟的豪宅，尤其是中世纪晚期的小型强化乡间别墅，其目的更多是为了展示而非防御。[第2段]一般来说，庄园就是住宅，或“首都宅院”，指封建领主的一个庄园，他只有在偶尔造访时，如果他拥有许多庄园，才会占领。正因为如此，这才是举行“宫廷男爵”或庄园宫廷会议的地方。有时，一个管家或总管被任命为君主监督和管理他的不同庄园财产。日常的行政管理权下放给了一个法警，或者说里夫（reeve）[第2段]虽然不像城堡那样通常用坚固的防御工事建造，但许多庄园的房屋都有部分的防御工事：它们被围在围墙或沟渠里，这些围墙或沟渠通常也包括农场建筑。为了防御强盗和小偷，它经常被一条带吊桥的护城河包围，并配有小门房和望塔；但没有一个城堡或大塔楼或高高的幕墙来抵御围攻。庄园宅邸的主要特点是其大会堂，由于封建战争的减少，家庭生活变得更加平静，因此增加了附属公寓。[第2段]到16世纪初，庄园宅邸和小城堡开始具有乡村绅士住宅的特点和便利设施。这种16世纪晚期的转变产生了法国文艺复兴时期许多较小的城堡，以及英国伊丽莎白和雅各布风格的众多乡村宅邸。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVER</Tag>
    <English>Weaver</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>作坊</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEAVER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Weaving is a textile craft in which two distinct sets of yarns or threads, called the warp and the filling or weft (older woof), are interlaced to form a fabric or cloth. The warp threads run lengthways on the piece of cloth, and the weft runs across from side to side, across the bolt of cloth.[PARAGRAPH:2]Cloth is woven on a loom, a device that holds the warp threads in place while filling threads are woven through them. Weft is an old English word meaning "that which is woven".[PARAGRAPH:2]The way the warp and filling threads interlace with each other is called the weave. The majority of woven products are created with one of three basic weaves: plain weave, satin weave, or twill.[PARAGRAPH:2]Woven cloth can be plain (in one colour or a simple pattern), or can be woven in decorative or artistic designs, including tapestries. Fabric in which the warp and/or weft is tie-dyed before weaving is called ikat.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]编织是一种纺织工艺，其中两组不同的纱线或线，称为经纱和纬纱（旧纬纱），交织在一起形成织物或布。经线在织物上纵向运行，纬线在织物的螺栓上从一边到另一边运行。[第2段]织物是在织机上织的，织机是一种在织入纬线时将经线固定在适当位置的装置。纬线是一个古老的英语单词，意思是“编织的东西”。[第2段]经线和纬线相互交织的方式叫做编织。大多数机织产品是由三种基本织物之一制成的：平纹织物、缎纹织物或斜纹织物。[第2款]机织布可以是平纹织物（一种颜色或简单图案），也可以是装饰性或艺术性的织物，包括挂毯。在织造前经纱和/或纬纱扎染的织物称为纤维织物。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREWERY</Tag>
    <English>Brewery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>啤酒厂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREWERY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A brewery is a dedicated building for the making of beer, though beer can be made in the home, and has been for much of beer's history. A company which makes beer is called either a brewery or a brewing company.[PARAGRAPH:2]The diversity of size in breweries is matched by the diversity of processes, degrees of automation, and kinds of beer produced in breweries. Typically a brewery is divided into distinct sections, with each section reserved for one part of the brewing process.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]啤酒厂是专门用来生产啤酒的建筑，尽管啤酒可以在家里生产，而且啤酒的历史也有很多。酿造啤酒的公司称为酿酒厂或酿酒公司。[第2段]酿酒厂规模的多样性与酿酒厂生产的工艺、自动化程度和啤酒种类的多样性相匹配。通常，啤酒厂被分成不同的部分，每个部分都是为酿造过程的一部分保留的。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAVERN</Tag>
    <English>Tavern</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>酒馆</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAVERN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A tavern is a place of business where people gather to drink alcoholic beverages and be served food, and in some cases, where travelers receive lodging. An inn is a tavern which has a license to put up guests as lodgers. The word derives from the Latin taberna and the Greek taverna, whose original meaning was a shed or workshop. In the English language the tavern was an establishment which served wine whilst the inn served beer/ale. Over time, the words tavern and inn became interchangeable and synonymous with one another. Travelers stayed in taverns.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]酒馆是人们聚集在一起喝酒精饮料、吃东西的地方，在某些情况下，游客在这里住宿。客栈是一种酒馆，它有把客人寄宿的许可证。这个词来源于拉丁语taberna和希腊语taverna，其原意是棚屋或作坊。在英语中，酒馆是一个提供葡萄酒的场所，而客栈则提供啤酒/麦芽酒。随着时间的推移，tavern和inn这两个词变得可以相互替换，成为了同义词。旅行者们住在酒馆里。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INN</Tag>
    <English>Inn</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>旅店</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Inns are generally establishments or buildings where travelers can seek lodging and, usually, food and drink. They are typically located in the country or along a highway.[PARAGRAPH:2]Found in Europe, they possibly first sprang up when the Romans built their system of Roman roads two millennia ago. Some inns in Europe are several centuries old. In addition to providing for the needs of travellers, inns traditionally acted as community gathering places.[PARAGRAPH:2]In Europe, it is the provision of accommodation, if anything, that now differentiates inns from taverns, alehouses and pubs. The latter tend only to supply alcohol (although in the UK the conditions of their licence sometimes require them to have a nominal supply of food and soft drinks). Inns tend to be grander and more long-lived establishments. Famous London examples include the George and The Tabard. There is however no longer a formal distinction between an inn and other kinds of establishment, and many pubs will use the name "inn", either simply because they are long established and maybe were once a Coaching inn, or to summon up a particular kind of image; however, originally an Inn had to provide not only food and lodging, but also stabling and fodder for the traveller's horse(s) and for fresh horses for the Mail coach.[PARAGRAPH:2]The original functions of an inn are now usually split among separate establishments, such as hotels, lodges, and motels, all of which might provide the traditional functions of an inn but which focus more on lodging customers than on other services; public houses, which are primarily alcohol-serving establishments; and restaurants and taverns, which serve food and drink. (Hotels often contain restaurants and also often serve complimentary breakfast and meals, thus providing all of the functions of traditional inns.) In North America, the lodging aspect of the word "inn" lives on in hotel brand names like Holiday Inn, and in some state laws that refer to lodging operators as innkeepers.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]客栈通常是旅行者可以在其中寻求住宿，通常是食物和饮料的场所或建筑物。它们通常位于乡村或公路沿线。[第2段]发现于欧洲，可能是在两千年前罗马人修建罗马道路系统时首先出现的。欧洲的一些客栈已有几个世纪的历史。除了满足旅行者的需求外，客栈传统上还充当着社区聚会场所。[第2段]在欧洲，正是提供住宿（如果有的话），使客栈区别于酒馆、酒馆和酒吧。后者往往只供应酒精（尽管在英国，他们的执照条件有时要求他们有食品和软饮料的名义供应）。客栈往往是更宏伟和更长寿的机构。伦敦著名的例子包括乔治和塔巴德。然而，客栈和其他类型的设施之间不再有正式的区别，许多酒吧将使用“客栈”的名称，或者仅仅因为它们已经建立很久，可能曾经是一个教练客栈，或者是为了唤起一种特殊的形象；然而，最初的客栈不仅要提供食物和住宿，但同时也为旅行者的马和邮车的新马提供马厩和饲料。[第2段]旅馆最初的功能现在通常被分成不同的机构，如旅馆、旅馆和汽车旅馆，所有这些都可能提供客栈的传统功能，但它们更多地关注住宿客户，而不是其他服务；公共房屋，主要是提供酒精饮料的设施；餐馆和酒馆，提供食物和饮料。（酒店通常包含餐厅，还经常提供免费早餐和餐食，从而提供传统酒店的所有功能。）在北美，“酒店”一词的住宿方面以酒店品牌（如Holiday inn）为基础，在一些州法律中将住宿经营者称为酒店管理者。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEXTILE_MILL</Tag>
    <English>Textile Mill</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>纺织厂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEXTILE_MILL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Textile manufacturing is a major industry. It is based in the conversion of three types of fibre into yarn, then fabric, then textiles. These are then fabricated into clothes or other artifacts. Cotton remains the most important natural fibre, so is treated in depth. There are many variable processes available at the spinning and fabric-forming stages coupled with the complexities of the finishing and colouration processes to the production of a wide ranges of products. There remains a large industry that uses hand techniques to achieve the same results.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]纺织制造业是一个主要产业。它的基础是将三种纤维转变成纱线，然后是织物，然后是纺织品。然后将其制成衣服或其他工艺品。棉花仍然是最重要的天然纤维，因此经过深度处理。在纺纱和织物成型阶段有许多可变的工艺，加上整理和染色工艺的复杂性，可以生产各种各样的产品。仍然有一个大的行业使用手工技术来达到同样的效果。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWELER</Tag>
    <English>Jeweler</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>宝石商店</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWELER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The first signs of established jewellery making in Ancient Egypt was around 3,000-5,000 years ago. he Egyptians preferred the luxury, rarity, and workability of gold over other metals. Predynastic Egypt had Jewellery in Egypt soon began to symbolize power and religious power in the community. Although it was worn by wealthy Egyptians in life, it was also worn by them in death, with jewellery commonly placed among grave goods.[PARAGRAPH:2]In conjunction with gold jewellery, Egyptians used coloured glass in place of precious gems. Although the Egyptians had access to gemstones, they preferred the colours they could create in glass over the natural colours of stones. For nearly each gemstone, there was a glass formulation used by the Egyptians to mimic it. The colour of the jewellery was very important, as different colours meant different things; the Book of the Dead dictated that the necklace of Isis around a mummys neck must be red to satisfy Isiss need for blood, while green jewellery meant new growth for crops and fertility. Although lapis lazuli and silver had to be imported from beyond the countrys borders, most other materials for jewellery were found in or near Egypt, for example in the Red Sea, where the Egyptians mined Cleopatra's favourite gem, the emerald. Egyptian jewellery was predominantly made in large workshops attached to temples or palaces.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]古埃及制造珠宝的第一个标志是大约3000-5000年前。埃及人更喜欢黄金的奢华、稀有和易加工性。前犹太时代的埃及在埃及有珠宝，很快就开始象征社会中的权力和宗教权力。虽然它是富有的埃及人在生活中佩戴的，但它也被他们在死亡时佩戴，珠宝通常放在坟墓物品中。[第2段]与黄金珠宝一起，埃及人使用有色玻璃代替珍贵的宝石。虽然埃及人可以获得宝石，但他们更喜欢用玻璃制造的颜色，而不是石头的自然颜色。几乎每一块宝石都有一种玻璃配方，埃及人用来模仿它。珠宝的颜色非常重要，因为不同的颜色意味着不同的东西；《死亡之书》规定，伊西斯围绕木乃伊脖子的项链必须是红色，以满足伊西斯对血液的需求，而绿色珠宝则意味着农作物和生育能力的新增长。尽管青金石和银必须从境外进口，但大多数其他珠宝材料都是在埃及境内或附近发现的，例如在红海，埃及人在那里开采埃及艳后最喜爱的宝石绿宝石。埃及珠宝主要是在附属于寺庙或宫殿的大型作坊中制作的。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SMOKEHOUSE</Tag>
    <English>Smokehouse</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>熏制所</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SMOKEHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A smokehouse is a building where meat or fish is cured with smoke. The finished product might be stored in the building, sometimes for a year or more.[PARAGRAPH:2]Traditional smokehouses served both as meat smokers and to store the meats, often for groups and communities of people. Food preservation occurred by salt curing and extended cold smoking for two weeks or longer. Smokehouses were often secured to prevent animals and thieves from accessing the food.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]熏房是用烟熏肉或鱼的建筑物。成品可能会存放在大楼里，有时会存放一年或更长时间。[第2段]传统的烟房既可以吸食肉类，也可以储存肉类，通常是为群体和社区的人。食物保存是通过盐腌制和长时间冷吸烟两周或更长时间来实现的。为了防止动物和窃贼接近食物，烟房经常被保护起来。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STAR_FORT</Tag>
    <English>Star Fort</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>星堡</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A star fort, or trace italienne, is a fortification in the style that evolved during the age of gunpowder, when cannon came to dominate the battlefield, and was first seen in the mid-15th century in Italy. Passive ring-shaped (enceinte) fortifications of the Medieval era proved vulnerable to damage or destruction by cannon fire, when it could be directed from outside against a perpendicular masonry wall. In addition, an attacking force that could get close to the wall was able to conduct undermining operations in relative safety, as the defenders could not shoot at them from nearby walls. In contrast, the star fortress was a very flat structure composed of many triangular bastions, specifically designed to cover each other, and a ditch. Further structures, such as ravelins, hornworks or crownworks, and detached forts could be added to create a complex symmetrical structure.[PARAGRAPH:2]Star fortifications were further developed in the late fifteenth and early sixteenth centuries primarily in response to the French invasion of the Italian peninsula. The French army was equipped with new cannon and bombards that were easily able to destroy traditional fortifications built in the Middle Ages. In order to counteract the power of the new weapons, defensive walls were made lower and thicker. They were built of many materials, usually earth and brick, as brick does not shatter on impact from a cannonball as does stone. Another important design modification were the bastions that characterized the new fortresses. In order to improve the defense of the fortress, covering fire had to be provided, often from multiple angles. The result was the development of star-shaped fortresses.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]星堡，或称trace italienne，是在火药时代发展起来的一种防御工事，当时大炮在战场上占主导地位，15世纪中叶在意大利首次出现。中世纪被动式环形防御工事被证明很容易受到炮火的破坏或破坏，因为炮火可以从外部指向垂直的砖墙。此外，一支能够接近隔离墙的攻击部队能够在相对安全的情况下进行破坏行动，因为防御者不能从附近的隔离墙向他们射击。相比之下，星堡则是一个非常平坦的结构，由许多三角形的堡垒和一条沟渠组成，专门设计用来相互覆盖。进一步的结构，如渡鸦、角铁或皇冠，以及独立的堡垒，可以被添加到一个复杂的对称结构中。[第2段]恒星防御工事在15世纪末和16世纪初进一步发展，主要是为了应对法国对意大利半岛的入侵。法国军队装备了新的大炮和炮弹，能够轻易摧毁中世纪建造的传统防御工事。为了抵消新武器的威力，防御墙变得越来越低，越来越厚。它们是用许多材料建造的，通常是泥土和砖块，因为砖块不会像石头一样在炮弹的撞击下破碎。另一个重要的设计修改是堡垒的特点，新的堡垒。为了加强堡垒的防御，必须提供掩护火力，通常是从多个角度。其结果是发展了星形堡垒。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WAREHOUSE</Tag>
    <English>Warehouse</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>贮藏库</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WAREHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A warehouse is a commercial building for storage of goods. Warehouses are used by manufacturers, importers, exporters, wholesalers, transport businesses, customs, etc. They are usually large plain buildings in industrial areas of cities and towns. They usually have loading docks to load and unload goods from trucks. Sometimes warehouses load and unload goods directly from railways, airports, or seaports. They often have cranes and forklifts for moving goods, which are usually placed on ISO standard pallets loaded into pallet racks.[PARAGRAPH:2]Stored goods can include any raw materials, components, or finished goods associated with agriculture, manufacturing, or commerce.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]仓库是用来储存货物的商业建筑。仓库被制造商、进口商、出口商、批发商、运输企业、海关等使用，通常是城镇工业区的大型平原建筑。他们通常有装卸卡车货物的装卸台。有时仓库直接从铁路、机场或海港装卸货物。他们通常有起重机和叉车来搬运货物，这些货物通常放在装载到托盘架上的ISO标准托盘上。[第2段]储存的货物可以包括任何与农业、制造业或商业有关的原材料、部件或制成品。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COFFEE_HOUSE</Tag>
    <English>Coffee House</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>咖啡馆</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COFFEE_HOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A coffeehouse or coffee shop is an establishment which primarily serves prepared coffee or other hot beverages. It shares some of the characteristics of a bar, and some of the characteristics of a restaurant, but it is different from a cafeteria. As the name suggests, coffeehouses focus on providing coffee and tea as well as light snacks. Many coffee houses in the Middle East, and in West Asian immigrant districts in the Western world, offer shisha (nargile in Turkish and Greek), flavored tobacco smoked through a hookah.[PARAGRAPH:2]From a cultural standpoint, coffeehouses largely serve as centers of social interaction: the coffeehouse provides social members with a place to congregate, talk, write, read, entertain one another, or pass the time, whether individually or in small groups of 2 or 3.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]咖啡厅或咖啡厅是主要提供咖啡或其他热饮料的场所。它有酒吧的一些特点，也有餐馆的一些特点，但它不同于自助餐厅。顾名思义，咖啡馆专注于提供咖啡、茶和小吃。中东的许多咖啡馆，以及西方世界的西亚移民区，都提供什刹（土耳其语和希腊语为nargile），用水烟吸食的香料烟草，咖啡馆在很大程度上是社会互动的中心：咖啡馆为社会成员提供了一个聚会、交谈、写作、阅读、娱乐或消磨时间的场所，无论是单独的还是2或3人组成的小组。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUXURY_STORE</Tag>
    <English>Luxury Store</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>奢侈品商店</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUXURY_STORE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Luxury Store is a place where people can acquire products and services that are not considered essential and associated with affluence. These are most commonly called luxury goods.[PARAGRAPH:2]The concept of luxury has been present in various forms since the beginning of civilization. Its role was just as important in ancient western and eastern empires as it is in modern societies. With the clear differences between social classes in earlier civilizations, the consumption of luxury was limited to the elite classes. It also meant the definition of luxury was fairly clear. Whatever the poor cannot have and the elite can was identified as luxury.[PARAGRAPH:2]Later though, with increasing 'democratization', several new product categories were created within the luxury market which were aptly called: accessible luxury or mass luxury. This kind of luxury specifically targeted the middle class (or what is sometimes termed as aspiring class). As luxury penetrated into the masses, defining luxury has become difficult.[PARAGRAPH:2]One things remains clear: luxury evokes a sense of belonging to a certain elite group. Thus, there always was, and always will be need for luxury goods in all civilizations.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]奢侈品商店是人们可以获得不被认为是必需的、与富裕相关的产品和服务的地方。这些都是最常见的奢侈品。[第2段]自文明开始以来，奢侈品的概念就以各种形式出现。它在古代西方和东方帝国中的作用和在现代社会中的作用一样重要。由于早期文明社会阶层之间存在明显差异，奢侈品的消费仅限于精英阶层。这也意味着奢侈品的定义相当明确。无论穷人不能拥有什么，而精英阶层可以被认定为奢侈品。[第2段]后来，随着“民主化”的加剧，奢侈品市场上出现了几个新的产品类别，它们被恰当地称为：无障碍奢侈品或大众奢侈品。这种奢侈品专门针对中产阶级（或有时被称为有抱负的阶级）。随着奢侈品深入大众，定义奢侈品变得困难了。[第2段]有一件事仍然很清楚：奢侈品唤起了一种属于某个精英群体的感觉。因此，在所有文明中，奢侈品的需求一直存在，而且将永远存在。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORGE</Tag>
    <English>Blacksmith</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>铁匠铺</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A forge is a furnace where metal is heated or melted. In ancient times smiths with small forges could be found in most settlements. The furnaces were stoked with coal, which was fanned by manually pumped bellows to create intense heat. The blacksmith would heat the metal in the oven and then shape it by putting the metal on an anvil and beating it with heavy hammers. The finished product was then put into cold water to harden and cool. The smith might also melt the metal and pour it into molds.[PARAGRAPH:2]Modern forges are huge industrial structures requiring many workers to operate. The operation is similar to that in the smithy; except on a grand scale. Tons of ore are poured into massive vats, which are conveyed into the furnace. Once the metal is smelted, it may be mixed with other materials to create an alloy such as steel, and it may undergo a number of different processes to remove impurities. The finished metal can then be rolled into sheets, poured into molds, stamped into coins, and so forth.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>锻造炉是金属被加热或熔化的熔炉。在古代，铁匠和小锻造可以在大多数定居点找到。炉子里加了煤，煤通过手动泵送的风箱扇动，产生强烈的热量。铁匠会在烤箱里加热金属，然后把金属放在铁砧上，用重锤敲打，使其成形。然后将成品放入冷水中硬化和冷却。铁匠也可能熔化金属并将其倒入模具中。这次行动与铁匠铺的相似，只是规模宏大。成吨的矿石被倒入巨大的大桶中，然后被输送到熔炉中。一旦金属被熔炼，它可能会与其他材料混合以形成合金，如钢，并且它可能会经历许多不同的过程来去除杂质。然后，成品金属可以卷成薄片，倒入模具，冲压成硬币，等等。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOTHECARY</Tag>
    <English>Apothecary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>药剂室</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOTHECARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Apothecary is a historical name for a medical professional (it's also the name of his business establishment) who formulates and dispenses materia medica to physicians, surgeons and patients - a role now served by a pharmacist. In addition to pharmacy responsibilities, the apothecary offered general medical advice and a range of services that are now performed solely by other specialist practitioners, such as surgery and midwifery.[PARAGRAPH:2]Apothecaries often operated through a retail shop which, in addition to ingredients for medicines, sold tobacco and patent medicines. In its investigation of herbal and chemical ingredients, the work of an apothecary may be regarded as a precursor of the modern sciences of chemistry and pharmacology, prior to the formulation of the scientific method.[PARAGRAPH:2]According to Sharif Kaf al-Ghazal, Jolyn Carter, and S. Hadzovic, the first apothecary shops were founded during the Middle Ages in Baghdad. The first one was founded by Muslim pharmacists in 754, during the Abbasid Caliphate, or Islamic Golden Age. Apothecaries were also active in Islamic Spain by the 11th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the end of the 14th century, Geoffrey Chaucer (1342-1400) was mentioning an English apothecary in the Canterbury Tales, specifically "The Nun's Priest's Tale". Another famous mention of an apothecary appears in William Shakespeare's play Romeo and Juliet, in which a poor apothecary sells Romeo an elixir of death with which Romeo commits suicide.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the 15th century, the apothecary gained the status of a skilled practitioner, but by the end of the 19th century, the medical professions had taken on their current institutional form, with defined roles for physicians and surgeons, and the role of the apothecary was more narrowly conceived as that of pharmacist.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]药剂师是一个专业的医生（也是他的公司名称）的历史名称，他为医生、外科医生和病人制定和分发药物，现在由药剂师担任这个角色。除了药房的职责外，药剂师还提供一般的医疗建议和一系列服务，现在这些服务都是由其他专业医生单独提供的，例如外科和助产师。[第2段]药剂师通常通过零售店经营，除了药品成分外，出售烟草和专利药品。在对草药和化学成分的研究中，在制定科学方法之前，药剂师的工作可以被视为现代化学和药理学科学的先驱。[第2段]根据谢里夫・卡夫・加扎尔、乔琳・卡特和S.Hadzovic，第一家药剂师商店是中世纪在巴格达建立的。第一个是由穆斯林药剂师在754年，阿巴斯哈里发时期，或伊斯兰黄金时代建立的。到11世纪，药剂师在伊斯兰西班牙也很活跃。[第2段]到14世纪末，杰弗里乔叟（1342-1400）在坎特伯雷故事中提到了一位英国药剂师，特别是“修女的牧师故事”。威廉・莎士比亚的戏剧《罗密欧与朱丽叶》中又提到了一位药剂师，一位贫穷的药剂师向罗密欧出售了一种不治之症，罗密欧因此自杀，医疗行业已经采取了目前的体制形式，医生和外科医生的角色已经明确，而药剂师的角色被狭义地理解为药剂师的角色。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INFIRMARY</Tag>
    <English>Infirmary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>医院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INFIRMARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Infirmary is a place for the care of the infirm, sick, or injured. In the Middle Ages, infirmaries were often attached to monasteries, with care provided by monks and nuns. Additionally, they could also serve as almhouses or refuges for pilgrims.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]医务室是一个照顾体弱、生病或受伤的人的地方。在中世纪，医务室通常附属于修道院，由僧侣和尼姑提供护理。此外，它们还可以作为朝圣者的避难所或避难所。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KONTOR</Tag>
    <English>Kontor</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>汉萨同盟商站</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KONTOR_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The kontor was a foreign trading post of the Hanseatic League, which was established in most bigger cities of the League. In addition to the major kontore in London (Steelyard), Ipswich, Bruges, Bergen (Bryggen), and Novgorod (Peterhof), some ports had a representative merchant and a warehouse.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of all the kontor buildings, only Bergen's kontor, known as Bryggen in Norway, has survived until the present day. The Hanseatic kontor at Bryggen was closed in 1754 and replaced by a "Norwegian kontor", run by Norwegian citizens, but still with a large element of German immigrants. Bergen's kontor is on the UNESCO list of the World Cultural Heritage sites. The building of the Hanseatic Warehouse in King's Lynn, England, also survived - but it was converted into offices in 1971.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]康托是汉萨同盟的一个对外贸易站，汉萨同盟在同盟的大多数大城市都建立了。除了伦敦的康托尔少校（钢厂）、伊普斯维奇、布鲁日、伯根（布莱根）和诺夫哥罗德（彼得霍夫），一些港口还有一个代表性的商人和一个仓库。[第2段]在所有康托尔建筑中，只有伯根的康托尔，即挪威的布莱根，幸存至今。布莱根的汉萨文化馆于1754年关闭，取而代之的是挪威公民经营的“挪威文化馆”，但仍有大量德国移民。卑尔根的康托被联合国教科文组织列入世界文化遗产名录。英国林恩国王汉萨仓库的建筑也幸存了下来，但它在1971年被改建成了办公室。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- General Buildings -->
  <!-- Religious Buildings -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_SHRINE</Tag>
    <English>Pagan Shrine</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>异教神社</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Paganism (from Latin paganus, meaning "country dweller, rustic") is a word used to refer to various religions and religious beliefs from across the world. It is a term which, from a Western perspective, has modern connotations of spiritualist, animistic or shamanic practices or beliefs of any folk religion, and of historical and contemporary polytheistic religions in particular.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>异教徒（来自拉丁异教徒，意思是“乡下人，乡下人”）是一个词，用来指来自世界各地的各种宗教和宗教信仰。这是一个术语，从西方的角度来看，它具有任何民间宗教，特别是历史和当代多神论宗教的灵性、万物有灵论或萨满实践或信仰的现代内涵。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_SHRINE_HELP</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]Requires [LINK=literal]Paganism[\LINK]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]需要[LINK=literal]异教徒[\LINK]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_QUARTER</Tag>
    <English>Jewish Quarter</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>犹太区</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_QUARTER_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In the Jewish Diaspora, a Jewish quarter is the area of a city traditionally inhabited by Jews. Jewish quarters, like the Jewish ghettos in Europe, were often the outgrowths of segregated ghettos instituted by the surrounding Christian authorities. A Yiddish term for a Jewish quarter or neighborhood is "Di yiddishe gas", or "The Jewish street". Many European and Middle Eastern cities once had a historical Jewish quarter and some still have it.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Jewish ghettos existed because Jews were viewed as that they were foreigners due to their non-Christian beliefs in a Renaissance Christian environment. As a result, Jews were placed under strict regulations throughout many European cities. The character of ghettos has varied through times. In some cases, the ghetto was a Jewish quarter with a relatively affluent population (for instance the Jewish ghetto in Venice). In other cases, ghettos were places of terrible poverty and during periods of population growth, ghettos had narrow streets and tall, crowded houses. Residents had their own justice system. Around the ghetto stood walls that, during pogroms, were closed from inside to protect the community, but from the outside during Christmas, Pesach, and Easter Week to prevent the Jews from leaving during those times.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]在犹太人散居区，犹太人聚居区是犹太人传统居住的城市区域。犹太人聚居区，就像欧洲的犹太人聚居区一样，往往是由周围基督教当局建立的隔离聚居区的产物。意第绪语中犹太人居住区或社区的一个术语是“Di yiddishe gas”，或“犹太街”。许多欧洲和中东城市曾经有一个历史上的犹太人聚居区，但有些城市仍然有这个聚居区。[第2段]犹太人聚居区的存在是因为犹太人在文艺复兴时期的基督教环境中的非基督教信仰被视为外国人。因此，犹太人在欧洲许多城市都受到严格的管制。贫民区的性质随着时代的变化而变化。在某些情况下，犹太人聚居区是犹太人聚居区，人口相对富裕（例如威尼斯的犹太人聚居区）。在其他情况下，贫民区是极度贫困的地方，在人口增长时期，贫民区有狭窄的街道和高大拥挤的房屋。居民有自己的司法系统。犹太人聚居区周围矗立着围墙，在大屠杀期间，这些围墙是从内部封闭的，以保护社区，但在圣诞节、比沙克和复活节周期间，这些围墙是从外部封闭的，以防止犹太人在那段时间离开。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_QUARTER_HELP</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]Less instability from [LINK=literal]Judaism[\LINK]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]来自犹太教的[LINK=literal]较少的不稳定性[\LINK]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_TEMPLE</Tag>
    <English>Islamic Mosque</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>伊斯兰清真寺</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A mosque is a place of worship for followers of Islam. The word entered the English language most likely through French (mosque), from Spanish (mezquita), from Berber (tamezgida), ultimately originating in Arabic: masjid. The Arabic word masjid literally means a place of prostration. The word "mosque" in English refers to all types of buildings dedicated for Islamic worship, although there is a distinction in Arabic between the smaller masjid dedicated for the daily five prayers and the larger masjid jami where the daily five prayers and the Friday congregation sermons are held with a high volume of attendence. The masjid jami also plays more roles such as teaching Qur'an and educating future imams.[PARAGRAPH:2]The mosque serves as a place where Muslims can come together for salat (prayer) as well as a center for information, education, and dispute settlement. The Imam leads the prayer.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>清真寺是伊斯兰教信徒的礼拜场所。这个词最有可能是通过法语（mosque）、西班牙语（mezquita）、柏柏尔语（tamezgida）进入英语的，最终起源于阿拉伯语：masjid。阿拉伯语单词masjid字面意思是一个拜倒的地方。英语中的“清真寺”一词指的是所有类型的伊斯兰礼拜建筑，尽管在阿拉伯语中有一个区别，即较小的清真寺每天为五个祈祷，较大的清真寺每天为五个祈祷和星期五的会众布道举行了大量的出席。清真寺还扮演着更多的角色，比如教导古兰经和教育未来的伊玛目。[第2段]清真寺是穆斯林聚集在一起祈祷的地方，也是信息、教育和解决争端的中心。伊玛目领导祈祷。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CHAPEL</Tag>
    <English>Islamic Minaret</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>伊斯兰宣礼塔</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CHAPEL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Minarets are distinctive architectural features of Islamic mosques. Minarets are generally tall spires with onion-shaped crowns, usually either free standing or much taller than any surrounding support structure. As well as providing a visual cue to a Muslim community, the main function of the minaret is to provide a vantage point from which the muezzin can call out the adhan, calling the faithful to prayer.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>尖塔是伊斯兰清真寺独特的建筑特征。尖塔通常是带有洋葱形冠的高尖塔，通常是独立的，或者比周围的支撑结构高很多。除了向穆斯林社区提供视觉提示外，宣礼塔的主要功能是提供一个有利的位置，穆埃津可以从这里召唤出adhan，召唤信徒祈祷。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_MADRASSA</Tag>
    <English>Islamic Madrassa</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>伊斯兰学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_MADRASSA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A "madrassa" is an Arabic institute of higher learning, usually religious in nature. The earliest madrasses were formed in Islamic mosques, where scholars gathered to study and debate religious and secular issues of the day. Over time students would come to study with the most learned scholars; the most popular teachers often had to construct separate buildings to hold their growing student population.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At the madrassas the students would learn to read and write and study religious doctrine, history and law. Some madrassas also taught logic, world history, foreign language, mathematics, art and science. Since state-run colleges and universities did not appear until later in history, the madrassas were critical centers of learning in many early Arabic cities.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>“宗教学校”是阿拉伯的高等学府，通常是宗教性质的。最早的宗教学校形成于伊斯兰清真寺，学者们聚集在那里研究和辩论当时的宗教和世俗问题。随着时间的推移，学生们将与最有学问的学者一起学习；最受欢迎的教师常常不得不建造单独的建筑物来容纳他们不断增长的学生群体。[新线][新线]在宗教学校，学生们将学习读写和学习宗教教义、历史和法律。一些宗教学校还教授逻辑、世界历史、外语、数学、艺术和科学。由于国立学院和大学直到后来才出现在历史上，伊斯兰学校是许多早期阿拉伯城市的重要学习中心。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
    <English>Islamic Grand Mosque</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>大清真寺</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]"Great Mosque" refers to a large mosque, resembling a Christian cathedral in size and significance. Examples of such mosques include the Grand Mosque of Damascus, the Great Mosque of Algiers or the Sultan Ahmed Mosque of Istanbul.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>“大清真寺”指的是一座大型清真寺，在规模和意义上类似于基督教大教堂。这些清真寺的例子包括大马士革大清真寺、阿尔及尔大清真寺或伊斯坦布尔苏丹艾哈迈德清真寺。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>House of Wisdom</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>智慧之家</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_SCHOOL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The House of Wisdom was a library and translation institute in Abbassid-era Baghdad. It was a key institution in the Translation Movement and considered to have been a major intellectual center of the Islamic Golden Age. The House of Wisdom acted as a society founded by Abbasid caliphs Harun al-Rashid and his son al-Ma'mun who reigned from 813-833 CE. Based in Baghdad from the 9th to 13th centuries, many of the most learned Muslim scholars were part of this excellent research and educational institute.[PARAGRAPH:2]The term house of wisdom is a direct translation of Persian Sassanians' designation for a library. It was modeled on that of the Sassanians, had the purpose of translating books from Persian to Arabic, and also of preservation of translated books. The House was an unrivalled centre for the study of humanities and for sciences, including mathematics, astronomy, medicine, chemistry, zoology and geography. Drawing on Persian, Indian and Greek texts - including those of Pythagoras, Plato, Aristotle, Hippocrates, Euclid, Plotinus, Galen, Sushruta, Charaka, Aryabhata, Socrates and Brahmagupta - the scholars accumulated a great collection of world knowledge, and built on it through their own discoveries. The great scholars of the House of Wisdom included Al-Khawarizmi, the "father" of algebra, which takes its name from his book Kitab al-Jabr.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]智慧之家是阿巴斯时代巴格达的一个图书馆和翻译机构。它是翻译运动中的一个重要机构，被认为是伊斯兰黄金时代的一个主要的知识中心。智慧之家是由阿巴斯哈里发哈伦・拉希德和他的儿子阿尔・马门（al-Ma'mun）在公元813-833年统治的一个社会。在巴格达，从9世纪到13世纪，许多最有学问的穆斯林学者都是这个优秀的研究和教育机构的一部分。[第2段]智慧之家一词是波斯萨珊人对图书馆的命名的直接翻译。它仿照萨珊人的风格，目的是把书从波斯语翻译成阿拉伯语，同时也保存翻译过的书。这所房子是一个无与伦比的人文和科学研究中心，包括数学、天文学、医学、化学、动物学和地理。学者们借鉴了波斯、印度和希腊的文献，包括毕达哥拉斯、柏拉图、亚里士多德、希波克拉底、欧几里得、普罗提努斯、加伦、苏苏鲁塔、查拉卡、阿里亚巴塔、苏格拉底和布拉马古塔的文献，积累了大量的世界知识，并通过自己的发现建立在这些知识之上。智慧之家的伟大学者包括代数之父哈瓦里兹米（Al-Khawarizmi），他的名字来源于他的著作Kitab Al-Jabr。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_TEMPLE</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Church</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教会</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_CHAPEL</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Belfry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教钟塔</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_MONASTERY</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Monastery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教修道院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Cathedral</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教大教堂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_RELIQUARY</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Reliquary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教圣物柜</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Cathedral School</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教会学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_SCRIPTORIUM</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Scriptorium</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教缮写室</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHOLIC_SEMINARY</Tag>
    <English>Catholic Seminary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>天主教神学院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_TEMPLE</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Church</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教会</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_CHAPEL</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Belfry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教钟塔</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_MONASTERY</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Monastery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教修道院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Cathedral</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教大教堂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_RELIQUARY</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Reliquary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教圣物柜</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Cathedral School</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教会学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_SCRIPTORIUM</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Scriptorium</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教缮写室</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORTHODOX_SEMINARY</Tag>
    <English>Orthodox Seminary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>东正教神学院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_TEMPLE</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Church</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教会</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_CHAPEL</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Belfry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教钟塔</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_MONASTERY</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Monastery</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教修道院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_CATHEDRAL</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Cathedral</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教大教堂</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Church School</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教会学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_SEMINARY</Tag>
    <English>Protestant Seminary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>新教神学院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A temple is a building or structure whose primary purpose is to facilitate the meeting of a church. Originally, Jewish Christians met in synagogues, such as the Cenacle, and in one another's homes. As Christianity grew and became more accepted by governments, rooms and, eventually, entire buildings were set aside for the explicit purpose of Christian worship.[PARAGRAPH:2]Traditional church buildings are often in the shape of a cross and frequently have a tower or dome. More modern church buildings have a variety of architectural styles and layouts; many buildings that were designed for other purposes have now been converted for church use, and, similarly, many original church buildings have been put to other uses.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]寺庙是一种建筑或结构，其主要目的是促进教堂的会合。最初，犹太基督教徒在犹太教堂，如塞纳克尔，以及在彼此的家中相遇。随着基督教的发展，并越来越被政府接受，房间和最终，整个建筑物都被放置在基督教礼拜的明确目的。[第2段]传统的教堂建筑往往是一个十字架的形状，经常有一个塔或圆顶。较现代的教堂建筑有多种建筑风格和布局；许多为其他目的设计的建筑现在已改为供教堂使用，同样，许多原来的教堂建筑也被用于其他用途。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_CHAPEL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A belfry, or simply bell tower, is a tower which contains one or more bells, or which is designed to hold bells, even if it has none. In the European tradition, such a tower most commonly serves as part of a church and contains church bells.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[TAB]钟楼，或简称钟楼，是指包含一个或多个钟楼，或设计用于容纳钟楼，即使没有钟楼。在欧洲的传统中，这样的塔通常是教堂的一部分，里面有教堂的钟声。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, that houses a room reserved for prayer (e.g. an oratory) as well as the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits).[PARAGRAPH:2]Monasteries may vary greatly in size - a small dwelling accommodating only a hermit, or in the case of communities anything from a single building housing only a one senior and two or three junior monks or nuns, to vast complexes and estates housing tens or hundreds.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]修道院指的是为祈祷而保留的房间（如演讲室）以及僧侣（无论僧侣或尼姑）的家庭住所和工作场所的建筑物或建筑群，无论是居住在社区还是单独居住（隐士）。[第2款]修道院的规模可能有很大的不同――一个仅容纳隐士的小住宅，或者在社区的情况下，从一栋仅容纳一名高级僧侣和两名或三名初级僧侣或尼姑的建筑，到容纳数十或数百名僧侣或尼姑的大型综合体和庄园。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A cathedral is a church housing the seat of a bishop. Cathedrals were built in the largest towns and cities, to act as centers of religious study and worship. In addition to their religious significance, cathedrals acted as the center of social and cultural activity in the town. They brought great pride, stability, and tradition to the citizens of the community.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]大教堂是主教所在地的教堂。大教堂建在最大的城镇，作为宗教研究和礼拜的中心。除了宗教意义外，大教堂还是该镇社会和文化活动的中心。他们给社区居民带来了极大的骄傲、稳定和传统。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_RELIQUARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A reliquary is a container for relics. These may be the physical remains of saints, such as bones, pieces of clothing, or some object associated with saints or other religious figures.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[标签]圣骨箱是存放文物的容器。这些可能是圣人的身体遗骸，如骨头、衣服或与圣人或其他宗教人物有关的物品。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_SEMINARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]A seminary, theological college, or divinity school is a specialized education institution for the purpose of instructing students (seminarians) in philosophy, theology, spirituality and the religious life, usually in order to prepare them to become members of the clergy.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[表]神学院、神学院或神学院是专门教育学生（神学院）哲学、神学、灵性和宗教生活的机构，通常是为了使他们成为神职人员。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROTESTANT_SCHOOL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In the Late Middle Ages, and especially after the start of the Renaissance, the need was growing for some kind of a basic public education. Early on, the religious communities were the perfect place to distribute knowledge among the more common people. The biggest difference from previous religious buildings is that these schools were open to everyone, not only for monks and other members of the clergy. Religious Schools were very common among Protestant communities.</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
      <Chinese>[表]在中世纪晚期，特别是文艺复兴开始后，人们越来越需要某种基本的公共教育。早期，宗教团体是向更普通的人传播知识的最佳场所。与以往的宗教建筑最大的不同是，这些学校对所有人开放，不仅对僧侣和其他神职人员开放。宗教学校在新教徒社区中非常普遍。</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_CHAPEL</Tag>
    <English>Belfry</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>钟塔</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_RELIQUARY</Tag>
    <English>Reliquary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>圣物柜</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_SCHOOL</Tag>
    <English>Religious School</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>宗教学校</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_SEMINARY</Tag>
    <English>Seminary</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>神学院</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALBUILDING_SCRIPTORIUM</Tag>
    <English>Scriptorium</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>缮写室</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Religious Buildings -->
  <!-- Other -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STABILITY_HELP</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]+1 Stability</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]+1稳定</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DAMAGE_ABILITY</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]Damages enemy units in your nearby territory</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]伤害你附近地区的敌人单位</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BOMBARD_IMMUNE_DEFENSE</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod% Defense (Cannot be Broken by Bombardment)</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod% 防御 (不能被轰炸)</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BUILDING_COMBO_BUILDING_INFO1</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_GOLD] </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_GOLD] </Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BUILDING_COMBO_BUILDING_INFO2</Tag>
    <English>with [LINK=literal]%s1_Building[\LINK]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>使用 [LINK=literal]%s1_Building[\LINK]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_STATE_RELIGION_CULTURE1</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] </English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] </Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_STATE_RELIGION_CULTURE2</Tag>
    <English>with [LINK=literal]%s1_Religion[\LINK]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>使用 [LINK=literal]%s1_Religion[\LINK]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_PAGAN_CULTURE_PER_CITY</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] per city, if you don't have a State Religion</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] 每个城市, 如果你没有国教</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_PAGAN_CULTURE</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] without a State Religion</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod[ICON_CULTURE] 没有国教</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_REQUIRES_CIVIC</Tag>
    <English>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]Requires [LINK=literal]%s1[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT]</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]要求 [LINK=literal]%s1[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT]</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_INTEREST_RATE</Tag>
    <English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod % interest added to your [ICON_GOLD] at the beginning of every turn</English>
    <L1/>
    <L2/>
    <L3/>
    <L4/>
     <Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod % 利息进入到您的 [ICON_GOLD] 在每回合开始的时候</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Other -->
</Civ4GameText>
