<?xml version="1.0" encoding="GB2312"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by XMLSPY 2004 Professional Ed. Release 2, Installed Multi + SMP for 3 users (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - RFCE Civilizations -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
  <!-- Civilization Burgundy -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Burgundians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>勃艮第文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Burgundy</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>勃艮第</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Burgundian:Burgundians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>勃艮第</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BURGUNDY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Duchy of Burgundy, with origins in the Roman Empire, was a political entity that at its peak spread from what is today southwestern France, to central France, Belgium and the southern Netherlands. A center of trade, art, thought, and military power, it was at the center of conflict amongst the Kingdoms of France, Spain, Austria, and the Holy Roman Empire; as an independent entity, at times the Duchy rivaled the powers that coveted it.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through political intrigue, fortuitous marriages, financial power, and military strength, the early dukes and kings of Burgundy controlled a wealthy area of Gaul, including much of Provence, Switzerland, Franche-Comt? and the current Rgion de Bourgogne. After battles both martial and legal, Burgundy became nominally a fief of the France. As such a large and wealthy province, Burgundian dukes often rivaled and surpassed their feudal lords: the landed nobility had little interest in becoming a mere French province, and Burgundy flourished as a mostly independent state.[PARAGRAPH:2]Plague in the mid 14th century left Burgundy in a crisis of sucession, but with the outcome of a strong and capable Valois dynasty. Friendly but not subservient to the kings of France, the Valois brought the Duchy's golden age. During this period the Duchy's power extended into the low countries and presided over the wealthy cities of Dijon, Bruges, Ypres, Luxembourg, Brussels, and Ghent, among others.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Valois, flush with wealth and power, attempted to end the suzerainty of France once and for all, but were defeated. When Duke Charles the Bold died in battle in 1477, the duchy was effectively finished as anything more than a French province.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Duchy of Burgundy, with origins in the Roman Empire, was a political entity that at its peak spread from what is today southwestern France, to central France, Belgium and the southern Netherlands. A center of trade, art, thought, and military power, it was at the center of conflict amongst the Kingdoms of France, Spain, Austria, and the Holy Roman Empire; as an independent entity, at times the Duchy rivaled the powers that coveted it.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through political intrigue, fortuitous marriages, financial power, and military strength, the early dukes and kings of Burgundy controlled a wealthy area of Gaul, including much of Provence, Switzerland, Franche-Comt? and the current Rgion de Bourgogne. After battles both martial and legal, Burgundy became nominally a fief of the France. As such a large and wealthy province, Burgundian dukes often rivaled and surpassed their feudal lords: the landed nobility had little interest in becoming a mere French province, and Burgundy flourished as a mostly independent state.[PARAGRAPH:2]Plague in the mid 14th century left Burgundy in a crisis of sucession, but with the outcome of a strong and capable Valois dynasty. Friendly but not subservient to the kings of France, the Valois brought the Duchy's golden age. During this period the Duchy's power extended into the low countries and presided over the wealthy cities of Dijon, Bruges, Ypres, Luxembourg, Brussels, and Ghent, among others.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Valois, flush with wealth and power, attempted to end the suzerainty of France once and for all, but were defeated. When Duke Charles the Bold died in battle in 1477, the duchy was effectively finished as anything more than a French province.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Burgundy -->
  <!-- Civilization Byzantium -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Byzantines</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>拜占庭文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Byzantium</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>拜占庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Byzantine:Byzantines</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>拜占庭</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Byzantine Empire, centered around the city of Constantinople, was the successor to the Roman Empire. At its height, the Byzantine Empire reached from Persia to Spain, controlling nearly all the territory that felt the lap of the Mediterranean's warm waters.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the Byzantine Empire began and the Roman Empire ceased is a point of much contention. Some historians place the beginning of the Byzantine Empire in 300 AD, when Constantine I moved the capital of the Roman Empire from Rome to a city called Byzantium (later know as Constantinople). Others place the birth of the Byzantine Empire at the end of the reign of Theodosius I, who at his death split the Roman Empire into the Western Empire, ruled from Rome, and the Eastern Empire, ruled from Constantinople.[PARAGRAPH:2]Regardless of historic debate, after the sacking of Rome in 476 AD, the Byzantine Empire was to become the foremost European nation in art, trade and stability - although not necessarily all at once. Taking the throne in 527 AD, Justinian I extended the grip of the Byzantine Empire from Constantinople to the furthest coasts of the Mediterranean Sea. However the Empire would not be able to enjoy the benefits of such territorial expansions for long, as Justinian's successor, Justin II, would begin a trend of placating the various enemies of the Empire - the Sassanid Persians, the Bulgars, and the Arabs, newly organized under Mohammed - with territory in exchange for peace.[PARAGRAPH:2]Territorial losses would continue to weaken the Byzantines until a new lineage of emperors, known as the Macedonian Emperors, arose to invigorate the Empire once again. Basil I founded the Macedonian line in 869. Under the Macedonians, the Byzantine Empire once again began to reach outwards, solidifying its hold on much of the territory neighboring Constantinople. Art flourished in their roughly two centuries of rule, as did the Greek Orthodox Church.[PARAGRAPH:2]The new millennium would be a painful one for Byzantium. Relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church had been deteriorating for many years, and the conflict came to a head with the Great Schism (1054), which finally split the two religions. Militarily, increased assaults by the Seljuk Turks culminated in a resounding defeat for the Empire at the Battle of Manzikert, the Empire losing much of its freshly-gained holdings.[PARAGRAPH:2]But once again, the rise of a powerful new dynasty reversed the Empire's decline. This new dynasty, the Comnenius, sent the call to Western Europe for aid in fighting the Seljuk Turks. Pope Urban II, seeing a chance to reconquer the Holy Lands of Antioch and Jerusalem, as well as halt the squabbling of the European Kings, spread the word for the First Crusade.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through the Crusaders' efforts, the Byzantine Empire regained a portion of its lost territory. But the holy warriors of Western Europe became difficult to control, often threatening to assault the very Empire that had requested their aid. John II and Manuel I, the two most prestigious of the Comnenius emperors, held off the Crusaders and safeguarded the empire from a host of external foes, while ushering in a new era of Byzantine artistic and economic prowess.[PARAGRAPH:2]Manuel I Comnenius was the last great emperor of the Byzantines and the last Comneni. The Angeloi dynasty, successors to the Comneni, proved unable to halt the Empire's slow collapse. In 1204, the knights of the Fourth Crusade, summoned by a disposed Angeloi prince, sacked Constantinople and split the Byzantine Empire into three smaller kingdoms. Nicaea, one of these ex-Byzantine states, recaptured Constantinople years later, but all hopes of reviving the Byzantine Empire would be ended with the capture of the city by the Ottoman leader Mehmed II in 1461.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Byzantine Empire, centered around the city of Constantinople, was the successor to the Roman Empire. At its height, the Byzantine Empire reached from Persia to Spain, controlling nearly all the territory that felt the lap of the Mediterranean's warm waters.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the Byzantine Empire began and the Roman Empire ceased is a point of much contention. Some historians place the beginning of the Byzantine Empire in 300 AD, when Constantine I moved the capital of the Roman Empire from Rome to a city called Byzantium (later know as Constantinople). Others place the birth of the Byzantine Empire at the end of the reign of Theodosius I, who at his death split the Roman Empire into the Western Empire, ruled from Rome, and the Eastern Empire, ruled from Constantinople.[PARAGRAPH:2]Regardless of historic debate, after the sacking of Rome in 476 AD, the Byzantine Empire was to become the foremost European nation in art, trade and stability - although not necessarily all at once. Taking the throne in 527 AD, Justinian I extended the grip of the Byzantine Empire from Constantinople to the furthest coasts of the Mediterranean Sea. However the Empire would not be able to enjoy the benefits of such territorial expansions for long, as Justinian's successor, Justin II, would begin a trend of placating the various enemies of the Empire - the Sassanid Persians, the Bulgars, and the Arabs, newly organized under Mohammed - with territory in exchange for peace.[PARAGRAPH:2]Territorial losses would continue to weaken the Byzantines until a new lineage of emperors, known as the Macedonian Emperors, arose to invigorate the Empire once again. Basil I founded the Macedonian line in 869. Under the Macedonians, the Byzantine Empire once again began to reach outwards, solidifying its hold on much of the territory neighboring Constantinople. Art flourished in their roughly two centuries of rule, as did the Greek Orthodox Church.[PARAGRAPH:2]The new millennium would be a painful one for Byzantium. Relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church had been deteriorating for many years, and the conflict came to a head with the Great Schism (1054), which finally split the two religions. Militarily, increased assaults by the Seljuk Turks culminated in a resounding defeat for the Empire at the Battle of Manzikert, the Empire losing much of its freshly-gained holdings.[PARAGRAPH:2]But once again, the rise of a powerful new dynasty reversed the Empire's decline. This new dynasty, the Comnenius, sent the call to Western Europe for aid in fighting the Seljuk Turks. Pope Urban II, seeing a chance to reconquer the Holy Lands of Antioch and Jerusalem, as well as halt the squabbling of the European Kings, spread the word for the First Crusade.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through the Crusaders' efforts, the Byzantine Empire regained a portion of its lost territory. But the holy warriors of Western Europe became difficult to control, often threatening to assault the very Empire that had requested their aid. John II and Manuel I, the two most prestigious of the Comnenius emperors, held off the Crusaders and safeguarded the empire from a host of external foes, while ushering in a new era of Byzantine artistic and economic prowess.[PARAGRAPH:2]Manuel I Comnenius was the last great emperor of the Byzantines and the last Comneni. The Angeloi dynasty, successors to the Comneni, proved unable to halt the Empire's slow collapse. In 1204, the knights of the Fourth Crusade, summoned by a disposed Angeloi prince, sacked Constantinople and split the Byzantine Empire into three smaller kingdoms. Nicaea, one of these ex-Byzantine states, recaptured Constantinople years later, but all hopes of reviving the Byzantine Empire would be ended with the capture of the city by the Ottoman leader Mehmed II in 1461.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Byzantium -->
  <!-- Civilization France -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The French</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>法兰西文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>France</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>法兰西</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>French</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>法兰西</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Modern France has its roots in ancient Gaul. In the 2nd century BC Rome intervened on the side of Massilia (Marseilles), a Greek colony founded in 600 BC, in its struggle against the barbarian tribes of the hinterland. The result was the formation, in 121 BC, of the Roman Provincia in what is now southern France; between 58 to 50 BC Julius Caesar seized the remainder. For more than four centuries Gaul enjoyed the benefits of Roman rule, and many ruins of aqueducts and bathhouses still dot the French landscape. After 395 AD the internal problems of the Empire encouraged barbarian penetration of Gaul. By 418, the Franks and Burgundians were established west of the Rhine, and the Visigoths had settled in Aquitaine. The period of the Merovingian and Carolingian Frankish dynasties (476-887) frames the Early Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following his ascension, the first Merovingian king, Clovis (481-511), consolidated the position of the Franks in northern Gaul. Clovis came to believe that his victories were due to the Christian God. Clovis' subsequent conversion assured the Frankish rulers of the support not only of the Catholic Church but of the majority of their own subjects. The Frankish kingdom reached its largest extent under Charlemagne (768-814), who united modern-day France, Italy, and Germany under his rule. After Charlemagne's death, his grandsons divided the kingdom into the three parts that have largely survived to the present. France was a divided kingdom for much of the medieval period, but power gradually began to accumulate in the hands of the rulers of the Ile de France region centered around Paris. By the rise of the house of Valois in 1328, France was the most powerful kingdom in Europe. Its ruler could muster larger armies than rivals; he could tap enormous fiscal resources; and the king's courts maintained royal supremacy. The history of France in the Late Middle Ages is dominated by efforts of its kings to maintain their suzerainty, efforts that, despite French advantages, were long frustrated.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hundred Years War was an intermittent struggle between England and France in the 14th-15th centuries over a series of dynastic disputes, including the legitimate succession to the French crown. The war's turning point was reached in 1429, when an English army was forced to raise its siege of Orleans by a relief force organized by Joan of Arc. By 1453, England retained only Calais, which it finally relinquished in 1558. The French kings of the 16th century spent much of their time fighting the Hapsburg monarchs for control of Italy, while religious conflict between Catholics and Protestants led to a series of civil wars between 1562 and 1598.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ascension of the Bourbon line of kings beginning in 1589 brought renewed stability to France, and the country soared to some of its greatest heights during the long rule of Louis XIV (1643-1715). Under Louis, France became the artistic and intellectual capital of Europe. From his magnificent palace of Versailles, Louis was truly the "Sun King", the absolute master of all he surveyed. The French military was the most powerful in Europe at this time, known for the elite Musketeer units that served as the king's personal guard. France was so strong at this time that the other European nations kept banding together to stop France from conquering them - a pattern that would be repeated in the French Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]These intellectual developments, although significant by themselves, gave rise to a still more momentous change: the French Enlightenment. This movement was a cultural transformation based on rationalism, empiricism, and an amorphous concept of freedom found in the influential writings of figures like Voltaire (1694-1778) and Rousseau (1712-78). Compounding the situation was the bankruptcy of the French crown, which forced the king to call upon representatives of the people for additional taxes. Hence, what began in 1787 as a conflict between royal authority and aristocrats became a triangular struggle, with "the masses" opposing both absolutism and privilege. By any standard, the fall of the Bastille to the Parisian crowd in 1789 was a monumental event, a seemingly miraculous triumph of the people. But the French Revolution soon degenerated into a reign of terror and chaos. After a decade of violence and uncertainty, Napoleon terminated the bloodshed by overthrowing the French government in 1800, at the price of suppressing freedom altogether. In utter contrast to the Revolution, militarism became the defining quality of the Napoleonic regime. The French armies under Napoleon won victory after victory against all of the other great European powers, but decades of war led to the exhaustion of the nation and eventual defeat in 1815.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, the revolutionary fervor of the French citizenry was undiminished by the Napoleonic experience, and led to further revolutions in 1830 and 1848. The latter revolution lead to the short-lived Second Republic (1848-1852), which was overthrown by Napoleon's nephew "Napoleon III" who instituted the Second Empire (1852-1870). Following defeat in the Franco-Prussia War, the Third Republic (1870-1940) was formed, which survived the First World War but collapsed in the face of the German invasion in 1940. After the war, the period of the short-lived Fourth Republic (1947-59) was succeeded by the Fifth Republic (the current one), adopted in September 1958 by popular referendum. Although shorn of its past colonial holdings and aura of military invulnerability, France today remains a major economic power and influential member of the European Union.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]Modern France has its roots in ancient Gaul. In the 2nd century BC Rome intervened on the side of Massilia (Marseilles), a Greek colony founded in 600 BC, in its struggle against the barbarian tribes of the hinterland. The result was the formation, in 121 BC, of the Roman Provincia in what is now southern France; between 58 to 50 BC Julius Caesar seized the remainder. For more than four centuries Gaul enjoyed the benefits of Roman rule, and many ruins of aqueducts and bathhouses still dot the French landscape. After 395 AD the internal problems of the Empire encouraged barbarian penetration of Gaul. By 418, the Franks and Burgundians were established west of the Rhine, and the Visigoths had settled in Aquitaine. The period of the Merovingian and Carolingian Frankish dynasties (476-887) frames the Early Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following his ascension, the first Merovingian king, Clovis (481-511), consolidated the position of the Franks in northern Gaul. Clovis came to believe that his victories were due to the Christian God. Clovis' subsequent conversion assured the Frankish rulers of the support not only of the Catholic Church but of the majority of their own subjects. The Frankish kingdom reached its largest extent under Charlemagne (768-814), who united modern-day France, Italy, and Germany under his rule. After Charlemagne's death, his grandsons divided the kingdom into the three parts that have largely survived to the present. France was a divided kingdom for much of the medieval period, but power gradually began to accumulate in the hands of the rulers of the Ile de France region centered around Paris. By the rise of the house of Valois in 1328, France was the most powerful kingdom in Europe. Its ruler could muster larger armies than rivals; he could tap enormous fiscal resources; and the king's courts maintained royal supremacy. The history of France in the Late Middle Ages is dominated by efforts of its kings to maintain their suzerainty, efforts that, despite French advantages, were long frustrated.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hundred Years War was an intermittent struggle between England and France in the 14th-15th centuries over a series of dynastic disputes, including the legitimate succession to the French crown. The war's turning point was reached in 1429, when an English army was forced to raise its siege of Orleans by a relief force organized by Joan of Arc. By 1453, England retained only Calais, which it finally relinquished in 1558. The French kings of the 16th century spent much of their time fighting the Hapsburg monarchs for control of Italy, while religious conflict between Catholics and Protestants led to a series of civil wars between 1562 and 1598.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ascension of the Bourbon line of kings beginning in 1589 brought renewed stability to France, and the country soared to some of its greatest heights during the long rule of Louis XIV (1643-1715). Under Louis, France became the artistic and intellectual capital of Europe. From his magnificent palace of Versailles, Louis was truly the "Sun King", the absolute master of all he surveyed. The French military was the most powerful in Europe at this time, known for the elite Musketeer units that served as the king's personal guard. France was so strong at this time that the other European nations kept banding together to stop France from conquering them - a pattern that would be repeated in the French Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]These intellectual developments, although significant by themselves, gave rise to a still more momentous change: the French Enlightenment. This movement was a cultural transformation based on rationalism, empiricism, and an amorphous concept of freedom found in the influential writings of figures like Voltaire (1694-1778) and Rousseau (1712-78). Compounding the situation was the bankruptcy of the French crown, which forced the king to call upon representatives of the people for additional taxes. Hence, what began in 1787 as a conflict between royal authority and aristocrats became a triangular struggle, with "the masses" opposing both absolutism and privilege. By any standard, the fall of the Bastille to the Parisian crowd in 1789 was a monumental event, a seemingly miraculous triumph of the people. But the French Revolution soon degenerated into a reign of terror and chaos. After a decade of violence and uncertainty, Napoleon terminated the bloodshed by overthrowing the French government in 1800, at the price of suppressing freedom altogether. In utter contrast to the Revolution, militarism became the defining quality of the Napoleonic regime. The French armies under Napoleon won victory after victory against all of the other great European powers, but decades of war led to the exhaustion of the nation and eventual defeat in 1815.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, the revolutionary fervor of the French citizenry was undiminished by the Napoleonic experience, and led to further revolutions in 1830 and 1848. The latter revolution lead to the short-lived Second Republic (1848-1852), which was overthrown by Napoleon's nephew "Napoleon III" who instituted the Second Empire (1852-1870). Following defeat in the Franco-Prussia War, the Third Republic (1870-1940) was formed, which survived the First World War but collapsed in the face of the German invasion in 1940. After the war, the period of the short-lived Fourth Republic (1947-59) was succeeded by the Fifth Republic (the current one), adopted in September 1958 by popular referendum. Although shorn of its past colonial holdings and aura of military invulnerability, France today remains a major economic power and influential member of the European Union.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization France -->
  <!-- Civilization Arabia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Arabs</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉伯文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Arabia</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉伯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Arab:Arabs</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉伯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Before the spread of Islam and the Arabic language, the term "Arab" referred to any of the nomadic residents of the Arabian Peninsula. When used in a modern context, "Arab" refers to any of the Arabic-speaking peoples who reside on the Atlantic Coast of Africa, Southwestern Iran, Egypt, Sudan, Saudi-Arabia, Syria, and Iraq. The earliest nomadic inhabitants of the Arabian Peninsula herded their sheep, goats, and camels through an unforgiving desert environment; while those Arabs who settled in the oases provided date and cereal agriculture as trade staples for Arab caravans that transported spices, ivory, and gold from southern Arabia and the Horn of Africa to the civilizations farther north.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 7th century AD, Muhammad emerged as the prophet for the religion of Islam, which was widely adopted by the Arab community. Islam unified the Bedouins and the town-dwellers of the oases, and within a century, spread throughout most of the present day Arab-speaking world. The newfound social organization that followed Islam offered new possibilities for the Arabs as agricultural production and intercity trading, particularly in luxury goods, saw significant increases. Gradually, the triad of temple, court, and market formed, as well as a standardized style of writing for laws and other texts. New institutions also emerged, including coinage, territorial deities, royal priesthoods, and standing armies, which further enhanced Arab power.[PARAGRAPH:2]By proclaiming his message publicly, Muhammad gained many followers. After his death, the succeeding caliphs continued to spread the faith of Islam far beyond the religion's birthplace in Mecca. Aside from initial conquests in Iraq and Syria, the Arab conquests penetrated regions including Anatolia, Northern Africa, and Iran. Using their Camel Archers to cross difficult desert terrain, the Arabs were able to create an empire stretching from Spain to the borders of India in barely more than a hundred years. The Arab empire of the medieval period was far more advanced than contemporary Europeans; Harun al-Rashid's Baghdad may have held a million people at the same time that Charlemagne's Aachen was a "capital" of ten thousand. Centers of learning attracted scholars from across the Muslim world to great cities such as Baghdad, Damascus, and Cordoba. The Arabs of this period made many advances in medicine, astronomy, mathematics, and other areas, as well as translating many of the classics of the Ancient Greeks into Arabic, thereby saving them from destruction.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the period of the Crusades, the Arabic world came under assault from Christian Europe. The greatest of Muslim generals from this period was Salah al-Din, better known as Saladin, who successfully defeated the Third Crusade and recaptured Jerusalem for the Arabs. In addition to his military skills, Saladin was known to be a pious man and was well-respected by his enemies as well as his allies - which was very unusual indeed for the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2]For most of the past five centuries, much of the Arab world has been ruled by foreigners; first by the Ottoman Turks, then by the Western colonial powers. Since the onset of de-colonization in the 1950s, traditional Arab values have been modified through the combined pressures of urbanization, industrialization, and Western influence. While urban Arabs still tend to identify themselves more by nationality than by tribe, village farmers revere the pastoral nomad's romantic way of life and claim a kinship with the great desert tribes of the past. As heirs to the ancient Egyptians, Babylonians, Persians, Hebrews, even to the Greeks and Indians, the societies created by Muslims bridge time and space. The original Arab tribes, in less than 20 years after Muhammad's death, defeated the Byzantine and Persian empires, occupied a vast territory from Libya to Persia, and then developed into the Arab, or Islamic, Empire known today.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]Before the spread of Islam and the Arabic language, the term "Arab" referred to any of the nomadic residents of the Arabian Peninsula. When used in a modern context, "Arab" refers to any of the Arabic-speaking peoples who reside on the Atlantic Coast of Africa, Southwestern Iran, Egypt, Sudan, Saudi-Arabia, Syria, and Iraq. The earliest nomadic inhabitants of the Arabian Peninsula herded their sheep, goats, and camels through an unforgiving desert environment; while those Arabs who settled in the oases provided date and cereal agriculture as trade staples for Arab caravans that transported spices, ivory, and gold from southern Arabia and the Horn of Africa to the civilizations farther north.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 7th century AD, Muhammad emerged as the prophet for the religion of Islam, which was widely adopted by the Arab community. Islam unified the Bedouins and the town-dwellers of the oases, and within a century, spread throughout most of the present day Arab-speaking world. The newfound social organization that followed Islam offered new possibilities for the Arabs as agricultural production and intercity trading, particularly in luxury goods, saw significant increases. Gradually, the triad of temple, court, and market formed, as well as a standardized style of writing for laws and other texts. New institutions also emerged, including coinage, territorial deities, royal priesthoods, and standing armies, which further enhanced Arab power.[PARAGRAPH:2]By proclaiming his message publicly, Muhammad gained many followers. After his death, the succeeding caliphs continued to spread the faith of Islam far beyond the religion's birthplace in Mecca. Aside from initial conquests in Iraq and Syria, the Arab conquests penetrated regions including Anatolia, Northern Africa, and Iran. Using their Camel Archers to cross difficult desert terrain, the Arabs were able to create an empire stretching from Spain to the borders of India in barely more than a hundred years. The Arab empire of the medieval period was far more advanced than contemporary Europeans; Harun al-Rashid's Baghdad may have held a million people at the same time that Charlemagne's Aachen was a "capital" of ten thousand. Centers of learning attracted scholars from across the Muslim world to great cities such as Baghdad, Damascus, and Cordoba. The Arabs of this period made many advances in medicine, astronomy, mathematics, and other areas, as well as translating many of the classics of the Ancient Greeks into Arabic, thereby saving them from destruction.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the period of the Crusades, the Arabic world came under assault from Christian Europe. The greatest of Muslim generals from this period was Salah al-Din, better known as Saladin, who successfully defeated the Third Crusade and recaptured Jerusalem for the Arabs. In addition to his military skills, Saladin was known to be a pious man and was well-respected by his enemies as well as his allies - which was very unusual indeed for the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2]For most of the past five centuries, much of the Arab world has been ruled by foreigners; first by the Ottoman Turks, then by the Western colonial powers. Since the onset of de-colonization in the 1950s, traditional Arab values have been modified through the combined pressures of urbanization, industrialization, and Western influence. While urban Arabs still tend to identify themselves more by nationality than by tribe, village farmers revere the pastoral nomad's romantic way of life and claim a kinship with the great desert tribes of the past. As heirs to the ancient Egyptians, Babylonians, Persians, Hebrews, even to the Greeks and Indians, the societies created by Muslims bridge time and space. The original Arab tribes, in less than 20 years after Muhammad's death, defeated the Byzantine and Persian empires, occupied a vast territory from Libya to Persia, and then developed into the Arab, or Islamic, Empire known today.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Arabia -->
  <!-- Civilization Bulgaria -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Bulgarians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>保加利亚文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Bulgaria</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>保加利亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Bulgarian:Bulgarians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>保加利亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BULGARIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Bulgars originally came from Central Asia, 'somewhere east of the Black Sea,' near modern day Kazakhstan and were occasional allies of the Huns. They began sporadic service with the Byzantines as mercenaries in the late 5th century, and by the time of Emperor Justinian I were actually administering some towns in the Empire, defending them against other Bulgars and nomadic tribes from the east. The Bulgars had a falling outwith the Empire, retreated to the steppes, and were next heard from when they joined the Gepids and Lombards in invading Italy. Around 600 AD, the Bulgars had returned and conquered the Slavic area of the Balkans controlled bythe Byzantines. The Byzantine Empire recognized the first Bulgarian Empire in 681 AD, and this nation lasted until 1081 AD.[PARAGRAPH:2]Even though the Bulgars ruled this area with an iron fist, they ended up assimilating much of the Slavic language and culture and eventually would mingle so much with their subjects that eventually it was impossible to determine who was Bulgar and who was Slav. This interbreeding with their Slavic subjects did not dull their ferocity however, and during the Middle Ages Bulgaria was a great military power. The Bulgars fought many wars against the Byzantine Empire, their other neighbors, and nomadic invaders. By 865 AD, Czar Boris I had converted to Christianity and established an independent Bulgarian branch of the Eastern Orthodox church and adopted the Cyrillic alphabet as the official state language, and this alphabet and church spread from Bulgaria to the rest of eastern Europe and then into Russia. Boris' son, Czar Simeon I (893-927 AD) was one of Bulgaria's greatest rulers and during his reign, Bulgaria flourished as a center of Slavic culture and learning. As befitted his warrior heritage, Simeon also conquered many new territories and at his death, Bulgaria stretched from the Black Sea to the Adriatic. After Simeon's death, Bulgaria waned in power, eventually being conquered by the Byzantines. After almost two hundred years of rule by the Byzantines, there followed a two hundred year second Bulgarian Empire that was, in turn, conquered by the Ottoman Empire.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Bulgars originally came from Central Asia, 'somewhere east of the Black Sea,' near modern day Kazakhstan and were occasional allies of the Huns. They began sporadic service with the Byzantines as mercenaries in the late 5th century, and by the time of Emperor Justinian I were actually administering some towns in the Empire, defending them against other Bulgars and nomadic tribes from the east. The Bulgars had a falling outwith the Empire, retreated to the steppes, and were next heard from when they joined the Gepids and Lombards in invading Italy. Around 600 AD, the Bulgars had returned and conquered the Slavic area of the Balkans controlled bythe Byzantines. The Byzantine Empire recognized the first Bulgarian Empire in 681 AD, and this nation lasted until 1081 AD.[PARAGRAPH:2]Even though the Bulgars ruled this area with an iron fist, they ended up assimilating much of the Slavic language and culture and eventually would mingle so much with their subjects that eventually it was impossible to determine who was Bulgar and who was Slav. This interbreeding with their Slavic subjects did not dull their ferocity however, and during the Middle Ages Bulgaria was a great military power. The Bulgars fought many wars against the Byzantine Empire, their other neighbors, and nomadic invaders. By 865 AD, Czar Boris I had converted to Christianity and established an independent Bulgarian branch of the Eastern Orthodox church and adopted the Cyrillic alphabet as the official state language, and this alphabet and church spread from Bulgaria to the rest of eastern Europe and then into Russia. Boris' son, Czar Simeon I (893-927 AD) was one of Bulgaria's greatest rulers and during his reign, Bulgaria flourished as a center of Slavic culture and learning. As befitted his warrior heritage, Simeon also conquered many new territories and at his death, Bulgaria stretched from the Black Sea to the Adriatic. After Simeon's death, Bulgaria waned in power, eventually being conquered by the Byzantines. After almost two hundred years of rule by the Byzantines, there followed a two hundred year second Bulgarian Empire that was, in turn, conquered by the Ottoman Empire.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Bulgaria -->
  <!-- Civilization Cordoba -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Cordobans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Cordoba</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Cordoban:Cordobans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>科尔多瓦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CORDOBA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In 711 AD, thousands of Muslim Arabs and Berbers landed at Gibraltar to begin a rapid conquest of Spain. The Arabs called the region al-Andalus (from which the modern name "Andalusia" is derived) and brought it under the control of the Umayyad Caliphate. This Arabian dynasty had been the civil and spiritual leaders of Islam for the previous fifty years, but their nepotistic rule caused much unrest in the Muslim world. After the ousting of the Umayyads in Damascus by the Abbasids in 750, Abd ar-Rahman, a grandson of a former caliph and one of the few surviving Umayyad clan, fled to al-Andalus and took over this Muslim salient in Europe. His emirate, centered around Cordoba, was the only one that remained independent from the Abbasid Caliphate. The Abbasids did not have the manpower to re-conquer such a far-flung province and under the rule of the ar-Rahman dynasty, Cordovan Spain became a powerful, centralized state, expanding its territory northward at the expense of Christian kingdoms that had resisted the Muslim invaders. Abd ar-Rahman had Cordoba's Great Mosque built in 785, which survives to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 929 AD Abd ar-Rahman III declared himself the Caliph of Cordoba. The title Caliph is reserved for the leader of Islam, but there were already two caliphs in the Muslim world. The Abbasid (or Baghdad) caliph, who was Sunni, traced his descent from Abbas, an uncle of the Prophet Muhammad. The Fatimid caliph, who was Shi'i, traced his descent from Fatima, a daughter of the Prophet. The Umayyads were also Arabs of the Sunni sect, but their lineage traced to Uthman, the third caliph who succeeded Muhammad.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Cordovan Umayyads reached their height in the late 10th century, consolidating their hold on the provinces in Spain and expanding into North Africa against the Fatimids. However, following the familiar pattern seen throughout the history of the Muslim Crescent, regional rulers grew discontented with the leadership at Cordoba and undermined the authority of the Umayyads, and between 1009-1031 a bitter civil war ripped apart the Cordovan Caliphate. Afterwards, al-Andalus was split into small kingdoms called taifas, ruled by local warlords.[PARAGRAPH:2]These local warlords could not stand up to the Christian kingdoms in the north that started the reconquest of Spain. To lend urgency to this push, Pope Alexander II declared it a Crusade, forgiving the sins of those on the way to fight the Muslims. By 1212, the Christian kingdoms of Leon, Castile, Aragon and Catalonia had pushed the Muslims halfway down the peninsula, and a major defeat of the Muslim rulers at Las Navas de Tolosa heralded the beginning of the end for al-Andalus. Cordoba itself fell in 1236. The rest of the history of al-Andalus is a series of defeats, retreats and the shrinking of the Muslim presence in Spain until all that remained of the once mighty al-Andalus was a narrow strip of land near Granada. Ferdinand of Aragon and Isabella of Castile launched a last war against the Muslims and conquered Granada at last in 1492.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]In 711 AD, thousands of Muslim Arabs and Berbers landed at Gibraltar to begin a rapid conquest of Spain. The Arabs called the region al-Andalus (from which the modern name "Andalusia" is derived) and brought it under the control of the Umayyad Caliphate. This Arabian dynasty had been the civil and spiritual leaders of Islam for the previous fifty years, but their nepotistic rule caused much unrest in the Muslim world. After the ousting of the Umayyads in Damascus by the Abbasids in 750, Abd ar-Rahman, a grandson of a former caliph and one of the few surviving Umayyad clan, fled to al-Andalus and took over this Muslim salient in Europe. His emirate, centered around Cordoba, was the only one that remained independent from the Abbasid Caliphate. The Abbasids did not have the manpower to re-conquer such a far-flung province and under the rule of the ar-Rahman dynasty, Cordovan Spain became a powerful, centralized state, expanding its territory northward at the expense of Christian kingdoms that had resisted the Muslim invaders. Abd ar-Rahman had Cordoba's Great Mosque built in 785, which survives to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 929 AD Abd ar-Rahman III declared himself the Caliph of Cordoba. The title Caliph is reserved for the leader of Islam, but there were already two caliphs in the Muslim world. The Abbasid (or Baghdad) caliph, who was Sunni, traced his descent from Abbas, an uncle of the Prophet Muhammad. The Fatimid caliph, who was Shi'i, traced his descent from Fatima, a daughter of the Prophet. The Umayyads were also Arabs of the Sunni sect, but their lineage traced to Uthman, the third caliph who succeeded Muhammad.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Cordovan Umayyads reached their height in the late 10th century, consolidating their hold on the provinces in Spain and expanding into North Africa against the Fatimids. However, following the familiar pattern seen throughout the history of the Muslim Crescent, regional rulers grew discontented with the leadership at Cordoba and undermined the authority of the Umayyads, and between 1009-1031 a bitter civil war ripped apart the Cordovan Caliphate. Afterwards, al-Andalus was split into small kingdoms called taifas, ruled by local warlords.[PARAGRAPH:2]These local warlords could not stand up to the Christian kingdoms in the north that started the reconquest of Spain. To lend urgency to this push, Pope Alexander II declared it a Crusade, forgiving the sins of those on the way to fight the Muslims. By 1212, the Christian kingdoms of Leon, Castile, Aragon and Catalonia had pushed the Muslims halfway down the peninsula, and a major defeat of the Muslim rulers at Las Navas de Tolosa heralded the beginning of the end for al-Andalus. Cordoba itself fell in 1236. The rest of the history of al-Andalus is a series of defeats, retreats and the shrinking of the Muslim presence in Spain until all that remained of the once mighty al-Andalus was a narrow strip of land near Granada. Ferdinand of Aragon and Isabella of Castile launched a last war against the Muslims and conquered Granada at last in 1492.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Cordoba -->
  <!-- Civilization Spain -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Spanish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>西班牙文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Spain</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>西班牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Spanish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>西班牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Kingdom of Spain is located in the extreme southwest of the European continent, and occupies approximately 85 percent of the Iberian Peninsula. Spain is bordered on the west by Portugal, in the northeast by France, and by the great wall of the Pyrenees Mountains. The Iberian Peninsula that the Spanish inhabited was occupied by various other civilizations, including the Phoenicians, Carthaginians, Romans, Visigoths, and Muslims, and Spain is now associated with having a very rich, eclectic culture as a result.[PARAGRAPH:2]The development of Christian society and culture in the first 300 years following Islamic conquest in Spain was slow, but major changes occurred for the Spanish in the 12th and 13th centuries. The population grew, communication with northern Europe intensified, commerce and urban life gained in importance, and the kingdoms of Castile, Aragon, Navarre, and Portugal emerged as the governing bodies of the Iberian Peninsula. These kingdoms reached the frontiers that they would keep, with minimum amount of alteration, until the end of the Middle Ages, when Isabella I became Queen of Castile.[PARAGRAPH:2]Isabella began participating in the royal court at the age of 13; and when Portugal, Aragon, and France offered their marriage candidates, she favored Ferdinand of Aragon. Isabella ascended to the throne as Queen of Castile to rule sensibly and with a prudent political program. Her unification of the states of the Iberian Peninsula into a single entity, the maintenance and control over the Straits of Gibraltar, policy of expansion into Muslim North Africa, reform of Spanish Catholicism, and support for the exploration and expansion of the unknown were evidence of her wisdom and capabilities as Queen. In 1492 Columbus, with the blessing and financial backing of Isabella, sought a route to the legendary rich markets of China and Japan. He instead discovered what would become known as "The New World", the present day Americas. This voyage gave way to a new golden age of expeditions and conquest, as the Americas contained gold, a valuable resource that Spain happened to be desperately bereft of at the time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Spanish explorer Hernando Cortes came to the New World with the sole purpose of seeking out new frontiers and riches in the unknown. Men like Cortes became known as Conquistadores, adventurers who undertook their expeditions in the vast landmasses of the Americas at their own expense, risking their lives without aid from the Spanish royalty. Their conquests included campaigns in Guatemala, Peru, Cuzco, Columbia, Chile, the Bay of Honduras, and as far as the Pacific coastal regions. The Conquistadors, however, were given to fighting and searching for gold, and were swiftly replaced by administrators and settlers from Spain who governed in their place.[PARAGRAPH:2]The twin forces of disease and conquest combined to devastate the indigenous peoples of the Americas, allowing the Spaniards to carve out an enormous empire comprising most of North and South America. Many of the Spanish colonies proved to yield fabulous wealth in the form of gold and sugar, but working conditions were so harsh that large numbers of Africans were brought across the Atlantic as slaves to replace the Indians who had died working on the plantations. These lucrative operations inevitably became high-profile targets of pirates and other raiders who were endorsed by European powers such as England. The Monarchy of Spain endeavored to retaliate by building an armada of warships that was dubbed "The Invincible Armada". The armada was a collection of over 130 naval warships and transport-ships, which contained approximately 8,000 seamen and 19,000 soldiers. King Philip II (1556-98) directed this armada to invade England when the various and frequent raids on Spanish commerce in the Caribbean became intolerable. England's success in repelling the Spanish fleet saved England and the Netherlands from potential consolidation into the Spanish Empire, but despite the Armada's defeat, Spain remained temporarily the strongest land power in Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Spain declined in power quickly; the enormous influx of gold and silver from the Americas debased the Spanish currency, and most of the nation's military might was wasted in the quagmire of religious conflict known as the Thirty Years War (1618-48). By the beginning of the 18th century, Spain had become somewhat marginal in international politics, even though it continued to hold vast territories in the Americas. Spain's period of imperial power and exploration left a legacy that consisted of 18 nations in Latin American, the Spanish presence in the Phillipines, and the ever-growing Spanish-speaking population in the United States today. It is also due to the work of Jesuit missionaries from Spain that hundreds of millions of people in Latin America practice Roman Catholicism to this day. In 1975 Spain transitioned into a constitutional monarchy by way of a democratic constitution and is now recognized for its eclectic culture as well as for the glory and mystique that it once possessed in its youth.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Kingdom of Spain is located in the extreme southwest of the European continent, and occupies approximately 85 percent of the Iberian Peninsula. Spain is bordered on the west by Portugal, in the northeast by France, and by the great wall of the Pyrenees Mountains. The Iberian Peninsula that the Spanish inhabited was occupied by various other civilizations, including the Phoenicians, Carthaginians, Romans, Visigoths, and Muslims, and Spain is now associated with having a very rich, eclectic culture as a result.[PARAGRAPH:2]The development of Christian society and culture in the first 300 years following Islamic conquest in Spain was slow, but major changes occurred for the Spanish in the 12th and 13th centuries. The population grew, communication with northern Europe intensified, commerce and urban life gained in importance, and the kingdoms of Castile, Aragon, Navarre, and Portugal emerged as the governing bodies of the Iberian Peninsula. These kingdoms reached the frontiers that they would keep, with minimum amount of alteration, until the end of the Middle Ages, when Isabella I became Queen of Castile.[PARAGRAPH:2]Isabella began participating in the royal court at the age of 13; and when Portugal, Aragon, and France offered their marriage candidates, she favored Ferdinand of Aragon. Isabella ascended to the throne as Queen of Castile to rule sensibly and with a prudent political program. Her unification of the states of the Iberian Peninsula into a single entity, the maintenance and control over the Straits of Gibraltar, policy of expansion into Muslim North Africa, reform of Spanish Catholicism, and support for the exploration and expansion of the unknown were evidence of her wisdom and capabilities as Queen. In 1492 Columbus, with the blessing and financial backing of Isabella, sought a route to the legendary rich markets of China and Japan. He instead discovered what would become known as "The New World", the present day Americas. This voyage gave way to a new golden age of expeditions and conquest, as the Americas contained gold, a valuable resource that Spain happened to be desperately bereft of at the time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Spanish explorer Hernando Cortes came to the New World with the sole purpose of seeking out new frontiers and riches in the unknown. Men like Cortes became known as Conquistadores, adventurers who undertook their expeditions in the vast landmasses of the Americas at their own expense, risking their lives without aid from the Spanish royalty. Their conquests included campaigns in Guatemala, Peru, Cuzco, Columbia, Chile, the Bay of Honduras, and as far as the Pacific coastal regions. The Conquistadors, however, were given to fighting and searching for gold, and were swiftly replaced by administrators and settlers from Spain who governed in their place.[PARAGRAPH:2]The twin forces of disease and conquest combined to devastate the indigenous peoples of the Americas, allowing the Spaniards to carve out an enormous empire comprising most of North and South America. Many of the Spanish colonies proved to yield fabulous wealth in the form of gold and sugar, but working conditions were so harsh that large numbers of Africans were brought across the Atlantic as slaves to replace the Indians who had died working on the plantations. These lucrative operations inevitably became high-profile targets of pirates and other raiders who were endorsed by European powers such as England. The Monarchy of Spain endeavored to retaliate by building an armada of warships that was dubbed "The Invincible Armada". The armada was a collection of over 130 naval warships and transport-ships, which contained approximately 8,000 seamen and 19,000 soldiers. King Philip II (1556-98) directed this armada to invade England when the various and frequent raids on Spanish commerce in the Caribbean became intolerable. England's success in repelling the Spanish fleet saved England and the Netherlands from potential consolidation into the Spanish Empire, but despite the Armada's defeat, Spain remained temporarily the strongest land power in Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Spain declined in power quickly; the enormous influx of gold and silver from the Americas debased the Spanish currency, and most of the nation's military might was wasted in the quagmire of religious conflict known as the Thirty Years War (1618-48). By the beginning of the 18th century, Spain had become somewhat marginal in international politics, even though it continued to hold vast territories in the Americas. Spain's period of imperial power and exploration left a legacy that consisted of 18 nations in Latin American, the Spanish presence in the Phillipines, and the ever-growing Spanish-speaking population in the United States today. It is also due to the work of Jesuit missionaries from Spain that hundreds of millions of people in Latin America practice Roman Catholicism to this day. In 1975 Spain transitioned into a constitutional monarchy by way of a democratic constitution and is now recognized for its eclectic culture as well as for the glory and mystique that it once possessed in its youth.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Spain -->
  <!-- Civilization Norse -->
  <!--<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_DESC</Tag>
		<English>The Norse</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Les Scandinaves</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavier:Die Skandinavier:den Skandinaviern</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Male:Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1:1:1</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Gli Scandinavi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Los Escandinavos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>Os Escandinavos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Norse</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Scandinavie</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavien</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Scandinavia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Escandinavia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>Escandinvia</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>
			<Text>Norse:Norse</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</English>
		<French>
			<Text>scandinave:scandinave:scandinaves:scandinaves</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Skandinavisch:skandinavischen:skandinavische</Text>
			<Gender>Neuter:Neuter:Neuter</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>scandinavo:scandinava:scandinavi:scandinave</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>escandinavo:escandinava:escandinavos:escandinavas</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
 			<Text>escandinavo:escandinava:escandinavos:escandinavas</Text>
			<Gender>Male:Female:Male:Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:0:1:1</Plural>
 	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]More properly known as Scandinavians or Norsemen, the Vikings were a group of people from northern Europe who became famous for carrying out a series of raids across the continent between roughly 800 - 1050 AD. The period is sometimes known as the "Viking Age," and it was an era of chaos and disruption for large parts of Europe. The Vikings can be classified into three main groups: the Danes largely attacked England; the Norwegians visited Scotland, Ireland, and points further west; while the Swedes invaded the river systems of what is now Russia. Although the Vikings usually employed hit and run tactics, many of them settled in new communities in the areas they had subjugated, eventually mixing with the local population. And while the Vikings are thought today to be bloodthirsty brigands, they probably acted more often as commercial traders than as warriors.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Historians debate the reason why the Vikings suddenly emerged from Scandinavia at the end of the eighth century AD and began preying upon other parts of Europe. Theories include: the Vikings were suffering overpopulation caused by better agricultural tools; that the unification of Norway led to an excess of idle warriors; the Vikings were reacting to attempts by the Franks to muscle them out of trade with the east; or that the men went off to raid and pillage out of simple boredom. One particularly interesting theory is that the climate of Europe was warmer during the early Middle Ages, leading to an excess population in Scandinavia and the subsequent Viking colonization of places such as Iceland and Greenland.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Whatever the actual reason for their expansion, the Viking drive outward began with the sacking of the important island monastery of Lindisfarne, located off the coast of Britain, in 793 AD. England was regularly raided by the Danes in the following decade, and in 865 a major invasion landed in East Anglia. This force was led by several landless Viking kings; in the battles that followed most of the English kingdoms were defeated, but the state of Wessex under Alfred the Great managed to hold the invaders off. The Vikings settled in Northumbria, and their territory became known as the "Danela" (most of these Vikings were Danes).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Another wave of Vikings landed in England in 947 under the command of Erik Bloodaxe, who managed to capture the city of York. Vikings would largely remain in control of England until the Norman invasion of 1066 - and the Normans were themselves the French descendents of Vikings. Scotland and Ireland also experienced a heavy Norwegian Viking presence at this time; a number of important cities were founded by them - including Dublin. Eventually the Vikings settled down and intermarried with the native Irish.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]The main target for Viking aggression, however, was France. All throughout the ninth century the Vikings sailed up and down the Seine River with impunity, sacking French towns and monasteries at their leisure. Finally the French king Charles the Simple made an agreement with the Viking leader Hrolf Ganger in 911, in which Hrolf was granted control over territory in northern France. In exchange, Hrolf and his men agreed to convert to Christianity and become vassals of the French king. Hrolf's name was changed to Rollo and he became duke of the province of Normandy (named for the Norsemen who settled in it). The Normans retained their martial edge even after conversion to Christianity, and would go on to make a number of important conquests in England, the Mediterranean, and during the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]The exploits of the Viking sailors were the stuff of legend. Viking mariners found their way to Iceland, Greenland, and even Newfoundland in North America, setting up colonies in all of these locations. Viking longboats were both fast and seaworthy, and their shallow drafts allowed them to sail far up the river systems of Europe. The Vikings could strike from the sea and be gone again before the military forces of a kingdom could be marshaled to meet them. In the east, the Swedes traveled down the rivers of modern Russia and founded the state of Kievan Rus', which grew rich off the river trade between the Baltic and the Byzantine Empire. These Vikings also found employment as mercenaries within the Byzantine domains, and their most elite warriors found employment in the Byzantine Varangian Guard. The Viking Age finally came to a close around 1050AD, as the Vikings were incorporated into Christian Europe and settled down to the less exciting but more stable pursuits of agriculture and fishing; their reputation as fierce invaders from the sea has endured to this day.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Plus connus, et &#224; juste titre, comme des Scandinaves ou des Normands, les Vikings constituent un peuple issu du nord de l'Europe et rendu c&#233;l&#232;bre par ses raids sur le continent entre 800 et 1050 ap. J.-C. Cette p&#233;riode, parfois appel&#233;e "l'&#226;ge viking", est caract&#233;ris&#233;e par le chaos et le bouleversement dans de grandes parties de l'Europe. Les Vikings peuvent &#234;tre class&#233;s en trois groupes principaux : les Danois, qui attaquent essentiellement la Grande-Bretagne ; les Norv&#233;giens qui se rendent en Ecosse, en Irlande et dans divers lieux plus &#224; l'ouest ; et enfin les Su&#233;dois qui envahissent les am&#233;nagements fluviaux de l'actuelle Russie. Si les Vikings emploient souvent des tactiques &#233;clair, bon nombre d'entre eux s'installent dans de nouvelles communaut&#233;s dans les territoires qu'ils conqui&#232;rent, finissant par se m&#233;langer avec la population locale. M&#234;me si, aujourd'hui, on consid&#232;re souvent les Vikings comme des brigands sanguinaires, ils ont sans doute agi plus souvent comme des commer&#231;ants que comme des guerriers.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]La raison de l'&#233;mergence soudaine des Vikings &#224; partir de la Scandinavie, &#224; la fin du VIIIe si&#232;cle ap. J.-C. et du d&#233;but de leurs assauts sur d'autres r&#233;gions d'Europe est l'objet de controverses entre les historiens. Selon les diverses th&#233;ories : les Vikings auraient &#233;t&#233; victimes d'une surpopulation en raison de l'am&#233;lioration des outils agricoles ; l'unification de la Norv&#232;ge aurait conduit &#224; un exc&#232;s de guerriers inactifs ; les Vikings auraient r&#233;agi aux tentatives des Francs de les exclure du commerce avec l'Est ; les hommes auraient organis&#233; des raids et des pillages pour simplement mettre fin &#224; leur ennui. L'une des th&#233;ories est particuli&#232;rement int&#233;ressante : le climat de l'Europe se serait adouci au d&#233;but du Moyen Age, ce qui aurait entra&#238;n&#233; une surpopulation en Scandinavie et par cons&#233;quent la colonisation par les Vikings de territoires tels que l'Islande et le Groenland.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Quelle que soit la raison de leur expansion, l'offensive des Vikings commence avec le pillage de l'important monast&#232;re insulaire de Lindisfarne, situ&#233; au large des c&#244;tes britanniques, en 793 ap. J.-C. L'Angleterre est r&#233;guli&#232;rement la cible de raids par les Danois dans la d&#233;cennie suivante et en 865, une importante flotte accoste dans l'est de l'Angleterre. Ces forces sont dirig&#233;es par plusieurs rois vikings n'ayant aucune terre. Au cours des batailles qui s'ensuivent, la majorit&#233; des royaumes britanniques est vaincue, except&#233; l'Etat de Wessex, dirig&#233; par Alfred le Grand, qui r&#233;ussit &#224; repousser les envahisseurs. Les Vikings s'installent en Northumbrie, et leur territoire est alors connu comme le "Danelaw" (les Danois constituent la majorit&#233; des Vikings).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Une autre vague de Vikings arrive en Angleterre en 947 sous la direction d'Erik Bloodaxe ("&#224; la hache sanglante"), qui r&#233;ussit &#224; s'emparer de la ville de York. Les Vikings contr&#244;lent une grande partie de l'Angleterre jusqu'&#224; l'invasion normande de 1066, les Normands &#233;tant eux-m&#234;mes les descendants fran&#231;ais des Vikings. L'Ecosse et l'Irlande connaissent &#233;galement &#224; cette &#233;poque une forte pr&#233;sence de Vikings norv&#233;giens, qui fondent de nombreuses grandes villes, comme Dublin. Finalement, les Vikings s'installent et se marient avec les Irlandais natifs.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Cependant, la principale cible des agressions vikings est la France. Pendant tout le IXe si&#232;cle, les Vikings remontent et descendent la Seine en toute impunit&#233;, saccageant &#224; loisir les villes et monast&#232;res fran&#231;ais. Le roi de France Charles le Simple finit par signer en 911 un accord avec le chef viking Hrolf Ganger selon lequel ce dernier obtient le contr&#244;le du territoire dans le nord de la France. En &#233;change, Hrolf et ses hommes acceptent de se convertir au christianisme et de devenir des vassaux du roi fran&#231;ais. Hrolf est rebaptis&#233; Rollon et devient duc de la province de Normandie (dont le nom vient des Normands qui s'y &#233;taient install&#233;s). Les Normands conservent leur esprit guerrier m&#234;me apr&#232;s leur conversion au christianisme, et effectuent de nombreuses conqu&#234;tes importantes en Angleterre, en M&#233;diterran&#233;e et pendant les croisades.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Les exploits des navigateurs vikings alimentent la l&#233;gende. Les marins vikings trouvent une voie vers l'Islande, le Groenland et m&#234;me Terre-Neuve en Am&#233;rique du Nord, installant des colonies dans tous ces territoires. Les drakkars vikings sont non seulement rapides mais tiennent aussi la mer, tandis que leur tirant d'eau peu profond leur permet de remonter de nombreux fleuves en Europe. Les Vikings peuvent frapper depuis la mer et dispara&#238;tre avant m&#234;me que les forces militaires d'un royaume ne soient rassembl&#233;es pour les affronter. A l'Est, les Su&#233;dois remontent les fleuves de l'actuelle Russie et fondent l'Etat Rus' de Kiev, qui s'enrichit gr&#226;ce au commerce fluvial entre la mer Baltique et l'Empire byzantin. Ces Vikings cr&#233;ent &#233;galement des postes de mercenaires dans la garde var&#232;gue byzantine. L'&#226;ge viking finit par s'achever vers 1050 ap. J.-C., lorsque les Vikings sont int&#233;gr&#233;s &#224; l'Europe chr&#233;tienne et qu'ils s'installent pour vivre d'activit&#233;s moins prometteuses mais plus stables telles que l'agriculture et la p&#234;che. Leur r&#233;putation de f&#233;roces envahisseurs de la mer a cependant perdur&#233; jusqu'&#224; aujourd'hui.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die auch als Skandinavier oder Nordmnner bekannten Wikinger lebten in Stammesverbnden in Nordeuropa und waren in der Zeit um etwa 800-1050 nach Christus fr ihre Raubzge auf dem ganzen Kontinent berhmt-berchtigt. Diese Periode wird manchmal auch als "Wikingerzeitalter" bezeichnet und war durch Chaos und Unruhen in groen Teilen Europas geprgt. Allgemein lassen sich die Wikinger in drei Hauptgruppen unterteilen: Die Dnen trieben vorwiegend in England ihr Unwesen, die Norweger in Schottland, Irland und den weiter westlich gelegenen Gebieten und die Schweden fielen ber das dortige Flusssystem in die Region des heutigen Russland ein. Obwohl die Wikinger in der Regel die so genannte "Hit and Run"-Taktik anwandten, wurden doch viele von ihnen in neuen Lebensgemeinschaften in den eroberten Gebieten ansssig und mischten sich schlielich mit der rtlichen Bevlkerung. Heute werden sie vorwiegend als blutrnstige Briganten dargestellt, tatschlich waren sie jedoch in erster Linie als Handelstreibende ttig und weniger als Krieger.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Unter Historikern ist es umstritten, warum die Wikinger gegen Ende des 8. Jahrhunderts pltzlich aus Skandinavien aufbrachen und in andere Teile Europas einfielen. Entsprechend wurden zu diesem Thema unterschiedliche Theorien aufgestellt: Die Wikinger litten aufgrund ihrer fortschrittlichen landwirtschaftlichen Technologien unter bervlkerung; die Einigung Norwegens fhrte zu einem berschuss unttiger Krieger; die Wikinger reagierten auf das von den Franken provozierte Krftemessen im Kampf um die Vorherrschaft bei den Handelsaktivitten mit dem Osten; und schlielich: Die Mnner schwrmten aus reiner Langeweile zu ihren berfllen und Plnderungen aus. Eine besonders interessante Theorie besagt allerdings, dass es im frhen Mittelalter wegen des milderen Klimas in Europa zu einer bervlkerung in Skandinavien kam und die Wikinger daher neue Siedlungsgebiete in Island und Grnland erschlieen mussten.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Was auch immer der tatschliche Anlass fr ihre Expansionsbestrebungen gewesen sein mag, fest steht, dass die Wikinger zunchst einmal im Jahr 793 die bedeutende Klosterinsel Lindisfarne an der englischen Kste eroberten. Im darauf folgenden Jahrzehnt wurde England regelm溥ig von den Dnen berfallen und im Jahr 865 begann schlielich der von verschiedenen heimatlosen Wikingerknigen angefhrte groe Einmarsch in das Knigreich Ostanglien. In den nun folgenden Schlachten wurden die meisten angelschsischen Knigreiche erfolgreich geschlagen, einzig das Knigreich Wessex unter Alfred dem Groen schaffte es, die Invasoren abzuwehren. Nachdem die Wikinger sich schlielich in Northumbrien angesiedelt hatten, wurde dieses Gebiet in "Danelag" umbenannt (da es sich bei den Eroberern vorwiegend um dnische Wikinger handelte).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Im Jahr 947 folgte eine weitere Angriffswelle der Wikinger in England, diesmal angefhrt von Erik Blutaxt, der die Stadt York einnahm. Die Wikinger beherrschten nun groe Teile Englands, bis zur Invasion der Normannen im Jahr 1066, die ihrerseits selbst franzsischstmmige Nachfahren der Wikinger waren. In dieser Periode waren die norwegischen Wikinger in Schottland und Irland allgegenwrtig und grndeten mehrere bedeutende Stdte, darunter auch Dublin. Nach und nach wurden die Wikinger in dieser Region vollends heimisch und verbanden sich schlielich durch Heirat mit den gebrtigen Iren.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Das Hauptziel der wikingischen Aggressoren war jedoch Frankreich. Whrend des gesamten 9. Jahrhunderts befuhren die Wikinger ungehindert die Seine und eroberten franzsische Stdte und Klster, wie es ihnen gerade passte. Schlielich schloss der franzsische Knig Karl der Einfltige im Jahr 911 einen Vertrag mit dem Wikingerfhrer Hrolf Ganger, in dem er ihm die Abtretung Nordfrankreichs zusicherte. Im Gegenzug willigten Hrolf und seine Mnner ein, zum Christentum zu konvertieren und Vasallen des franzsischen Knigs zu werden. Hrolf nderte seinen Namen in Rollo und wurde Herzog der Provinz Normandie (nach den "Nordmnnern" benannt, die sich dort ansiedelten). Aber auch nach ihrem Bekenntnis zum Christentum blieben die Normannen ihrem kriegerischen Wesen treu: Sie machten weiterhin bedeutende Eroberungen in England und dem Mittelmeerraum ebenso wie whrend der Kreuzzge.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Die Heldentaten der wikingischen Seefahrer sind legendr. Diese unerschrockenen Seeleute fuhren bis nach Island, Grnland und sogar Neufundland vor der nordamerikanischen Kste und errichteten berall Kolonien. Die Langboote der Wikinger waren schnell und hochseetauglich, gleichzeitig ermglichte ihr geringer Tiefgang aber auch das Befahren der europischen Flsse. So waren die Wikinger in der Lage, von der Seeseite her anzugreifen und lngst wieder verschwunden zu sein, bevor die Militrtruppen eines Knigreichs auch nur herbeigerufen werden konnten. Im Osten nutzten die schwedischen Wikinger das dortige Flusssystem, um bis in das Gebiet des heutigen Russlands vorzudringen. Hier grndeten sie das Reich der Kiewer Rus, das dank des florierenden Flusshandels zwischen den Balten und dem Byzantinischen Reich schnell zu Wohlstand gelangte. Einige dieser Wikinger verdingten sich wiederum als Sldner in byzantinischen Hoheitsgebieten, ihre Elitekrieger wurden sogar in die Wargergarde des byzantinischen Kaisers aufgenommen. Das Ende der Wikingerzeit wird etwa um 1050 nach Christus datiert. Zu diesem Zeitpunkt hatten sich die Wikinger mehr und mehr in das christliche Europa eingegliedert und waren sesshaft geworden, um weniger aufregenden, dafr aber etwas bestndigeren Ttigkeiten in der Landwirtschaft und im Fischereigewerbe nachzukommen. Ihr Ruf als wildes, kmpferisches Seefahrervolk hat jedoch bis zum heutigen Tage berdauert.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Pi&#249; propriamente noti come scandinavi o nordici, i Vichinghi furono un popolo dell'Europa settentrionale divenuto famoso per le serie di incursioni condotte pi&#249; o meno tra l'800 e il 1050 d.C., periodo talvolta detto &quot;era dei Vichinghi&quot; e in cui il caos e la devastazione dominarono in vaste aree del continente. I Vichinghi si possono dividere in tre gruppi: i Danesi, che attaccarono principalmente l'Inghilterra; i Norvegesi, che invasero la Scozia, l'Irlanda e altri territori pi&#249; a ovest; e gli Svedesi, che invasero il bacino dell'odierna Russia. Anche se i Vichinghi spesso adottavano la strategia del mordi e fuggi, molti di loro finirono per insediarsi nelle aree colpite e per mescolarsi con le popolazioni locali. E anche se oggi i Vichinghi hanno fama d'essere stati pirati assetati di sangue, le loro attivit&#224; avevano probabilmente una natura pi&#249; commerciale che militare.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Gli storici ancora discutono sulle cause dell'improvviso sorgere in Scandinavia alla fine del VII secolo d.C. della civilt&#224; dei Vichinghi e delle loro incursioni predatorie in Europa. Alcuni credono che i Vichinghi fossero afflitti da sovrappopolazione (a causa dei migliori strumenti agricoli adottati negli ultimi tempi); altri che l'unificazione della Norvegia avesse portato a un soprannumero di guerrieri inattivi; o che quella dei Vichinghi sia stata una reazione al tentativo dei Franchi di estrometterli dal commercio con l'oriente; o ancora che le incursioni fossero il risultato di semplice noia da parte degli uomini. Una teoria degna di nota &#232; che nel Medioevo il clima dell'Europa settentrionale fosse pi&#249; mite e che ci?abbia determinato prima un problema di sovrappopolazione in Scandinavia e poi la colonizzazione dell'Islanda e della Groenlandia.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Quale che fosse la causa dell'espansionismo dei Vichinghi, la loro avventura inizi?col saccheggio del monastero di Lindisfarne, su un'isola al largo delle coste britanniche, nel 793 d.C. Nel decennio successivo l'Inghilterra fu regolarmente vittima di incursioni da parte dei Danesi, finch&#233; nell'865 nella regione dell'East Anglia non sbarc?una vera e propria invasione guidata da diversi re vichinghi senza una propria terra. Gli scontri successivi videro la sconfitta della maggior parte degli stati inglesi, salvo quello di Wessex, guidato da Alfredo il Grande, che riusc?a respingere gli invasori. I Vichinghi si insediarono nella regione di Northumbria, che venne ribattezzata &quot;Danela&quot; poich&#233; gran parte di questi vichinghi era danese.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Nel 947 segu?un'altra invasione sotto il comando di Erik Ascia-di-sangue, che riusc?a conquistare anche la citt&#224; di York. I Vichinghi mantennero il controllo dell'Inghilterra fino all'invasione dei normanni (discendenti francesi dei Vichinghi stessi) del 1066. Nello stesso periodo, Scozia e Irlanda sperimentarono una massiccia presenza di Norvegesi, ai quali si deve la fondazione di molte importanti citt&#224;, tra cui Dublino. I Norvegesi finirono per insediarsi e mescolarsi con la nativa popolazione degli Irlandesi.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]L'obiettivo principale dell'assalto vichingo fu per?la Francia. Per tutto il IX secolo i Vichinghi spadroneggiarono impuniti lungo la Senna, saccheggiando senza incontrare ostacoli citt&#224; e monasteri, finch&#233; il re dei Francesi Carlo il Semplice non si accord?col capo vichingo Hrolf Ganger nel 911, cedendogli il controllo della Francia settentrionale. In cambio, Hrolf e i suoi uomini accettarono di convertirsi al cristianesimo e di diventare vassalli del re di Francia. Il nome Hrolf si mut?in Rollo ed egli divenne il duca di Normandia (che prende il nome dagli occupanti norvegesi). Nonostante la conversione al cristianesimo, i normanni non mutarono la propria predisposizione agli scontri bellici e difatti furono protagonisti di molte importanti conquiste in Inghilterra, nel Mediterraneo e nel corso delle crociate.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Le imprese dei marinai vichinghi furono tali da assumere dimensioni leggendarie: furono essi a trovare le rotte per l'lslanda, la Groenlandia e per l'isola di Terranova in Nord America (luoghi tutti in cui fondarono delle colonie). Le navi vichinghe erano sia veloci sia resistenti e la relativa piattezza della loro parte inferiore permetteva anche la navigazione sui fiumi europei. I Vichinghi potevano attaccare via mare e salpare via prima ancora che lo stato colpito organizzasse una risposta armata. A est, gli Svedesi navigarono lungo i fiumi della odierna Russia o fondarono lo stato di Kievan Rus', che si arricch?grazie al traffico tra i territori del Mar Baltico e l'Impero bizantino. Alcuni di questi Vichinghi trovarono anche impiego come mercenari a difesa dei confini bizantini; i pi&#249; valorosi tra loro fecero parte del corpo d'elite delle guardie bizantine, i varangi. L'era dei vichinghi si concluse intorno al 1050 d.C., quando i vichinghi si possono considerare ormai in tutto e per tutto integrati nell'Europa cristiana e dediti alle meno eccitanti ma pi&#249; stabili occupazioni dell'agricoltura e della pesca, ma nonostante ci?la loro reputazione di feroci invasori dal mare &#232; rimasta viva fino a oggi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Conocidos tambi&#233;n como normandos, los vikingos eran una serie de pueblos procedentes del norte de Europa que se hicieron famosos por los ataques llevados a cabo por todo el continente en el perodo comprendido aproximadamente entre el 800 y 1050 d. C. Este perodo, conocido a veces como &quot;era vikinga&quot;, se caracteriz?en muchas partes de Europa por el caos y el desorden. Los vikingos se dividan en tres grandes grupos: los daneses centraron sus ataques principalmente en Inglaterra; los noruegos visitaron Escocia, Irlanda y algunas regiones situadas al oeste; y los suecos invadieron el sistema fluvial de lo que en nuestros das es Rusia. Aunque normalmente utilizaban t&#225;cticas de ataque fugaces, muchos de ellos establecieron comunidades nuevas en las &#225;reas sojuzgadas y acabaron por mezclarse con las poblaciones locales. Y, aunque hoy en da se tiene de ellos la imagen de saqueadores sanguinarios, lo m&#225;s probable es que en general actuasen m&#225;s como mercaderes que como guerreros.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Los historiadores debaten las razones que los llevaron a salir de Escandinavia a finales del siglo VIII d. C. y a empezar sus ataques a otras regiones de Europa. Hay diversas teoras: que Escandinavia sufra una superpoblacin provocada por el desarrollo del instrumental agrcola; que la unificacin de Noruega haba provocado la existencia de un exceso de guerreros sin nada que hacer; que se trataba de una reaccin de los intentos de los francos por impedirles acceder al comercio de las regiones orientales; o que los hombres se dedicaban al pillaje y al saqueo por puro aburrimiento. Una teora especialmente interesante es la que asegura que el clima de Europa era m&#225;s c&#225;lido durante la Edad Media, lo que produjo un exceso de poblacin en Escandinavia y la consiguiente colonizacin de regiones como Islandia y Groenlandia.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Pero al margen de la razn ltima de su expansin, lo que sabemos con certeza es que la expansin vikinga se inici?con el saqueo del importante monasterio de Lindisfarne, situado en una isla de la costa de Inglaterra, en el 793 d. C. En la siguiente d&#233;cada, Inglaterra sufri?los constantes saqueos de los daneses y, en el ao 865, una invasin en toda regla desembarc?en Anglia oriental. Este ej&#233;rcito estaba dirigido por varios reyes sin tierra; en las batallas que se produjeron a continuacin, la mayora de los reinos ingleses fueron derrotados, pero el estado de Wessex, bajo el mando de Alfredo el Grande, logr?contener a los invasores. Los vikingos se instalaron en Nortumbria, territorio que pas?a conocerse como &quot;Danela&quot; (pues la mayora de los invasores eran daneses).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Otra oleada de vikingos, bajo el mando de Erik Hacha Sangrienta, desembarc?en la isla en el ao 947 y logr?capturar la ciudad de York. Los vikingos mantendran bajo su control la mayor parte de Inglaterra hasta la invasin normanda de 1066, y hay que recordar que estos normandos eran a su vez los descendientes de los vikingos asentados en Francia. A estas alturas, Escocia e Irlanda haban soportado tambi&#233;n una importante presencia de vikingos noruegos. Muchas ciudades importantes, Dubln incluida, fueron fundadas por ellos. Con el paso del tiempo, los vikingos acabaron por mezclarse con los irlandeses nativos.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Sin embargo, el objetivo principal de los ataques vikingos fue Francia. A lo largo de todo el siglo IX, los vikingos navegaron con impunidad por el ro Sena y saquearon a su antojo los pueblos y monasterios de la regin. Finalmente, en el ao 911, el rey franco Carlos el Simple lleg?a un acuerdo con el lder vikingo Hrolf Ganger en el que le conceda el control del norte de Francia. A cambio, Hrolf y sus hombres se comprometan a convertirse al cristianismo y a jurar fidelidad al rey franco como vasallos. Hrolf se cambi?el nombre por el de Rollo y adopt?el ttulo de duque de Normanda (bautizada as?por los normandos que se asentaron en ella). Los normandos no abandonaron su cultura guerrera a pesar de su conversin al cristianismo, y continuaron realizando importantes conquistas en Inglaterra, el Mediterr&#225;neo y el Levante (durante las Cruzadas).[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Las hazaas de los marinos vikingos son legendarias. Parece ser que llegaron hasta Islandia, Groenlandia e incluso el Labrador, en Norteam&#233;rica, y fundaron colonias en todas estas regiones. Sus barcos, adem&#225;s de ser r&#225;pidos y muy marineros, posean un escaso calado que les permita adentrarse profundamente en los sistemas fluviales de Europa. Los vikingos podan atacar desde el mar y retirarse antes de que las fuerzas armadas de un reino pudieran reunirse para ofrecer resistencia. Al este, los suecos viajaron por los ros de la moderna Rusia y fundaron el estado de Kievan Rus, que se hizo rico gracias al comercio entre el B&#225;ltico y el Imperio Bizantino. Adem&#225;s, estos vikingos se emplearon como mercenarios en las tierras de los bizantinos y sus formidables guerreros formaron la guardia varega de los emperadores de Bizancio. La era vikinga lleg?a su fin alrededor del 1050, cuando los vikingos terminaron de incorporarse a la Europa cristiana y empezaron a dedicarse a las tareas, menos excitantes pero m&#225;s estables, de la agricultura y la pesca. Sin embargo, su reputacin de feroces invasores ha perdurado hasta nuestros das.</Spanish>
 	</TEXT>-->
  <!-- Civilization Norse -->
  <!-- Civilization Norway -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Norwegians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>挪威文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Norway</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>挪威</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Norwegian:Norwegians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>挪威</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NORWAY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The looting of the monastery at Lindisfarne in Northeast England on 8 January 793 by 'harrowing inroads of heathen men' has long been regarded as the event which marked the beginning of the Viking Age. The Viking Age was characterised by expansion and emigration by Viking seafarers. According to tradition, Harald Fairhair (Harald Hrfagre) unified them into one in 872 after the Battle of Hafrsfjord in Stavanger, thus becoming the first king of a united Norway. (The date of 872 may be somewhat arbitrary. In fact, the actual date may be just prior to 900). Harald's realm was mainly a South Norwegian coastal state. Harald Fairhair ruled with a strong hand and according to the sagas, many Norwegians left the country to live in Iceland, the Faroe Islands, Greenland, and parts of Britain and Ireland. The modern-day Irish cities of Dublin, Limerick and Waterford were founded by Norwegian settlers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Norse traditions were slowly replaced by Christian ones in the 10th and 11th centuries. This is largely attributed to the missionary kings Olav Tryggvasson and St. Olav. Haakon the Good was Norway's first Christian king, in the mid-10th century, though his attempt to introduce the religion was rejected. Born sometime in between 963-969, Olav Tryggvasson set off raiding in England with 390 ships. He attacked London during this raiding. Arriving back in Norway in 995, Olav landed in Moster. There he built a church which became the first Christian church ever built in Norway. From Moster, Olav sailed north to Trondheim where he was acclaimed King of Norway by the Eyrathing in 995.[PARAGRAPH:2]Feudalism never really developed in Norway and Sweden, as it did in the rest of Europe. However, the administration of government took on a very conservative feudal character. The Hanseatic League forced the royalty to cede to them greater and greater concessions over foreign trade and the economy. The League had this hold over the royalty because of the loans the Hansa had made to the royalty and the large debt the kings were carrying. The League's monopolistic control over the economy of Norway put pressure on all classes, especially the peasantry, to the degree that no real burgher class existed in Norway.[PARAGRAPH:2]Upon the death of Haakon V, King of Norway, in 1319, Magnus Erikson, at just three years old, inherited the throne as King Magnus VII of Norway. At the same time a movement to make Magnus King of Sweden proved successful. (At this time both the kings of Sweden and of Denmark were elected to the throne by their respective nobles.) Thus, with his election to the throne of Sweden, both Sweden and Norway were united under King Magnus VII.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1349, the Black Death radically altered Norway, killing between 50% and 60% of its population and leaving it in a period of social and economic decline. The plague left Norway very poor. Although the death rate was comparable with the rest of Europe, economic recovery took much longer because of the small, scattered population. Before the plague, the population was only about 500,000 people. After the plague, many farms lay idle while the population slowly increased. However, the few surviving farms' tenants found their bargaining positions with their landlords greatly strengthened.[PARAGRAPH:2]King Magnus VII ruled Norway until 1350, when his son, Haakon, was placed on the throne as Haakon VI. In 1363, Haakon VI married Margaret, the daughter of King Valdemar IV of Denmark. Upon the death of Haakon VI, in 1379, his son, Olaf IV, was only 10 years old. Olaf had already been elected to the throne of Denmark on 3 May 1376. Thus, upon Olaf's accession to the throne of Norway, Denmark and Norway entered personal union. Olaf's mother and Haakon's widow, Queen Margaret, managed the foreign affairs of Denmark and Norway during the minority of Olaf IV.[PARAGRAPH:2]Margaret was working toward a union of Sweden with Denmark and Norway by having Olaf elected to the Swedish throne. She was on the verge of achieving this goal when Olaf IV suddenly died. However, Denmark made Margaret temporary ruler upon the death of Olaf. On 2 February 1388 Norway followed suit and crowned Margaret. Queen Margaret knew that her power would be more secure if she were able to find a king to rule in her place. She settled on Eric of Pomerania, grandson of her sister. Thus at an all-Scandinavian meeting held at Kalmar, Erik of Pomerania was crowned king of all three Scandinavian countries. Thus, royal politics resulted in personal unions between the Nordic countries, eventually bringing the thrones of Norway, Denmark, and Sweden under the control of Queen Margaret when the country entered into the Kalmar Union.[PARAGRAPH:2]After Sweden broke out of the Kalmar Union in 1521, Norway tried to follow suit, but the ensuing rebellion was defeated, and Norway remained in a union with Denmark until 1814, a total of 436 years. During the national romanticism of the 19th century, this period was by some referred to as the "400-Year Night", since all of the kingdom's royal, intellectual, and administrative power was centred in Copenhagen in Denmark. In fact, it was a period of great prosperity and progress for Norway, especially in terms of shipping and foreign trade, and it also secured the country's revival from the demographic catastrophe it suffered in the Black Death. Based on the respective natural resources, Denmark-Norway was in fact a very good match, since Denmark supported Norway's needs for grain and food supplies, and Norway supplied Denmark with timber, metal, and fish.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the introduction of Protestantism in 1536, the archbishopric in Trondheim was dissolved, and Norway lost its independence, and effectually became a tributary to Denmark. The Church's incomes and possessions were instead redirected to the court in Copenhagen. Norway lost the steady stream of pilgrims to the relics of St. Olav at the Nidaros shrine, and with them, much of the contact with cultural and economic life in the rest of Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Eventually restored as a kingdom (albeit in legislative union with Denmark) in 1661, Norway saw its land area decrease in the 17th century with the loss of the provinces Bhuslen, Jemtland, and Herjedalen to Sweden, as the result of a number of disastrous wars with Sweden. In the north, however, its territory was increased by the acquisition of the northern provinces of Troms and Finnmark, at the expense of Sweden and Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]The famine of 1695-96 killed roughly 10% of Norway's population. The harvest failed in Scandinavia at least nine times between 1740 and 1800, with great loss of life.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]The looting of the monastery at Lindisfarne in Northeast England on 8 January 793 by 'harrowing inroads of heathen men' has long been regarded as the event which marked the beginning of the Viking Age. The Viking Age was characterised by expansion and emigration by Viking seafarers. According to tradition, Harald Fairhair (Harald Hrfagre) unified them into one in 872 after the Battle of Hafrsfjord in Stavanger, thus becoming the first king of a united Norway. (The date of 872 may be somewhat arbitrary. In fact, the actual date may be just prior to 900). Harald's realm was mainly a South Norwegian coastal state. Harald Fairhair ruled with a strong hand and according to the sagas, many Norwegians left the country to live in Iceland, the Faroe Islands, Greenland, and parts of Britain and Ireland. The modern-day Irish cities of Dublin, Limerick and Waterford were founded by Norwegian settlers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Norse traditions were slowly replaced by Christian ones in the 10th and 11th centuries. This is largely attributed to the missionary kings Olav Tryggvasson and St. Olav. Haakon the Good was Norway's first Christian king, in the mid-10th century, though his attempt to introduce the religion was rejected. Born sometime in between 963-969, Olav Tryggvasson set off raiding in England with 390 ships. He attacked London during this raiding. Arriving back in Norway in 995, Olav landed in Moster. There he built a church which became the first Christian church ever built in Norway. From Moster, Olav sailed north to Trondheim where he was acclaimed King of Norway by the Eyrathing in 995.[PARAGRAPH:2]Feudalism never really developed in Norway and Sweden, as it did in the rest of Europe. However, the administration of government took on a very conservative feudal character. The Hanseatic League forced the royalty to cede to them greater and greater concessions over foreign trade and the economy. The League had this hold over the royalty because of the loans the Hansa had made to the royalty and the large debt the kings were carrying. The League's monopolistic control over the economy of Norway put pressure on all classes, especially the peasantry, to the degree that no real burgher class existed in Norway.[PARAGRAPH:2]Upon the death of Haakon V, King of Norway, in 1319, Magnus Erikson, at just three years old, inherited the throne as King Magnus VII of Norway. At the same time a movement to make Magnus King of Sweden proved successful. (At this time both the kings of Sweden and of Denmark were elected to the throne by their respective nobles.) Thus, with his election to the throne of Sweden, both Sweden and Norway were united under King Magnus VII.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1349, the Black Death radically altered Norway, killing between 50% and 60% of its population and leaving it in a period of social and economic decline. The plague left Norway very poor. Although the death rate was comparable with the rest of Europe, economic recovery took much longer because of the small, scattered population. Before the plague, the population was only about 500,000 people. After the plague, many farms lay idle while the population slowly increased. However, the few surviving farms' tenants found their bargaining positions with their landlords greatly strengthened.[PARAGRAPH:2]King Magnus VII ruled Norway until 1350, when his son, Haakon, was placed on the throne as Haakon VI. In 1363, Haakon VI married Margaret, the daughter of King Valdemar IV of Denmark. Upon the death of Haakon VI, in 1379, his son, Olaf IV, was only 10 years old. Olaf had already been elected to the throne of Denmark on 3 May 1376. Thus, upon Olaf's accession to the throne of Norway, Denmark and Norway entered personal union. Olaf's mother and Haakon's widow, Queen Margaret, managed the foreign affairs of Denmark and Norway during the minority of Olaf IV.[PARAGRAPH:2]Margaret was working toward a union of Sweden with Denmark and Norway by having Olaf elected to the Swedish throne. She was on the verge of achieving this goal when Olaf IV suddenly died. However, Denmark made Margaret temporary ruler upon the death of Olaf. On 2 February 1388 Norway followed suit and crowned Margaret. Queen Margaret knew that her power would be more secure if she were able to find a king to rule in her place. She settled on Eric of Pomerania, grandson of her sister. Thus at an all-Scandinavian meeting held at Kalmar, Erik of Pomerania was crowned king of all three Scandinavian countries. Thus, royal politics resulted in personal unions between the Nordic countries, eventually bringing the thrones of Norway, Denmark, and Sweden under the control of Queen Margaret when the country entered into the Kalmar Union.[PARAGRAPH:2]After Sweden broke out of the Kalmar Union in 1521, Norway tried to follow suit, but the ensuing rebellion was defeated, and Norway remained in a union with Denmark until 1814, a total of 436 years. During the national romanticism of the 19th century, this period was by some referred to as the "400-Year Night", since all of the kingdom's royal, intellectual, and administrative power was centred in Copenhagen in Denmark. In fact, it was a period of great prosperity and progress for Norway, especially in terms of shipping and foreign trade, and it also secured the country's revival from the demographic catastrophe it suffered in the Black Death. Based on the respective natural resources, Denmark-Norway was in fact a very good match, since Denmark supported Norway's needs for grain and food supplies, and Norway supplied Denmark with timber, metal, and fish.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the introduction of Protestantism in 1536, the archbishopric in Trondheim was dissolved, and Norway lost its independence, and effectually became a tributary to Denmark. The Church's incomes and possessions were instead redirected to the court in Copenhagen. Norway lost the steady stream of pilgrims to the relics of St. Olav at the Nidaros shrine, and with them, much of the contact with cultural and economic life in the rest of Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]Eventually restored as a kingdom (albeit in legislative union with Denmark) in 1661, Norway saw its land area decrease in the 17th century with the loss of the provinces Bhuslen, Jemtland, and Herjedalen to Sweden, as the result of a number of disastrous wars with Sweden. In the north, however, its territory was increased by the acquisition of the northern provinces of Troms and Finnmark, at the expense of Sweden and Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]The famine of 1695-96 killed roughly 10% of Norway's population. The harvest failed in Scandinavia at least nine times between 1740 and 1800, with great loss of life.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Norway -->
  <!-- Civilization Denmark -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Danish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>丹麦文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Denmark</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>丹麦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Danish:Danish</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>丹麦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DENMARK_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The unified kingdom of Denmark emerged in the 10th century as a proficient seafaring nation in the struggle for control of the Baltic Sea. Danish rule over the personal Kalmar Union, established in 1397 (over Norway and Sweden), ended with Swedish secession in 1523. However, Denmark still kept a union over Norway which lasted until its dissolution in 1814. Denmark inherited an expansive colonial empire from this union, of which the Faroe Islands and Greenland are remnants. Beginning in the 17th century, there were several cessions of territory; these culminated in the 1830s with a surge of nationalist movements, which were defeated in the 1864 Second Schleswig War. Denmark remained neutral during World War I. In April 1940, a German invasion saw brief military skirmishes while the Danish resistance movement was active from 1943 until the German surrender in May 1945. An industrialized exporter of agricultural produce in the second half of the 19th century, Denmark introduced social and labour-market reforms in the early 20th century, making the basis for the present welfare state model with a highly developed mixed economy.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Constitution of Denmark was signed on 5 June 1849, ending the absolute monarchy which had begun in 1660. It establishes a constitutional monarchy -the current monarch is Queen Margrethe II- organised as a parliamentary democracy. The government and national parliament are seated in Copenhagen, the nation's capital, largest city and main commercial centre. Denmark exercises hegemonic influence in the Danish Realm, devolving powers to handle internal affairs. Denmark became a member of the European Union in 1973, maintaining certain opt-outs; it retains its own currency, the krone. It is among the founding members of NATO, the Nordic Council, the OECD, OSCE, and the United Nations; it is also part of the Schengen Area.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The unified kingdom of Denmark emerged in the 10th century as a proficient seafaring nation in the struggle for control of the Baltic Sea. Danish rule over the personal Kalmar Union, established in 1397 (over Norway and Sweden), ended with Swedish secession in 1523. However, Denmark still kept a union over Norway which lasted until its dissolution in 1814. Denmark inherited an expansive colonial empire from this union, of which the Faroe Islands and Greenland are remnants. Beginning in the 17th century, there were several cessions of territory; these culminated in the 1830s with a surge of nationalist movements, which were defeated in the 1864 Second Schleswig War. Denmark remained neutral during World War I. In April 1940, a German invasion saw brief military skirmishes while the Danish resistance movement was active from 1943 until the German surrender in May 1945. An industrialized exporter of agricultural produce in the second half of the 19th century, Denmark introduced social and labour-market reforms in the early 20th century, making the basis for the present welfare state model with a highly developed mixed economy.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Constitution of Denmark was signed on 5 June 1849, ending the absolute monarchy which had begun in 1660. It establishes a constitutional monarchy -the current monarch is Queen Margrethe II- organised as a parliamentary democracy. The government and national parliament are seated in Copenhagen, the nation's capital, largest city and main commercial centre. Denmark exercises hegemonic influence in the Danish Realm, devolving powers to handle internal affairs. Denmark became a member of the European Union in 1973, maintaining certain opt-outs; it retains its own currency, the krone. It is among the founding members of NATO, the Nordic Council, the OECD, OSCE, and the United Nations; it is also part of the Schengen Area.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Denmark -->
  <!-- Civilization Venezia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Venetians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>威尼斯文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Venezia</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>威尼斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Venetian:Venetians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>威尼斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VENEZIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The city of Venice originated as a collection of lagoon communities banded together for mutual defence from the Lombards as the power of the Byzantine Empire dwindled in northern Italy in the late seventh century. Sometime in the first decades of the eighth century, the people of the lagoon elected their first leader Ursus, who was confirmed by Byzantium and given the titles of hypatus and dux. He was the first historical Doge of Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the reign of the Participazio, Venice grew into its modern form. Though Heraclean by birth, Agnello, first doge of the family, was an early immigrant to Rialto and his dogeship was marked by the expansion of Venice towards the sea via the construction of bridges, canals, bulwarks, fortifications, and stone buildings. Agnello was succeeded by his son Giustiniano, who brought the body of Saint Mark the Evangelist to Venice from Alexandria and made him the patron saint of Venice. During the reign of the successor of the Participazio, Pietro Tradonico, Venice began to establish its military might which would influence many a later crusade and dominate the Adriatic for centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the High Middle Ages, Venice became extremely wealthy through its control of trade between Europe and the Levant, and began to expand into the Adriatic Sea and beyond. Venice was involved in the Crusades almost from the very beginning; Venetian ships assisted in capturing the coastal cities of Syria after the First Crusade, and in 1123 they were granted virtual autonomy in the Kingdom of Jerusalem through the Pactum Warmundi. In the 12th century the Venetians also gained extensive trading privileges in the Byzantine Empire and their ships often provided the Empire with a navy. The Venetian fleet was crucial to the transportation of the Fourth Crusade, but when the crusaders could not pay for the ships, the fleet was directed against Zara, a city on the Adriatic formerly under Venetian control. The crusade was then diverted to Constantinople, which was sacked in 1204. As a result of the partition of the Byzantine Empire which followed, Venice gained a great deal of territory in the Aegean Sea, including the islands of Crete and Euboea. Later, in 1489, the island of Cyprus, previously a crusader state, was annexed to Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the early fifteenth century, the Venetians also began to expand in Italy, as well as along the Dalmatian coast from Istria to Albania. By 1410, Venice had taken over most of Venetia, including such important cities as Verona and Padua.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1499 Venice allied itself with France against Milan, gaining Cremona. In the same year the Ottoman sultan moved to attack Lepanto by land, and sent a large fleet to support his offensive by sea. Antonio Grimani, more a businessman than a sailor, was defeated in the sea battle of Zonchio. Preferring peace to total war against the Turks, Venice surrendered the bases of Lepanto, Modon and Coron.[PARAGRAPH:2]Venice's attention was diverted from her usual maritime position by the delicate situation in northern Italy. Eager to take some of Venice's lands, all neighbouring powers joined in the League of Cambrai in 1508, under the leadership of Pope Julius II. The pope wanted Romagna, emperor Maximilian I Friuli and Veneto, Spain the Apulian ports, the king of France Cremona, the king of Hungary Dalmatia, and each of the others some part. The offensive against the huge army enlisted by Venice was launched from France. On 14 May 1509 Venice was crushingly defeated at the battle of Agnadello, in the Ghiara d'Adda, marking one of the most delicate points of the entire Venetian history. French and imperial troops were occupying the Veneto, but Venice managed to extricate herself through diplomatic efforts. The Apulian ports were ceded in order to come to terms with Spain, and pope Julius II soon recognized the danger brought by the eventual destruction of Venice (then the only Italian power able to face national states like France or the Ottomans). Andrea Gritti recaptured Padua in July 1509, successfully defending it against the besieging imperial troops. Spain and the pope broke off their alliance with France, and Venice regained Brescia and Verona. After seven years of ruinous war, the Serenissima regained her mainland dominions up to the Adda. Although the defeat had turned into a victory, the events of 1509 marked the end of the Venetian expansion.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The city of Venice originated as a collection of lagoon communities banded together for mutual defence from the Lombards as the power of the Byzantine Empire dwindled in northern Italy in the late seventh century. Sometime in the first decades of the eighth century, the people of the lagoon elected their first leader Ursus, who was confirmed by Byzantium and given the titles of hypatus and dux. He was the first historical Doge of Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the reign of the Participazio, Venice grew into its modern form. Though Heraclean by birth, Agnello, first doge of the family, was an early immigrant to Rialto and his dogeship was marked by the expansion of Venice towards the sea via the construction of bridges, canals, bulwarks, fortifications, and stone buildings. Agnello was succeeded by his son Giustiniano, who brought the body of Saint Mark the Evangelist to Venice from Alexandria and made him the patron saint of Venice. During the reign of the successor of the Participazio, Pietro Tradonico, Venice began to establish its military might which would influence many a later crusade and dominate the Adriatic for centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the High Middle Ages, Venice became extremely wealthy through its control of trade between Europe and the Levant, and began to expand into the Adriatic Sea and beyond. Venice was involved in the Crusades almost from the very beginning; Venetian ships assisted in capturing the coastal cities of Syria after the First Crusade, and in 1123 they were granted virtual autonomy in the Kingdom of Jerusalem through the Pactum Warmundi. In the 12th century the Venetians also gained extensive trading privileges in the Byzantine Empire and their ships often provided the Empire with a navy. The Venetian fleet was crucial to the transportation of the Fourth Crusade, but when the crusaders could not pay for the ships, the fleet was directed against Zara, a city on the Adriatic formerly under Venetian control. The crusade was then diverted to Constantinople, which was sacked in 1204. As a result of the partition of the Byzantine Empire which followed, Venice gained a great deal of territory in the Aegean Sea, including the islands of Crete and Euboea. Later, in 1489, the island of Cyprus, previously a crusader state, was annexed to Venice.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the early fifteenth century, the Venetians also began to expand in Italy, as well as along the Dalmatian coast from Istria to Albania. By 1410, Venice had taken over most of Venetia, including such important cities as Verona and Padua.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1499 Venice allied itself with France against Milan, gaining Cremona. In the same year the Ottoman sultan moved to attack Lepanto by land, and sent a large fleet to support his offensive by sea. Antonio Grimani, more a businessman than a sailor, was defeated in the sea battle of Zonchio. Preferring peace to total war against the Turks, Venice surrendered the bases of Lepanto, Modon and Coron.[PARAGRAPH:2]Venice's attention was diverted from her usual maritime position by the delicate situation in northern Italy. Eager to take some of Venice's lands, all neighbouring powers joined in the League of Cambrai in 1508, under the leadership of Pope Julius II. The pope wanted Romagna, emperor Maximilian I Friuli and Veneto, Spain the Apulian ports, the king of France Cremona, the king of Hungary Dalmatia, and each of the others some part. The offensive against the huge army enlisted by Venice was launched from France. On 14 May 1509 Venice was crushingly defeated at the battle of Agnadello, in the Ghiara d'Adda, marking one of the most delicate points of the entire Venetian history. French and imperial troops were occupying the Veneto, but Venice managed to extricate herself through diplomatic efforts. The Apulian ports were ceded in order to come to terms with Spain, and pope Julius II soon recognized the danger brought by the eventual destruction of Venice (then the only Italian power able to face national states like France or the Ottomans). Andrea Gritti recaptured Padua in July 1509, successfully defending it against the besieging imperial troops. Spain and the pope broke off their alliance with France, and Venice regained Brescia and Verona. After seven years of ruinous war, the Serenissima regained her mainland dominions up to the Adda. Although the defeat had turned into a victory, the events of 1509 marked the end of the Venetian expansion.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Venezia -->
  <!-- Civilization Kiev -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Kievans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>基辅文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Kievan Rus</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>基辅罗斯</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Kievan:Kievans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>基辅</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KIEV_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Rus people probably dominated what is now northwestern Russia since the eighth century. In the early ninth they became loosely organized under the Rus Khaganate, which may be regarded as a predecessor state to the Kievan Rus. According to the Primary Chronicle, the earliest chronicle of Kievan Rus, a Varangian named Rurik first established himself in Novgorod in about 860 before moving south and extending his authority to Kiev.[PARAGRAPH:2]These Varangians settled in Ladoga, then moved southward to Novgorod eventually reaching Kiev, putting an end to the Khazars' collecting tribute from Kievans. The Kievan Rus was founded by prince Oleg about 880. During the next thirty-five years, Oleg and his warriors subdued the various Eastern Slavic and Finnic tribes. In 907, Oleg led an attack against Constantinople, and in 911 he signed a commercial treaty with the Byzantine Empire as an equal partner. The new Kievan state prospered because it had an abundant supply of furs, beeswax, and honey for export and because it controlled three main trade routes of Eastern Europe: the Volga trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Orient, the Dnieper trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Black Sea, and the trade route from the Khazars to the Germans.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the reign of Svyatoslav (945-972) Kievan rulers had adopted Slavic religion and names, but their druzhina still consisted primarily of Scandinavians. Svyatoslav's military conquests were astonishing: he dealt lethal blows to two of his strongest neighbours, Khazaria and the Bulgarian Empire, which collapsed soon after his raids.[PARAGRAPH:2]The region of Kiev dominated the state of Kievan Rus for the next two centuries. The grand prince of Kiev controlled the lands around the city, and his theoretically subordinate relatives ruled in other cities and paid him tribute. The zenith of the state's power came during the reigns of Prince Vladimir the Great (980-1015) and Prince Yaroslav the Wise (1019-1054). Both rulers continued the steady expansion of Kievan Rus that had begun under Oleg.[PARAGRAPH:2]Vladimir rose to power in Kiev after the death of his father Sviatoslav I in 972 and after defeating his half-brother Yaropolk in 980. As Prince of Kiev, Vladimir's most notable achievement was the Christianization of Kievan Rus, a process that began in 988.[PARAGRAPH:2]Kievan Rus was not able to maintain its position as a powerful and prosperous state, in part because of the amalgamation of disparate lands under the control of a ruling clan. As the members of that clan became more numerous, they identified themselves with regional interests rather than with the larger patrimony. Thus, the princes fought among themselves, frequently forming alliances with outside groups such as the Polovtsians, Poles, and Hungarians. During the years from 1054 to 1224 no fewer than 64 principalities had a more or less ephemeral existence, 293 princes put forward succession claims, and their disputes led to 83 civil wars.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Crusades brought a shift in European trade routes that accelerated the decline of Kievan Rus. In 1204 the forces of the Fourth Crusade sacked Constantinople, making the Dnieper trade route marginal. As it declined, Kievan Rus splintered into many principalities and several large regional centers. The three most powerful of them were the Halych-Volhynia (eventually conquered by Poland and Lithuania), Novgorod Republic (later incorporated into Muscovy) and Vladimir-Suzdal, which gradually evolved into the Grand Duchy of Moscow.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Rus people probably dominated what is now northwestern Russia since the eighth century. In the early ninth they became loosely organized under the Rus Khaganate, which may be regarded as a predecessor state to the Kievan Rus. According to the Primary Chronicle, the earliest chronicle of Kievan Rus, a Varangian named Rurik first established himself in Novgorod in about 860 before moving south and extending his authority to Kiev.[PARAGRAPH:2]These Varangians settled in Ladoga, then moved southward to Novgorod eventually reaching Kiev, putting an end to the Khazars' collecting tribute from Kievans. The Kievan Rus was founded by prince Oleg about 880. During the next thirty-five years, Oleg and his warriors subdued the various Eastern Slavic and Finnic tribes. In 907, Oleg led an attack against Constantinople, and in 911 he signed a commercial treaty with the Byzantine Empire as an equal partner. The new Kievan state prospered because it had an abundant supply of furs, beeswax, and honey for export and because it controlled three main trade routes of Eastern Europe: the Volga trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Orient, the Dnieper trade route from the Baltic Sea to the Black Sea, and the trade route from the Khazars to the Germans.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the reign of Svyatoslav (945-972) Kievan rulers had adopted Slavic religion and names, but their druzhina still consisted primarily of Scandinavians. Svyatoslav's military conquests were astonishing: he dealt lethal blows to two of his strongest neighbours, Khazaria and the Bulgarian Empire, which collapsed soon after his raids.[PARAGRAPH:2]The region of Kiev dominated the state of Kievan Rus for the next two centuries. The grand prince of Kiev controlled the lands around the city, and his theoretically subordinate relatives ruled in other cities and paid him tribute. The zenith of the state's power came during the reigns of Prince Vladimir the Great (980-1015) and Prince Yaroslav the Wise (1019-1054). Both rulers continued the steady expansion of Kievan Rus that had begun under Oleg.[PARAGRAPH:2]Vladimir rose to power in Kiev after the death of his father Sviatoslav I in 972 and after defeating his half-brother Yaropolk in 980. As Prince of Kiev, Vladimir's most notable achievement was the Christianization of Kievan Rus, a process that began in 988.[PARAGRAPH:2]Kievan Rus was not able to maintain its position as a powerful and prosperous state, in part because of the amalgamation of disparate lands under the control of a ruling clan. As the members of that clan became more numerous, they identified themselves with regional interests rather than with the larger patrimony. Thus, the princes fought among themselves, frequently forming alliances with outside groups such as the Polovtsians, Poles, and Hungarians. During the years from 1054 to 1224 no fewer than 64 principalities had a more or less ephemeral existence, 293 princes put forward succession claims, and their disputes led to 83 civil wars.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Crusades brought a shift in European trade routes that accelerated the decline of Kievan Rus. In 1204 the forces of the Fourth Crusade sacked Constantinople, making the Dnieper trade route marginal. As it declined, Kievan Rus splintered into many principalities and several large regional centers. The three most powerful of them were the Halych-Volhynia (eventually conquered by Poland and Lithuania), Novgorod Republic (later incorporated into Muscovy) and Vladimir-Suzdal, which gradually evolved into the Grand Duchy of Moscow.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Kiev -->
  <!-- Civilization Hungary -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Hungarians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>匈牙利文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Hungary</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>匈牙利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Hungarian:Hungarians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>匈牙利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HUNGARY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Magyars were nomads related to the Huns and Avars and came originally from near Finland and Estonia. They settled north of the Black Sea and entered into service with the Byzantine Empire, making war on the Bulgars at Byzantine request. They then migrated from the Ukraine to escape the Pechenegs, who were attacking them at the behest of the Bulgars, and settled in the Danube River basin in 896 AD, under the rule of their Great Chief, Arpad. They were expert horsemen and terrifying warriors and conducted Viking-like raids on all the lands around them, but on horse, instead of by ship. They soon dominated the entire region, even laying siege to German cities and Constantinople itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 997, Duke Geza, the Magyar leader, died and his son Istvan promptly and forcefully asserted his supremacy over the nation and several discontented elder relatives who disputed his right to the succession. Until this point, Magyar leadership had been elected by seniority in the ruling family, not passed on by primogeniture. In 1000 AD, Istvan asked Pope Sylvester II for a royal crown, which the Pope sent, thus recognizing him as the first Christian king of Hungary, King Stephen. During his 38-year reign, Stephen I consolidated the Magyar state under a group of powerful nobles using modified Carolingian administrative practices, completed conversion of the Magyars to Christianity, and allied the kingdom more closely with the West, most notably by marrying Otto the Great's niece. Stephen was canonized in 1083, and the Crown of Saint Stephen became a symbol of Hungarian nationhood.[PARAGRAPH:2]The thrones of Hungary and Croatia were united in 1091, and during the reign of Bela III (1173-1196) Hungary became the strongest state in east central Europe. The power of the monarchy declined under the weak rule of Andrew II, who was forced to grant a charter, called the Golded Bull, to the nobles, allowing them greater privileges. In 1241, the Mongols invaded and devastated the land, further weakening the Magyar monarchy. The last of the Arpad dynasty died in 1301, and most of Hungary's rulers after that were foreigners.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]The Magyars were nomads related to the Huns and Avars and came originally from near Finland and Estonia. They settled north of the Black Sea and entered into service with the Byzantine Empire, making war on the Bulgars at Byzantine request. They then migrated from the Ukraine to escape the Pechenegs, who were attacking them at the behest of the Bulgars, and settled in the Danube River basin in 896 AD, under the rule of their Great Chief, Arpad. They were expert horsemen and terrifying warriors and conducted Viking-like raids on all the lands around them, but on horse, instead of by ship. They soon dominated the entire region, even laying siege to German cities and Constantinople itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 997, Duke Geza, the Magyar leader, died and his son Istvan promptly and forcefully asserted his supremacy over the nation and several discontented elder relatives who disputed his right to the succession. Until this point, Magyar leadership had been elected by seniority in the ruling family, not passed on by primogeniture. In 1000 AD, Istvan asked Pope Sylvester II for a royal crown, which the Pope sent, thus recognizing him as the first Christian king of Hungary, King Stephen. During his 38-year reign, Stephen I consolidated the Magyar state under a group of powerful nobles using modified Carolingian administrative practices, completed conversion of the Magyars to Christianity, and allied the kingdom more closely with the West, most notably by marrying Otto the Great's niece. Stephen was canonized in 1083, and the Crown of Saint Stephen became a symbol of Hungarian nationhood.[PARAGRAPH:2]The thrones of Hungary and Croatia were united in 1091, and during the reign of Bela III (1173-1196) Hungary became the strongest state in east central Europe. The power of the monarchy declined under the weak rule of Andrew II, who was forced to grant a charter, called the Golded Bull, to the nobles, allowing them greater privileges. In 1241, the Mongols invaded and devastated the land, further weakening the Magyar monarchy. The last of the Arpad dynasty died in 1301, and most of Hungary's rulers after that were foreigners.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Hungary -->
  <!-- Civilization Germany -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Germans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>日耳曼文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Germany</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>德意志</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>German:Germans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>德意志</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Julius Caesar's Gallic Wars brought the Germanic tribes into the spotlight of history. Although Roman efforts to establish hegemony across the Rhine continued for decades, the frontier eventually stabilized along the Rhine and Danube rivers. At that time, Germanic culture extended from Scandinavia as far south as the Carpathians. Although it was heavily fortified, the frontier was never a barrier to trade or culture. Germanic fear of the Huns eventually drove many of the tribes inside the borders of the Roman Empire in the 4th and 5th centuries, where the weakened Romans were unable to contain them. The Eastern Roman Empire survived the crisis and lasted for another thousand years, but the Germanic peoples carved out their own independent kingdoms in the West.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Germanics tribes that had invaded the Roman Empire, the Franks proved to be the most successful. The Merovingian kings and their Carolingian successors eventually brought much of what would later constitute Germany under Frankish control, but the ceaseless blows from Danes, Saracens (Muslims), and Magyars in the later 9th and 10th centuries weakened the kingdom's cohesion. Because the Carolingians themselves were unable to provide effective defense for the empire, there arose in nearly all the German lands powerful lines of margraves, counts, and hereditary rulers; their intrigues and wars against each other were interrupted only briefly by the rise of strong emperors such as Frederick Barbarossa (1155-1190). The subsequent history of Germany is, despite the role of the central rule of the Holy Roman Empire, one of the rise and fall of feuding principalities. It would be a thousand years before Germany was again unified under a single ruler.[PARAGRAPH:2]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.[PARAGRAPH:2]The same nationalism that had brought unity would also bring disaster. Ignoring the careful diplomacy that had isolated Prussia's opponent in each of Bismarck's wars, Germany rushed into World War I against a coalition of Britain, France, and Russia. Despite initial successes, the war eventually turned into a stalemate that Germany could not win, especially once the United Stated entered the war on the Entente side in 1917. Already staggering under a vengeful peace imposed by the Western Allies following World War I, the worldwide economic collapse that began in 1929 proved the catalyst for political extremism. Although bitterly opposed to each other, the Nazis and Communists during the next decade succeeded in mobilizing the political and economic resentments generated by defeat and depression. When Hitler finally became chancellor in January 1933, it was not on the crest of a wave of popular support but as the result of ruthless political intrigue.[PARAGRAPH:2]World War II is appropriately called "Hitler's War." Spearheaded by Panzer formations using revolutionary new tactics, Hitler came close to realizing his aim of establishing German hegemony in Europe. But the turning point of the war came with his decision to send his Panzers into Soviet Russia. Though at the end of 1942 an ultimate German victory still seemed possible, by spring 1945 the Third Reich was prostrate. As a legacy of surrender and the ensuing Cold War, a truncated Germany was divided into two zones of military occupation. While under Soviet rule East Germany suffered and stagnated, West Germany's recovery from total economic and political prostration at the end of World War II was of such dramatic proportions as to become a modern legend. The swift and unexpected downfall of the Soviet order in Europe led to a unification treaty, ratified by the West German Bundestag and the East German People's Chamber in September 1990. After 45 years of division, Germany was once again a united nation. Today Germany is one of the world's economic powerhouses, and a leading force in the European Union.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]Julius Caesar's Gallic Wars brought the Germanic tribes into the spotlight of history. Although Roman efforts to establish hegemony across the Rhine continued for decades, the frontier eventually stabilized along the Rhine and Danube rivers. At that time, Germanic culture extended from Scandinavia as far south as the Carpathians. Although it was heavily fortified, the frontier was never a barrier to trade or culture. Germanic fear of the Huns eventually drove many of the tribes inside the borders of the Roman Empire in the 4th and 5th centuries, where the weakened Romans were unable to contain them. The Eastern Roman Empire survived the crisis and lasted for another thousand years, but the Germanic peoples carved out their own independent kingdoms in the West.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Germanics tribes that had invaded the Roman Empire, the Franks proved to be the most successful. The Merovingian kings and their Carolingian successors eventually brought much of what would later constitute Germany under Frankish control, but the ceaseless blows from Danes, Saracens (Muslims), and Magyars in the later 9th and 10th centuries weakened the kingdom's cohesion. Because the Carolingians themselves were unable to provide effective defense for the empire, there arose in nearly all the German lands powerful lines of margraves, counts, and hereditary rulers; their intrigues and wars against each other were interrupted only briefly by the rise of strong emperors such as Frederick Barbarossa (1155-1190). The subsequent history of Germany is, despite the role of the central rule of the Holy Roman Empire, one of the rise and fall of feuding principalities. It would be a thousand years before Germany was again unified under a single ruler.[PARAGRAPH:2]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.[PARAGRAPH:2]The same nationalism that had brought unity would also bring disaster. Ignoring the careful diplomacy that had isolated Prussia's opponent in each of Bismarck's wars, Germany rushed into World War I against a coalition of Britain, France, and Russia. Despite initial successes, the war eventually turned into a stalemate that Germany could not win, especially once the United Stated entered the war on the Entente side in 1917. Already staggering under a vengeful peace imposed by the Western Allies following World War I, the worldwide economic collapse that began in 1929 proved the catalyst for political extremism. Although bitterly opposed to each other, the Nazis and Communists during the next decade succeeded in mobilizing the political and economic resentments generated by defeat and depression. When Hitler finally became chancellor in January 1933, it was not on the crest of a wave of popular support but as the result of ruthless political intrigue.[PARAGRAPH:2]World War II is appropriately called "Hitler's War." Spearheaded by Panzer formations using revolutionary new tactics, Hitler came close to realizing his aim of establishing German hegemony in Europe. But the turning point of the war came with his decision to send his Panzers into Soviet Russia. Though at the end of 1942 an ultimate German victory still seemed possible, by spring 1945 the Third Reich was prostrate. As a legacy of surrender and the ensuing Cold War, a truncated Germany was divided into two zones of military occupation. While under Soviet rule East Germany suffered and stagnated, West Germany's recovery from total economic and political prostration at the end of World War II was of such dramatic proportions as to become a modern legend. The swift and unexpected downfall of the Soviet order in Europe led to a unification treaty, ratified by the West German Bundestag and the East German People's Chamber in September 1990. After 45 years of division, Germany was once again a united nation. Today Germany is one of the world's economic powerhouses, and a leading force in the European Union.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Germany -->
  <!-- Civilization Poland -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Polish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>波兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Poland</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>波兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Polish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>波兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_POLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]There can be little doubt that, had they been able to overcome their internal divisions, the Poles would have been a dominant power in the Middle Ages. The first institution that can be called a Polish kingdom or nation arose in around 980 AD, when a tribal leader named Mieszko united three major tribes in eastern Europe and converted to Catholicism. The concept of a dynasty had not yet caught on in that part of Europe, though, so successions were often extremely violent and chaotic. After Mieszko's rule, the fortunes of the Polish nation-state depended entirely on the ruthlessness and strength of will of its leader. Some of Mieszko's successors were strong and able to impose their wills on the fractious principalities and tribes of Poland and Pomerania, and thereby defend effectively against foreign, usually German or Bohemian, invasion. Others were not.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1226 AD, just over two hundred years after Boleslaw II successfully reunited the Polish kingdom, Poland was deeply divided once again. Baltic tribes menaced the north and the German state of Brandenburg sought greater land and influence in the west. The Polish king, Conrad of Mazovia, decided to import an army to fight off both of these threats in exchange for an indefinite homeland in Poland. The army was the Teutonic Knights. They accepted Conrad's offer and, after arriving in northern Poland, waged several bloody campaigns of conquest against the German and Baltic occupiers. To Conrad's surprise, though, the Knights then decided that they would rather have their own country rather than a dependent homeland inside someone else's kingdom. Conrad had saved the Polish kingdom from outside invasion, only to be invaded from within.[PARAGRAPH:2]Future Polish kings then had to deal not just with Germans, Bohemians and Lithuanians, but the restless and aggressive Teutonic Knights. As if that were not enough, in 1241 a major Mongol invasion force arrived in Silesia (southeastern Poland). The Poles were able to defeat the Mongols, but at huge cost. Vast lands were laid waste and thousands of soldiers perished. In 1330 tensions between the Teutonic Knights and Poland erupted into open war, and after many political and military stalemates, the Polish king Casimir III was able to expand and recover from the Mongol attack and the endless conflicts with Poland's neighbors. But despite holding firm, Casimir had to settle for survival rather than prosperity.[PARAGRAPH:2]The golden age of Poland came at the end of the Middle Ages, when alliance with Lithuania led to a combined assault on the Teutonic Knights that culminated in the fated battle of Grunwald in 1410. The Knights were able to fight off one contingent of the allied force, but were crushed by the other. The Knights were not totally defeated, but they would never again exert their will upon Poland as forcefully as they had in the preceding two centuries. Casimir IV, perhaps the greatest Polish king, was able to capitalize on this success to unite the Polish succession lines with those of Hungary and Bohemia, creating, albeit briefly, an eastern European super-state that dominated the region culturally and militarily for two generations.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]There can be little doubt that, had they been able to overcome their internal divisions, the Poles would have been a dominant power in the Middle Ages. The first institution that can be called a Polish kingdom or nation arose in around 980 AD, when a tribal leader named Mieszko united three major tribes in eastern Europe and converted to Catholicism. The concept of a dynasty had not yet caught on in that part of Europe, though, so successions were often extremely violent and chaotic. After Mieszko's rule, the fortunes of the Polish nation-state depended entirely on the ruthlessness and strength of will of its leader. Some of Mieszko's successors were strong and able to impose their wills on the fractious principalities and tribes of Poland and Pomerania, and thereby defend effectively against foreign, usually German or Bohemian, invasion. Others were not.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1226 AD, just over two hundred years after Boleslaw II successfully reunited the Polish kingdom, Poland was deeply divided once again. Baltic tribes menaced the north and the German state of Brandenburg sought greater land and influence in the west. The Polish king, Conrad of Mazovia, decided to import an army to fight off both of these threats in exchange for an indefinite homeland in Poland. The army was the Teutonic Knights. They accepted Conrad's offer and, after arriving in northern Poland, waged several bloody campaigns of conquest against the German and Baltic occupiers. To Conrad's surprise, though, the Knights then decided that they would rather have their own country rather than a dependent homeland inside someone else's kingdom. Conrad had saved the Polish kingdom from outside invasion, only to be invaded from within.[PARAGRAPH:2]Future Polish kings then had to deal not just with Germans, Bohemians and Lithuanians, but the restless and aggressive Teutonic Knights. As if that were not enough, in 1241 a major Mongol invasion force arrived in Silesia (southeastern Poland). The Poles were able to defeat the Mongols, but at huge cost. Vast lands were laid waste and thousands of soldiers perished. In 1330 tensions between the Teutonic Knights and Poland erupted into open war, and after many political and military stalemates, the Polish king Casimir III was able to expand and recover from the Mongol attack and the endless conflicts with Poland's neighbors. But despite holding firm, Casimir had to settle for survival rather than prosperity.[PARAGRAPH:2]The golden age of Poland came at the end of the Middle Ages, when alliance with Lithuania led to a combined assault on the Teutonic Knights that culminated in the fated battle of Grunwald in 1410. The Knights were able to fight off one contingent of the allied force, but were crushed by the other. The Knights were not totally defeated, but they would never again exert their will upon Poland as forcefully as they had in the preceding two centuries. Casimir IV, perhaps the greatest Polish king, was able to capitalize on this success to unite the Polish succession lines with those of Hungary and Bohemia, creating, albeit briefly, an eastern European super-state that dominated the region culturally and militarily for two generations.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Poland -->
  <!-- Civilization Moscow -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Muscovites</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>莫斯科文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Muscovy</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>莫斯科</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Muscovy:Muscovites</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>莫斯科</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOSCOW_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Indo-European, Ural-Altaic, and other races have occupied what is now the territory of Russia since 2000 BC, but little is known about their institutions and activities. Modern Russia dates from about 770 AD, when Viking explorers began an intensive penetration of the Volga region. From bases in estuaries along the eastern Baltic, Scandinavian bands, probably in search of new trade routes to the east, began to penetrate territory populated by Finnish and Slavic tribes, where they found unlimited natural resources.[PARAGRAPH:2]Within a few decades the Rus, as the Viking settlers were known, together with other Scandinavians operating farther west, extended their raiding activities down the main river routes toward Baghdad and Constantinople, reaching the Black Sea in 860. In the period from 930 to 1000, the region came under complete control by the Rus from their capital at Kiev. The lifeblood of this sprawling Kievan empire was the commerce organized by these Viking princes. Sometime around 1000 the Kievan princes were converted to Christianity by Byzantine missionaries, and the medieval Russian states would maintain close cultural ties with the Byzantines. The united Kievan state broke apart after 1054 under the pressure of attacks by nomads from the steppes, fragmenting Russia into a number of independent principalities. The devastating attack by the Mongols in 1237-40 resulted in widepread destruction of cities, loss of life, and wiped out a developing commercial middle class centered around the fur trade. This helped bring about the long rule of autocracy in Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Russian principalities, it was Muscovy that proved to be the most successful. Beginning as the state that collected taxes for Russia's Mongol overlords, the princes of Muscovy eventually gained a position of leadership by throwing off the yoke of their oppressors. Ivan III (1462-1505) consolidated the gains his father, Vasily II, had won in the saddle, and his warrior descendent Ivan IV (1533-84), known as Ivan the Terrible, gained enough power to take the title of "Tsar", or Emperor, in 1547. This "gathering of the Russian lands" became a conscious and irresistible five-century drive by Moscow to annex all Slavic lands, both the Russian territories and the Belorussian and Ukrainian regions. The ascension of Peter I (1694-1725), known as Peter the Great, ushered in and established the social, political, and intellectual trends that were to dominate Russia for the next two centuries. The location of his new capital, St. Petersburg, on the shores of the Gulf of Finland symbolized this shift toward a European involvement. But while the Russian aristocracy may have adopted the courtly behavior and modern military tactics of the West, the vast majority of the Russian people remained mired in a slave-like state of feudal servitude.[PARAGRAPH:2]Catherine the Great (1762-1796), though a German princess who was unrelated to Peter in any way, would prove to be his true intellectual and political heir. Catherine's reign was notable for imperial expansion. Most important were the securing of the northern shore of the Black Sea, the annexation of the Crimea, and the expansion into the steppes beyond the Urals. This permitted the protection of Russian agricultural settlements in the south and the establishment of trade routes through the Black Sea. In the process, the military democracies of the Cossack hosts along the Dnieper, Don, and Volga rivers lost their autonomy and special privileges; the wealthier officers became Russian nobles, receiving the right to own and settle serfs on their own lands, while the fierce horsemen sank to the level of peasants with special military obligations. Catherine's partitioning of Poland also helped bring Russia closer to the rest of Europe, at least geographically.[PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the heritage of Peter and Catherine, by the time of Nicholas II (1894-1917) Russia was in disarray, plagued by internal misery and oppression. Defeat in the Russo-Japanese War followed by the 1905 Revolution indicated that Russia was in need of drastic reforms, but the autocratic structure of the Tsarist state was poorly suited to adapt to changing conditions. World War I imposed stresses on the Tsardom that it could not meet, and the Russian Revolution broke out in 1917, riding on a wave of popular discontent. The Kerensky Provisional Government, a moderate attempt to resolve the problems, collapsed in the face of the Bolshevik (Communist) revolution. Given the Bolshevik desire to dominate the whole of Russia and the rest of the former Tsarist empire, civil war was inevitable, and a bitter struggle between Red (Communist) and White (Tsarist) forces lasted until the Bolsheviks were victorious in 1922. Stalin would complete the consolidation of Communist power begun by Lenin, most notably through the forced industrialization of the Five-Year Plans and the mass starvations engendered by the collectivization of agriculture. Despite an almost inhuman level of suffering imposed on the Russian people, Stalin would lead the Soviet Union through the greatest threat to its existence during the Nazi invasion of 1941-45, and help it emerge as one of the world's superpowers following the Second World War.[PARAGRAPH:2]But in the ensuing Cold War, Russia's economy tottered towards collapse. The Communist economic system worked well at producing millions of tons of iron for use in tanks, but was unable to produce simple household goods to improve the daily lives of its people. Mikhail Gorbachev attempted to revive the stagnant Soviet economy through the relaxation of economic and political controls, but the forces of free speech and a free market quickly took hold in a way Gorbachev never would have imagined. Within a few years, the Soviet satellites in Eastern Europe were declaring their independence and new politicians like Boris Yeltsin were demanding democratic elections. An ill-conceived, ill-planned, and poorly executed coup attempt to unseat Yeltsin occurred in August 1991, bringing an end to the Communist Party and accelerating the movement to disband the Soviet Union. Yeltsin dissolved the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in December 1991, banned the Communist Party in Russia, and seized all of its property, becoming the first president of Russia. Today, as it often has throughout its history, Russia finds itself struggling between whether to follow the example of the West or pursue its own unique path of development.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]Indo-European, Ural-Altaic, and other races have occupied what is now the territory of Russia since 2000 BC, but little is known about their institutions and activities. Modern Russia dates from about 770 AD, when Viking explorers began an intensive penetration of the Volga region. From bases in estuaries along the eastern Baltic, Scandinavian bands, probably in search of new trade routes to the east, began to penetrate territory populated by Finnish and Slavic tribes, where they found unlimited natural resources.[PARAGRAPH:2]Within a few decades the Rus, as the Viking settlers were known, together with other Scandinavians operating farther west, extended their raiding activities down the main river routes toward Baghdad and Constantinople, reaching the Black Sea in 860. In the period from 930 to 1000, the region came under complete control by the Rus from their capital at Kiev. The lifeblood of this sprawling Kievan empire was the commerce organized by these Viking princes. Sometime around 1000 the Kievan princes were converted to Christianity by Byzantine missionaries, and the medieval Russian states would maintain close cultural ties with the Byzantines. The united Kievan state broke apart after 1054 under the pressure of attacks by nomads from the steppes, fragmenting Russia into a number of independent principalities. The devastating attack by the Mongols in 1237-40 resulted in widepread destruction of cities, loss of life, and wiped out a developing commercial middle class centered around the fur trade. This helped bring about the long rule of autocracy in Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Russian principalities, it was Muscovy that proved to be the most successful. Beginning as the state that collected taxes for Russia's Mongol overlords, the princes of Muscovy eventually gained a position of leadership by throwing off the yoke of their oppressors. Ivan III (1462-1505) consolidated the gains his father, Vasily II, had won in the saddle, and his warrior descendent Ivan IV (1533-84), known as Ivan the Terrible, gained enough power to take the title of "Tsar", or Emperor, in 1547. This "gathering of the Russian lands" became a conscious and irresistible five-century drive by Moscow to annex all Slavic lands, both the Russian territories and the Belorussian and Ukrainian regions. The ascension of Peter I (1694-1725), known as Peter the Great, ushered in and established the social, political, and intellectual trends that were to dominate Russia for the next two centuries. The location of his new capital, St. Petersburg, on the shores of the Gulf of Finland symbolized this shift toward a European involvement. But while the Russian aristocracy may have adopted the courtly behavior and modern military tactics of the West, the vast majority of the Russian people remained mired in a slave-like state of feudal servitude.[PARAGRAPH:2]Catherine the Great (1762-1796), though a German princess who was unrelated to Peter in any way, would prove to be his true intellectual and political heir. Catherine's reign was notable for imperial expansion. Most important were the securing of the northern shore of the Black Sea, the annexation of the Crimea, and the expansion into the steppes beyond the Urals. This permitted the protection of Russian agricultural settlements in the south and the establishment of trade routes through the Black Sea. In the process, the military democracies of the Cossack hosts along the Dnieper, Don, and Volga rivers lost their autonomy and special privileges; the wealthier officers became Russian nobles, receiving the right to own and settle serfs on their own lands, while the fierce horsemen sank to the level of peasants with special military obligations. Catherine's partitioning of Poland also helped bring Russia closer to the rest of Europe, at least geographically.[PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the heritage of Peter and Catherine, by the time of Nicholas II (1894-1917) Russia was in disarray, plagued by internal misery and oppression. Defeat in the Russo-Japanese War followed by the 1905 Revolution indicated that Russia was in need of drastic reforms, but the autocratic structure of the Tsarist state was poorly suited to adapt to changing conditions. World War I imposed stresses on the Tsardom that it could not meet, and the Russian Revolution broke out in 1917, riding on a wave of popular discontent. The Kerensky Provisional Government, a moderate attempt to resolve the problems, collapsed in the face of the Bolshevik (Communist) revolution. Given the Bolshevik desire to dominate the whole of Russia and the rest of the former Tsarist empire, civil war was inevitable, and a bitter struggle between Red (Communist) and White (Tsarist) forces lasted until the Bolsheviks were victorious in 1922. Stalin would complete the consolidation of Communist power begun by Lenin, most notably through the forced industrialization of the Five-Year Plans and the mass starvations engendered by the collectivization of agriculture. Despite an almost inhuman level of suffering imposed on the Russian people, Stalin would lead the Soviet Union through the greatest threat to its existence during the Nazi invasion of 1941-45, and help it emerge as one of the world's superpowers following the Second World War.[PARAGRAPH:2]But in the ensuing Cold War, Russia's economy tottered towards collapse. The Communist economic system worked well at producing millions of tons of iron for use in tanks, but was unable to produce simple household goods to improve the daily lives of its people. Mikhail Gorbachev attempted to revive the stagnant Soviet economy through the relaxation of economic and political controls, but the forces of free speech and a free market quickly took hold in a way Gorbachev never would have imagined. Within a few years, the Soviet satellites in Eastern Europe were declaring their independence and new politicians like Boris Yeltsin were demanding democratic elections. An ill-conceived, ill-planned, and poorly executed coup attempt to unseat Yeltsin occurred in August 1991, bringing an end to the Communist Party and accelerating the movement to disband the Soviet Union. Yeltsin dissolved the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in December 1991, banned the Communist Party in Russia, and seized all of its property, becoming the first president of Russia. Today, as it often has throughout its history, Russia finds itself struggling between whether to follow the example of the West or pursue its own unique path of development.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Moscow -->
  <!-- Civilization Genoa -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Genoans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>热那亚文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Genoa</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>热那亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Genoan:Genoans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>热那亚</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GENOA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Republic initially came into existence in the early 11th century, when Genoa became a self-governing commune within the old Regnum Italicum. In its early centuries, Genoa was an important trading city, like Venice. Genoa started her expansion during the Crusades: the Republic granted her fleet for the transportations and gained many settlements on the Middle East and favored commercial treaties. During 13th century the Republic of Genoa was allied with the Byzantine Empire of Nicaea, which received Genoese help to regain Constantinople in 1261. The alliance permitted a great commercial expansion on the Empire and also the conquest of many isles and settlements on the Aegean Sea (the most important was the isle of Chios which was lost only in 1566). In the same century the Republic conquered important trading interests throughout the Black Sea, where Genoa controlled many settlements on Crimea.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the west Mediterranean the principal rival to Genoa was Pisa, which was ultimately defeated in the naval Battle of Meloria (1284), gaining the island of Corsica from it in the late 13th century and later the control of the north-west of Sardinia, where Genoese families gained territories. In the contest between the Angevins and the Aragonese for control of Sicily after the Sicilian Vespers of 1283, Genoese merchants luckily chose to support Aragon, the winning side, and moved into the Sicilian economy with energy, lending money to the ruling class, organizing and controlling the production of sugar and silks and monopolizing the export of Sicilian grain, on which Genoa depended, situated by nature with no grain-growing contado to support its population, but which the Maghreb also required. In exchange, Genoa received African gold.[PARAGRAPH:2]As a result of the economic retrenchment Europe in the late 14th century, as well as its long war with Venice, which culminated in its defeat at Chioggia (1380), Genoa went into a decline. The rising Ottoman power cut into the Genoese emporia in the Aegean, and the Black Sea trade was squeezed off.[PARAGRAPH:2]Genoa was ultimately occupied by the French or the Milanese for much of the period. From 1499 to 1528, the Republic reached its nadir, being under nearly continual French occupation. The Spanish, with their intramural allies, the "old nobility" entrenched in the mountain fastnesses behind Genoa, captured the city on May 30, 1522 and subjected the city to a merciless pillage. When the great admiral Andrea Doria of the powerful Doria family allied with the Emperor Charles V to oust the French and restore Genoa's independence, a renewed prospect opened: 1528 marks the first loan from Genoese banks to Charles.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Genoa underwent something of a revival as a junior associate of the Spanish Empire, with Genoese bankers, in particular, financing many of the Spanish crown's foreign endeavors from their counting houses in Seville. The decline of Spain in the 17th century brought also the renewed decline of Genoa, and the Spanish crown's frequent bankruptcies, in particular, ruined many of Genoa's merchant houses.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Republic initially came into existence in the early 11th century, when Genoa became a self-governing commune within the old Regnum Italicum. In its early centuries, Genoa was an important trading city, like Venice. Genoa started her expansion during the Crusades: the Republic granted her fleet for the transportations and gained many settlements on the Middle East and favored commercial treaties. During 13th century the Republic of Genoa was allied with the Byzantine Empire of Nicaea, which received Genoese help to regain Constantinople in 1261. The alliance permitted a great commercial expansion on the Empire and also the conquest of many isles and settlements on the Aegean Sea (the most important was the isle of Chios which was lost only in 1566). In the same century the Republic conquered important trading interests throughout the Black Sea, where Genoa controlled many settlements on Crimea.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the west Mediterranean the principal rival to Genoa was Pisa, which was ultimately defeated in the naval Battle of Meloria (1284), gaining the island of Corsica from it in the late 13th century and later the control of the north-west of Sardinia, where Genoese families gained territories. In the contest between the Angevins and the Aragonese for control of Sicily after the Sicilian Vespers of 1283, Genoese merchants luckily chose to support Aragon, the winning side, and moved into the Sicilian economy with energy, lending money to the ruling class, organizing and controlling the production of sugar and silks and monopolizing the export of Sicilian grain, on which Genoa depended, situated by nature with no grain-growing contado to support its population, but which the Maghreb also required. In exchange, Genoa received African gold.[PARAGRAPH:2]As a result of the economic retrenchment Europe in the late 14th century, as well as its long war with Venice, which culminated in its defeat at Chioggia (1380), Genoa went into a decline. The rising Ottoman power cut into the Genoese emporia in the Aegean, and the Black Sea trade was squeezed off.[PARAGRAPH:2]Genoa was ultimately occupied by the French or the Milanese for much of the period. From 1499 to 1528, the Republic reached its nadir, being under nearly continual French occupation. The Spanish, with their intramural allies, the "old nobility" entrenched in the mountain fastnesses behind Genoa, captured the city on May 30, 1522 and subjected the city to a merciless pillage. When the great admiral Andrea Doria of the powerful Doria family allied with the Emperor Charles V to oust the French and restore Genoa's independence, a renewed prospect opened: 1528 marks the first loan from Genoese banks to Charles.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Genoa underwent something of a revival as a junior associate of the Spanish Empire, with Genoese bankers, in particular, financing many of the Spanish crown's foreign endeavors from their counting houses in Seville. The decline of Spain in the 17th century brought also the renewed decline of Genoa, and the Spanish crown's frequent bankruptcies, in particular, ruined many of Genoa's merchant houses.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Genoa -->
  <!-- Civilization England -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The English</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>英格兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>England</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>英格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>English</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>英格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In the classical age Britain lay on the periphery of the civilized world; Julius Caesar's visitations to the island in 55/54 BC were viewed as a daring voyage into the unknown. But in 43 AD the island was invaded by Roman soldiers under the Emperor Claudius, and it was to spend the next four centuries as a Roman province. The Romans built cities, roads, and great bathhouses, the ruins of which can still be seen today. With the collapse of Roman power under Germanic onslaught, tribal migrations into Britain began about the middle of the 5th century. The first arrivals were invited by a British chieftain to defend his kingdom against the Picts and Scots. These first mercenaries were from three tribes - the Angles, Saxons, and Jutes - which were located on the coastlands of northwestern Germany. Eventually, these peoples would themselves topple the existing order, and Britain would spend many centuries divided between various warring kingdoms such as Mercia, East Anglia, and others. The first political entity that could rightly be called "England" formed out of the efforts of the kingdom of Wessex to unite the island against the invasion of Danes and Vikings in the 9th century. But the English domination was fleeting; the subsequent Norman Conquest (1066) resulted in the subordination of England to a Frankish aristocracy, and the introduction of feudalism to the Isles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Norman invasion reoriented England from the Scandinavian world to the Mediterranean one, and reintroduced many elements of Latin culture that had been lost in the Germanic invasions. The English Normans would eventually give rise to a purely British line of kings, the Plantagenets. Three centuries later, the Wars of the Roses was the final struggle between the Yorkist and Lancastrian descendants of the Plantagenets for control of the throne. When Henry Tudor, earl of Richmond, seized the crown in 1485, leaving the Yorkist Richard III dead upon the field of battle, few Englishmen would have predicted that 118 years of Tudor rule had begun. Elizabeth I (1558-1603) proved to be the most able Tudor monarch. No observer in 1558, any more than in 1485, would have predicted that despite the social discord, political floundering, and international humiliation of the past decades, the kingdom again stood on the threshold of an extraordinary age. Her reign ushered in two centuries of British exploration, colonization, and artistic and intellectual advances. When Elizabeth, the "Virgin Queen," died childless, Parliament offered the crown to the closest blood kin, James VI of Scotland, who became James I of England (1603-1625) and founded the Stuart dynasty. The Stuarts kings did not possess the best luck; Charles I was defeated by the forces of Parliament in the English Civil War and executed, and a scant four decades later his descendent James II was also overthrown in the "Glorious Revolution" of 1688. But despite all this turbulence, by 1700 England had merged with Scotland to become "Britain" and established an identity that would be both Protestant and Parliamentry.[PARAGRAPH:2]The British Empire was to be one based on trade and control of the seas. Using the soldiers commonly denoted "Redcoats", every major war Britain engaged in during the 18th and 19th centuries increased its colonial power. The Seven Years' War was particularly notable in this respect, and so were the Napoleonic Wars. By 1820 the total population of the British Empire was 200 million, 26%% of the world's total population. However acquired, all these acquisitions added to the crown's and the country's power and reputation. For the privileged and the rich, the Victorian era was pre-eminently one of confidence and arrogance, under the able guidance of Britain's two longtime Prime Ministers, Gladstone and Disraeli. Stretching from Australia and New Zealand through India, much of Africa, and Canada, the British Empire under Victoria was truly one on which the "sun never set."[PARAGRAPH:2]But the "long summer of peace" came to an end in the bloodbath of Flanders. Although Britain suffered far less physical damage than France and underwent no political revolution, World War I may have affected it more fundamentally than any other European power. The war was a catalyst for social and economic change. The mainstays of the early Industrial Revolution, such as coal mining, textile production, and shipbuilding, upon which British prosperity had been built, were now impoverished or redundant. Britain was slow to develop many of the newer manufacturing industries, such as those involving chemicals, electronics, and automobiles. British foreign policy for much of the postwar period aimed at rehabilitating Germany, while domestic policy focused on institutionalizing socialism to counter public concerns. In general, these movements were opposed by France and resulted in a rupture between Britain and its wartime ally, forcing France into a position of isolation that would have prodigious consequences for Europe with the rise of Hitler in the 1930s. World War II was a British victory, but left the nation bankrupt and unable to prevent the onset of decolonization in the 1950s and 1960s. Although Britons maintained a high standard of living, the British economy continued to perform poorly throughout the 1960s and 1970s. As a reaction, Margaret Thatcher (1979-1990) set out to end socialism in Britain. Her most dramatic acts consisted of a continuing series of statutes to denationalize nearly every industry that Labour had brought into public ownership during the previous 40 years. Promising that "we shall govern as New Labour," the Blair government installed in general elections in 1997 accepted some of Thatcher's foreign policies but also carried out the economic reforms it promised in its manifesto. Faced now with terrorist attacks that threaten the lives of ordinary civilians, Britain has pledged to work together with the United States and other nations to defend this attack on civilization.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]In the classical age Britain lay on the periphery of the civilized world; Julius Caesar's visitations to the island in 55/54 BC were viewed as a daring voyage into the unknown. But in 43 AD the island was invaded by Roman soldiers under the Emperor Claudius, and it was to spend the next four centuries as a Roman province. The Romans built cities, roads, and great bathhouses, the ruins of which can still be seen today. With the collapse of Roman power under Germanic onslaught, tribal migrations into Britain began about the middle of the 5th century. The first arrivals were invited by a British chieftain to defend his kingdom against the Picts and Scots. These first mercenaries were from three tribes - the Angles, Saxons, and Jutes - which were located on the coastlands of northwestern Germany. Eventually, these peoples would themselves topple the existing order, and Britain would spend many centuries divided between various warring kingdoms such as Mercia, East Anglia, and others. The first political entity that could rightly be called "England" formed out of the efforts of the kingdom of Wessex to unite the island against the invasion of Danes and Vikings in the 9th century. But the English domination was fleeting; the subsequent Norman Conquest (1066) resulted in the subordination of England to a Frankish aristocracy, and the introduction of feudalism to the Isles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Norman invasion reoriented England from the Scandinavian world to the Mediterranean one, and reintroduced many elements of Latin culture that had been lost in the Germanic invasions. The English Normans would eventually give rise to a purely British line of kings, the Plantagenets. Three centuries later, the Wars of the Roses was the final struggle between the Yorkist and Lancastrian descendants of the Plantagenets for control of the throne. When Henry Tudor, earl of Richmond, seized the crown in 1485, leaving the Yorkist Richard III dead upon the field of battle, few Englishmen would have predicted that 118 years of Tudor rule had begun. Elizabeth I (1558-1603) proved to be the most able Tudor monarch. No observer in 1558, any more than in 1485, would have predicted that despite the social discord, political floundering, and international humiliation of the past decades, the kingdom again stood on the threshold of an extraordinary age. Her reign ushered in two centuries of British exploration, colonization, and artistic and intellectual advances. When Elizabeth, the "Virgin Queen," died childless, Parliament offered the crown to the closest blood kin, James VI of Scotland, who became James I of England (1603-1625) and founded the Stuart dynasty. The Stuarts kings did not possess the best luck; Charles I was defeated by the forces of Parliament in the English Civil War and executed, and a scant four decades later his descendent James II was also overthrown in the "Glorious Revolution" of 1688. But despite all this turbulence, by 1700 England had merged with Scotland to become "Britain" and established an identity that would be both Protestant and Parliamentry.[PARAGRAPH:2]The British Empire was to be one based on trade and control of the seas. Using the soldiers commonly denoted "Redcoats", every major war Britain engaged in during the 18th and 19th centuries increased its colonial power. The Seven Years' War was particularly notable in this respect, and so were the Napoleonic Wars. By 1820 the total population of the British Empire was 200 million, 26%% of the world's total population. However acquired, all these acquisitions added to the crown's and the country's power and reputation. For the privileged and the rich, the Victorian era was pre-eminently one of confidence and arrogance, under the able guidance of Britain's two longtime Prime Ministers, Gladstone and Disraeli. Stretching from Australia and New Zealand through India, much of Africa, and Canada, the British Empire under Victoria was truly one on which the "sun never set."[PARAGRAPH:2]But the "long summer of peace" came to an end in the bloodbath of Flanders. Although Britain suffered far less physical damage than France and underwent no political revolution, World War I may have affected it more fundamentally than any other European power. The war was a catalyst for social and economic change. The mainstays of the early Industrial Revolution, such as coal mining, textile production, and shipbuilding, upon which British prosperity had been built, were now impoverished or redundant. Britain was slow to develop many of the newer manufacturing industries, such as those involving chemicals, electronics, and automobiles. British foreign policy for much of the postwar period aimed at rehabilitating Germany, while domestic policy focused on institutionalizing socialism to counter public concerns. In general, these movements were opposed by France and resulted in a rupture between Britain and its wartime ally, forcing France into a position of isolation that would have prodigious consequences for Europe with the rise of Hitler in the 1930s. World War II was a British victory, but left the nation bankrupt and unable to prevent the onset of decolonization in the 1950s and 1960s. Although Britons maintained a high standard of living, the British economy continued to perform poorly throughout the 1960s and 1970s. As a reaction, Margaret Thatcher (1979-1990) set out to end socialism in Britain. Her most dramatic acts consisted of a continuing series of statutes to denationalize nearly every industry that Labour had brought into public ownership during the previous 40 years. Promising that "we shall govern as New Labour," the Blair government installed in general elections in 1997 accepted some of Thatcher's foreign policies but also carried out the economic reforms it promised in its manifesto. Faced now with terrorist attacks that threaten the lives of ordinary civilians, Britain has pledged to work together with the United States and other nations to defend this attack on civilization.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization England -->
  <!-- Civilization Portugal -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Portuguese</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>葡萄牙文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Portugal</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>葡萄牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Portuguese</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>葡萄牙</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The area which encompasses modern Portugal was originally settled by Celtic tribes around 1000 BC and was then subsequently conquered by the Visigoths and finally the Moors. The Christian Kings of Asturia eventually drove the Moors out of the area; the new nation of Portugal was formed after its separation from Spanish rule.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portugal was one of the first great internationally-based sea empires in the European world. Between 1415 and 1665, Portugal created a series of resting and refueling ports along the eastern and western coasts of Africa in a bid to eventually reach the profitable shores of India. In 1498 they achieved their goals when Vasco da Gama reached Kozhikode (known then as Calicut). Several important battles took place between the Arabs (who had previously monopolized spice trade in the Indian Ocean) and the Portuguese during this era, the most important of them being the victory over the Egyptian-Gujarati fleet off of Diu in 1509. This victory assured the Portuguese maritime superiority in the Indian Ocean and enabled them to capitalize on the rich spice trade routes between India and Europe. However, in 1578 King Sebastian of Portugal was killed at the battle of "Field of the Three Kings" in Morocco (which Portugal had long hoped to conquer), along with the majority of his force, destroying a central part of Portugal's land armies.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1580 the throne of Portugal was given over to the Habsburg kings of Spain, partially a result of the Portuguese weakness after the demise of its own king. At the same time, Portuguese power in both the east and west was declining due to a lack of skilled sailors available in Portugal. The English and the Dutch had also been amassing large navies, and began expanding their spheres of influence along routes traditionally held solely by the Portuguese. Although the Portuguese wrested national control back from the Spanish in a 1640 revolt, they lost their control in Malacca, Ceylon, Cochin, Hormuz, among many others to the Dutch or other seafaring nations. With their eastern territories diminishing, Brazil, discovered by Pedro Alvares Cabral in 1500, became increasingly important.[PARAGRAPH:2]Gold was discovered in Brazil in 1690, which had previously been exploited mostly for its dyewood, sugar, diamonds, tobacco and slaves. The ensuing gold rush boosted the population of Brazil from 200,000 in 1650 to 1.5 million in 1770. Brazil today remains the largest Portuguese-speaking country in the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1808, French troops under Napoleon Bonaparte invaded Portugal, forcing the prince regent, Dom Joo, to flee to Brazil and set up a new government. In 1821, the royal family moved back to Portugal after reclaiming the country. Dom Joo stayed behind, and then his son, Dom Pedro I, ruled Brazil until the country broke away from its mother country, declaring independence in 1822.[PARAGRAPH:2]After losing Brazil, Portugal focused on building its African acquisitions in order to compete with their British and French counterparts. However, after World War II, the majority of European nations began abandoning their outlying colonies. India forcibly retook the Portuguese colonies still in their territory. In 1974, a democratic government was established in Portugal. This new government negotiated the release of its African holdings, which were promptly devastated by civil war and vicious in-fighting generated by the Cold War.[PARAGRAPH:2]Today Portugal is ruled from its capital in Lisbon as a democratic republic under the constitution of 1976. It remains an important participant in the European Union as well as one of the major environmental reformers of Europe.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]The area which encompasses modern Portugal was originally settled by Celtic tribes around 1000 BC and was then subsequently conquered by the Visigoths and finally the Moors. The Christian Kings of Asturia eventually drove the Moors out of the area; the new nation of Portugal was formed after its separation from Spanish rule.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portugal was one of the first great internationally-based sea empires in the European world. Between 1415 and 1665, Portugal created a series of resting and refueling ports along the eastern and western coasts of Africa in a bid to eventually reach the profitable shores of India. In 1498 they achieved their goals when Vasco da Gama reached Kozhikode (known then as Calicut). Several important battles took place between the Arabs (who had previously monopolized spice trade in the Indian Ocean) and the Portuguese during this era, the most important of them being the victory over the Egyptian-Gujarati fleet off of Diu in 1509. This victory assured the Portuguese maritime superiority in the Indian Ocean and enabled them to capitalize on the rich spice trade routes between India and Europe. However, in 1578 King Sebastian of Portugal was killed at the battle of "Field of the Three Kings" in Morocco (which Portugal had long hoped to conquer), along with the majority of his force, destroying a central part of Portugal's land armies.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1580 the throne of Portugal was given over to the Habsburg kings of Spain, partially a result of the Portuguese weakness after the demise of its own king. At the same time, Portuguese power in both the east and west was declining due to a lack of skilled sailors available in Portugal. The English and the Dutch had also been amassing large navies, and began expanding their spheres of influence along routes traditionally held solely by the Portuguese. Although the Portuguese wrested national control back from the Spanish in a 1640 revolt, they lost their control in Malacca, Ceylon, Cochin, Hormuz, among many others to the Dutch or other seafaring nations. With their eastern territories diminishing, Brazil, discovered by Pedro Alvares Cabral in 1500, became increasingly important.[PARAGRAPH:2]Gold was discovered in Brazil in 1690, which had previously been exploited mostly for its dyewood, sugar, diamonds, tobacco and slaves. The ensuing gold rush boosted the population of Brazil from 200,000 in 1650 to 1.5 million in 1770. Brazil today remains the largest Portuguese-speaking country in the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1808, French troops under Napoleon Bonaparte invaded Portugal, forcing the prince regent, Dom Joo, to flee to Brazil and set up a new government. In 1821, the royal family moved back to Portugal after reclaiming the country. Dom Joo stayed behind, and then his son, Dom Pedro I, ruled Brazil until the country broke away from its mother country, declaring independence in 1822.[PARAGRAPH:2]After losing Brazil, Portugal focused on building its African acquisitions in order to compete with their British and French counterparts. However, after World War II, the majority of European nations began abandoning their outlying colonies. India forcibly retook the Portuguese colonies still in their territory. In 1974, a democratic government was established in Portugal. This new government negotiated the release of its African holdings, which were promptly devastated by civil war and vicious in-fighting generated by the Cold War.[PARAGRAPH:2]Today Portugal is ruled from its capital in Lisbon as a democratic republic under the constitution of 1976. It remains an important participant in the European Union as well as one of the major environmental reformers of Europe.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Portugal -->
  <!-- Civilization Austria -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Austrians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>奥地利文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Austria</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>奥地利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Austrian:Austrians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>奥地利</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Austria was first settled by various Celtic tribes. Noricum, a Celtic kingdom, was claimed by the Roman Empire and made a province. After the Roman Empire's fall, Austria was invaded by Bavarians, Slavs, and Avars. When Charlemagne conquered the land in 788, he encouraged colonization and Christianity. Austria, now part of Eastern Francia, was under the control of the house of Babenberg. In 976, the area known as Marchia Orientalis was given to Leopold of Babenberg in 976.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first record of the land being known as Austria is in 966 when referring to the territory of the Babenberg March. The following centuries are characterized by the early settlements of the country. In 1156, the Privilegium Minus elevated Austria to the duchy statues. The Babenbergs also gained the Duchy of Styria in 1192.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the death of Frederick II in 1246, the Barenberg line ended. Otakar II of Bohemia effectively controlled the duchies of Austria. After his defeat and Durnkrut by Rudolf I of Germany in 1278, his reign came to an end. The following centuries would mark a time of Austrian prosperity, under the ruling dynasty, the Habsburgs. In the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries, the Habsburgs accumulated provinces in the area of the Duchy of Austria. In 1438, Duke Albert V of Austria was chosen as the successor to his father-in-law, Emperor Sigismund. Although Albert ruled for only a year, from that time on, every emperor of the Holy Roman Empire was a Habsburg, with one exception.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Habsburgs began to accumulate lands over the years, and in 1477 the Archduke Maximilian acquired most of the Low Countries after marrying the heiress of Burgundy. His son Philip the Fair married the heiress of Castile and Aragon, and acquired Spain and its Italian, African, and New World adjuncts for the Habsburgs.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the Battle of Mohacs, Austrian rulers expanded their territories. However, the Ottoman expansion into Hungary led to frequent conflicts between the two powers. The long reign of Leopold I ended the Austrian conflict with the Turks. Following the defense of Vienna in 1628, a series of campaigns resulted in the return of Hungary to Austrian Control in 1699. However, during the latter part of the reign of Emperor Charles VI, Austria surrendered some of these gains. After this time, the age of Austrian-Prussian dualism began in Hungary.[PARAGRAPH:2]Various defeats against Napoleon spelled the end of the old Holy Roman Empire in 1806, and in 1804 the Austrian Empire was founded. In 1867, it was transformed into the dual-monarchy of Austria-Hungary. Following the Napoleonic wars, Austria emerged as one of Europe's dominant powers along with Prussia and Russia. In 1815, the German Confederation was founded under the presidency of Austria. Austria and Prussia were one of the two leading powers. After Germany wished to become a unified country, Austria was unwilling to become part of it and grew out of Germany, while Prussia grew into it. Following the defeat of Prussia at the battle of Koniggratz in Bohemia, Austria had to leave the German Confederation and was subsequently no longer permitted to take part in German politics.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Austro-Hungarian Compromise of 1867 provided a dual sovereignty under Franz Joseph I, who ruled until his death. The diversity of the empire made it difficult to control in an age of emerging nationalist movements. The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914 was the probable cause of World War I, which led to the downfall of the Austro-Hungarian Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1918 and 1919, Austria was known as the Republic of German Austria. The monarchy was, however, dissolved in 1919 and a parliamentary democracy was set up in 1920. In 1922, Austria was given a loan to improve the general economic condition. With the granting of the loan, Austria passed from an independent state to the control exercised by the League of Nations. At the time, the real ruler of Austria became the League, through its commissioner in Vienna.[PARAGRAPH:2]The First Austrian Republic lasted until 1933. The two major parties fought each other within the parliament. After the Austrian Civil War in 1934, several members of the Schutzbund Party were executed and the Social Democratic Party was outlawed. In 1936, German troops occupied the country and Hitler, a native of Austria himself, lost citizenship in 1925. Just before the collapse of the Third Reich, Karl Renner set up a Provisional Government in Vienna. Much like Germany, Austria, too, was divided into a British, French, a Soviet and an American Zone and governed by the Allied Commission for Austria.[PARAGRAPH:2]On May 1955, Austria regained independence and declared itself permanently neutral, which it remains today. The political system of the Second Republic came to be characterized by the system of Proporz, meaning that most posts of some political importance were split evenly between members of the Social Democrats and the People's Party. Today, Austria has five major parties: the SPO (Labour Party), the OVP (Conservatives), the Greens (Environmentalists), and FPO (nationalists). Austria became a member of the European Union in 1995, and has retained its constitutional neutrality.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]Austria was first settled by various Celtic tribes. Noricum, a Celtic kingdom, was claimed by the Roman Empire and made a province. After the Roman Empire's fall, Austria was invaded by Bavarians, Slavs, and Avars. When Charlemagne conquered the land in 788, he encouraged colonization and Christianity. Austria, now part of Eastern Francia, was under the control of the house of Babenberg. In 976, the area known as Marchia Orientalis was given to Leopold of Babenberg in 976.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first record of the land being known as Austria is in 966 when referring to the territory of the Babenberg March. The following centuries are characterized by the early settlements of the country. In 1156, the Privilegium Minus elevated Austria to the duchy statues. The Babenbergs also gained the Duchy of Styria in 1192.[PARAGRAPH:2]With the death of Frederick II in 1246, the Barenberg line ended. Otakar II of Bohemia effectively controlled the duchies of Austria. After his defeat and Durnkrut by Rudolf I of Germany in 1278, his reign came to an end. The following centuries would mark a time of Austrian prosperity, under the ruling dynasty, the Habsburgs. In the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries, the Habsburgs accumulated provinces in the area of the Duchy of Austria. In 1438, Duke Albert V of Austria was chosen as the successor to his father-in-law, Emperor Sigismund. Although Albert ruled for only a year, from that time on, every emperor of the Holy Roman Empire was a Habsburg, with one exception.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Habsburgs began to accumulate lands over the years, and in 1477 the Archduke Maximilian acquired most of the Low Countries after marrying the heiress of Burgundy. His son Philip the Fair married the heiress of Castile and Aragon, and acquired Spain and its Italian, African, and New World adjuncts for the Habsburgs.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the Battle of Mohacs, Austrian rulers expanded their territories. However, the Ottoman expansion into Hungary led to frequent conflicts between the two powers. The long reign of Leopold I ended the Austrian conflict with the Turks. Following the defense of Vienna in 1628, a series of campaigns resulted in the return of Hungary to Austrian Control in 1699. However, during the latter part of the reign of Emperor Charles VI, Austria surrendered some of these gains. After this time, the age of Austrian-Prussian dualism began in Hungary.[PARAGRAPH:2]Various defeats against Napoleon spelled the end of the old Holy Roman Empire in 1806, and in 1804 the Austrian Empire was founded. In 1867, it was transformed into the dual-monarchy of Austria-Hungary. Following the Napoleonic wars, Austria emerged as one of Europe's dominant powers along with Prussia and Russia. In 1815, the German Confederation was founded under the presidency of Austria. Austria and Prussia were one of the two leading powers. After Germany wished to become a unified country, Austria was unwilling to become part of it and grew out of Germany, while Prussia grew into it. Following the defeat of Prussia at the battle of Koniggratz in Bohemia, Austria had to leave the German Confederation and was subsequently no longer permitted to take part in German politics.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Austro-Hungarian Compromise of 1867 provided a dual sovereignty under Franz Joseph I, who ruled until his death. The diversity of the empire made it difficult to control in an age of emerging nationalist movements. The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914 was the probable cause of World War I, which led to the downfall of the Austro-Hungarian Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1918 and 1919, Austria was known as the Republic of German Austria. The monarchy was, however, dissolved in 1919 and a parliamentary democracy was set up in 1920. In 1922, Austria was given a loan to improve the general economic condition. With the granting of the loan, Austria passed from an independent state to the control exercised by the League of Nations. At the time, the real ruler of Austria became the League, through its commissioner in Vienna.[PARAGRAPH:2]The First Austrian Republic lasted until 1933. The two major parties fought each other within the parliament. After the Austrian Civil War in 1934, several members of the Schutzbund Party were executed and the Social Democratic Party was outlawed. In 1936, German troops occupied the country and Hitler, a native of Austria himself, lost citizenship in 1925. Just before the collapse of the Third Reich, Karl Renner set up a Provisional Government in Vienna. Much like Germany, Austria, too, was divided into a British, French, a Soviet and an American Zone and governed by the Allied Commission for Austria.[PARAGRAPH:2]On May 1955, Austria regained independence and declared itself permanently neutral, which it remains today. The political system of the Second Republic came to be characterized by the system of Proporz, meaning that most posts of some political importance were split evenly between members of the Social Democrats and the People's Party. Today, Austria has five major parties: the SPO (Labour Party), the OVP (Conservatives), the Greens (Environmentalists), and FPO (nationalists). Austria became a member of the European Union in 1995, and has retained its constitutional neutrality.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Austria -->
  <!-- Civilization Ottoman -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Ottomans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>突厥文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Turkey</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>土耳其</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Ottoman:Ottomans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>奥斯曼</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Ottoman Empire was a Turkish state situated upon the eastern Mediterranean that lasted for some 630 years, from 1299 - 1922 AD. At the height of its power, in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, the Ottoman domains stretched across vast regions in Anatolia, the Balkans, the Near East and northern Africa. For several centuries it was one of the foremost military powers in the world (until it began to stagnate technologically and fell far behind its competitors).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottoman state began as a vassal of the earlier Seljuk Turks, who had formed a large empire in the Near East in the eleventh century. When the Seljuk state of Rum in Anatolia collapsed, the Ottomans took advantage of the ensuing power vacuum and rose in power. According to tradition, Osman I became the bey, or chief, of the state of Sgt in 1281. When Osman captured the Byzantine city of Bilecik in 1299, he declared his state's independence from the Seljuks. This is the traditional date given as the foundation of the Ottoman Empire - which was named after its first leader, Osman.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans expanded rapidly in Anatolia throughout the fourteenth century. A series of capable military leaders made many gains against the tottering Byzantine state. The important cities of Nicaea and Nicomedia fell in 1331 and 1337, and by the 1360s the Ottomans had crossed over into Europe and began capturing territory in Thrace. As a sign of this growing power, Murad I declared himself a sultan (or king) in 1383. Around the year 1400, Timur invaded Anatolia. This caused a great deal of disruption, but the Ottomans bounced back and continued to make territorial gains. Under the rule of Mehmed II, the Ottomans attacked and captured Constantinople, whose mighty walls finally fell to the cannon of the Ottomans. This destroyed the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottomans made Constantinople their capital. Mehmed II became known as "Mehmed the Conqueror." Suleiman I, also known as Suleiman the Magnificent, continued to expand and consolidate the Empire; the Ottomans were at the height of their power and influence during his reign[PARAGRAPH:2]After the capture of Constantinople the Ottoman state virtually adopted the Byzantine civil service to run the empire, and its administration was generally sound (until the nineteenth century, when it began to fossilize and became outdated). The Ottoman Empire was very much a pre-modern dynastic state, made up of many different nationalities - in fact, Greeks largely ran its bureaucracy and were vital to its continued success. Militarily, the Ottomans were very strong largely because of their early adoption of gunpowder and their powerful cavalry forces. The military also employed elite slave soldiers known as "janissaries" who won victory after victory for the expanding Ottoman state. The military remained powerful until the late eighteenth century, when they fell fatally behind Western Europe in military technology.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans were known for their religious tolerance. The Empire was an Islamic state, and Islamic law dominated its legal system, but non-Muslims were generally well treated and enjoyed the freedom to worship their own religion. The Ottoman Empire was long seen as a refuge for Jews across Europe. Economically, the Ottoman Empire was somewhat of a failure. Most of the region's commerce was carried on by Greek or Italian merchants, which slowed the development of Turkish industry. Once the European voyages of exploration found new routes to India and China which did not involve passing through the Near East, the Ottoman Empire began a slow commercial decline.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the start of the nineteenth century, the Ottoman Empire still held enormous amounts of land, but the empire was stagnant and corrupt, and was widely viewed as the "sick man of Europe." The western powers, their commercial and military strength exploding under the influence of the Industrial Revolution, began to snap up vulnerable Ottoman territories. Britain and France forced humiliating commercial treaties on the Ottomans, and the Ottoman state was forced to take out massive loans to cover its debts - the start of a vicious cycle which only incurred more debt for the empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]While some positive reforms were carried out in terms of modernizing the Ottoman state, custom and tradition prevented the reformers from moving fast enough. Furthermore, the rising tide of nationalism began to tear the empire apart, as Serbians, Bulgarians, Romanians, and Greeks all declared their independence and set up their own nations. By the outbreak of World War I, the Ottomans had lost virtually all of their holdings in Europe. Desperate to preserve what was left, the Ottomans threw in their lot with the Central Powers (Germany and Austria), only to be defeated by a British-led Arab revolt in the Near East. When the war ended the victors partitioned and dissolved the Ottoman Empire at the Paris Peace Conference. However, the Turkish Revolution prevented the planned division of Anatolia from taking place. With the creation of the nation of Turkey in 1922, and the deposition of the final sultan Mehmed VI, the Ottoman Empire came to a close.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Ottoman Empire was a Turkish state situated upon the eastern Mediterranean that lasted for some 630 years, from 1299 - 1922 AD. At the height of its power, in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, the Ottoman domains stretched across vast regions in Anatolia, the Balkans, the Near East and northern Africa. For several centuries it was one of the foremost military powers in the world (until it began to stagnate technologically and fell far behind its competitors).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottoman state began as a vassal of the earlier Seljuk Turks, who had formed a large empire in the Near East in the eleventh century. When the Seljuk state of Rum in Anatolia collapsed, the Ottomans took advantage of the ensuing power vacuum and rose in power. According to tradition, Osman I became the bey, or chief, of the state of Sgt in 1281. When Osman captured the Byzantine city of Bilecik in 1299, he declared his state's independence from the Seljuks. This is the traditional date given as the foundation of the Ottoman Empire - which was named after its first leader, Osman.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans expanded rapidly in Anatolia throughout the fourteenth century. A series of capable military leaders made many gains against the tottering Byzantine state. The important cities of Nicaea and Nicomedia fell in 1331 and 1337, and by the 1360s the Ottomans had crossed over into Europe and began capturing territory in Thrace. As a sign of this growing power, Murad I declared himself a sultan (or king) in 1383. Around the year 1400, Timur invaded Anatolia. This caused a great deal of disruption, but the Ottomans bounced back and continued to make territorial gains. Under the rule of Mehmed II, the Ottomans attacked and captured Constantinople, whose mighty walls finally fell to the cannon of the Ottomans. This destroyed the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottomans made Constantinople their capital. Mehmed II became known as "Mehmed the Conqueror." Suleiman I, also known as Suleiman the Magnificent, continued to expand and consolidate the Empire; the Ottomans were at the height of their power and influence during his reign[PARAGRAPH:2]After the capture of Constantinople the Ottoman state virtually adopted the Byzantine civil service to run the empire, and its administration was generally sound (until the nineteenth century, when it began to fossilize and became outdated). The Ottoman Empire was very much a pre-modern dynastic state, made up of many different nationalities - in fact, Greeks largely ran its bureaucracy and were vital to its continued success. Militarily, the Ottomans were very strong largely because of their early adoption of gunpowder and their powerful cavalry forces. The military also employed elite slave soldiers known as "janissaries" who won victory after victory for the expanding Ottoman state. The military remained powerful until the late eighteenth century, when they fell fatally behind Western Europe in military technology.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans were known for their religious tolerance. The Empire was an Islamic state, and Islamic law dominated its legal system, but non-Muslims were generally well treated and enjoyed the freedom to worship their own religion. The Ottoman Empire was long seen as a refuge for Jews across Europe. Economically, the Ottoman Empire was somewhat of a failure. Most of the region's commerce was carried on by Greek or Italian merchants, which slowed the development of Turkish industry. Once the European voyages of exploration found new routes to India and China which did not involve passing through the Near East, the Ottoman Empire began a slow commercial decline.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the start of the nineteenth century, the Ottoman Empire still held enormous amounts of land, but the empire was stagnant and corrupt, and was widely viewed as the "sick man of Europe." The western powers, their commercial and military strength exploding under the influence of the Industrial Revolution, began to snap up vulnerable Ottoman territories. Britain and France forced humiliating commercial treaties on the Ottomans, and the Ottoman state was forced to take out massive loans to cover its debts - the start of a vicious cycle which only incurred more debt for the empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]While some positive reforms were carried out in terms of modernizing the Ottoman state, custom and tradition prevented the reformers from moving fast enough. Furthermore, the rising tide of nationalism began to tear the empire apart, as Serbians, Bulgarians, Romanians, and Greeks all declared their independence and set up their own nations. By the outbreak of World War I, the Ottomans had lost virtually all of their holdings in Europe. Desperate to preserve what was left, the Ottomans threw in their lot with the Central Powers (Germany and Austria), only to be defeated by a British-led Arab revolt in the Near East. When the war ended the victors partitioned and dissolved the Ottoman Empire at the Paris Peace Conference. However, the Turkish Revolution prevented the planned division of Anatolia from taking place. With the creation of the nation of Turkey in 1922, and the deposition of the final sultan Mehmed VI, the Ottoman Empire came to a close.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Ottoman -->
  <!-- Civilization Sweden -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Swedish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>瑞典文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Sweden</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>瑞典</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Swedish:Swedish</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>瑞典</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SWEDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Little is known of Swedish history before the Viking period of the late 8th century. Two related peoples, the Svear and the Gtar, then lived in south central Sweden. Almost incessantly at war with each other, they united in the 9th century under the control of Svear. The Swedish name for Sweden, Sverige, means "realm of the Svear." Swedish Vikings sailed eastward across the Baltic Sea and into the rivers of Russia. By the 9th and 10th centuries they were doing business as far east as Constantinople. According to legend, a Swedish Viking chieftain, Rurik, was the creator of the first Russian monarchy. Finland came under Swedish rule in the 12th century. In 1397 the Union of Kalmar joined the kingdoms of Sweden, Denmark, and Norway under the Danish monarchy. The Swedes opposed Danish command, which ended in 1523, when Gustavus Vasa came to the Swedish throne as King Gustav I.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under Gustav I and his successors, Sweden became a martial power. Two Swedish monarchs were famed as warrior kings. Gustav II, also known as Gustavus Adolphus, won great triumphs in the Thirty Years' War. As an effect of this war, Sweden increased land in northern Germany and became master of the Baltic region. In 1638, Sweden founded a brief colony in America called New Sweden. Continually challenged by its neighbors, Sweden fought a series of wars with Denmark, Russia, Poland, and Saxony during the early 18th century. The Swedish king Charles XII won first impressive victories. But his devastating defeat by the Russian Tsar Peter the Great in 1709 commenced Sweden's decline as a European power.[PARAGRAPH:2]The loss of Finland to Russia in 1809 led to the deposition of King Gustav IV. A new constitution was adopted and a Frenchman, Jean Baptiste Bernadotte, was chosen as the Swedish crown prince. After Napoleon's defeat in 1814, Norway was taken from Denmark and given to Sweden to substitute its loss of Finland. The union of Sweden and Norway lasted until 1905, when Norway peacefully gained its independence. Bernadotte came to the throne in 1818 as King Charles XIV John and was the founder of the present Swedish royal house.[PARAGRAPH:2]The constant years of war impoverished Sweden. A lack of financial prospects caused a large number of Swedes to emigrate from the country. Sweden was never again to go to war, adopting the policy of neutrality and nonalignment that continues today. The growth of Swedish industry in the early 20th century restored its economy. Sweden also developed its social welfare system that guaranteed the needs of existence to every Swedes. Sweden was able to uphold its neutrality in both World War I and II, establishing itself as a haven for refugees escaping the damage of both these wars. Sweden has also sought to promote peace in not only itself, but in all countries. Many of Sweden's troops served in the United Nations peacekeeping forces.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]Little is known of Swedish history before the Viking period of the late 8th century. Two related peoples, the Svear and the Gtar, then lived in south central Sweden. Almost incessantly at war with each other, they united in the 9th century under the control of Svear. The Swedish name for Sweden, Sverige, means "realm of the Svear." Swedish Vikings sailed eastward across the Baltic Sea and into the rivers of Russia. By the 9th and 10th centuries they were doing business as far east as Constantinople. According to legend, a Swedish Viking chieftain, Rurik, was the creator of the first Russian monarchy. Finland came under Swedish rule in the 12th century. In 1397 the Union of Kalmar joined the kingdoms of Sweden, Denmark, and Norway under the Danish monarchy. The Swedes opposed Danish command, which ended in 1523, when Gustavus Vasa came to the Swedish throne as King Gustav I.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under Gustav I and his successors, Sweden became a martial power. Two Swedish monarchs were famed as warrior kings. Gustav II, also known as Gustavus Adolphus, won great triumphs in the Thirty Years' War. As an effect of this war, Sweden increased land in northern Germany and became master of the Baltic region. In 1638, Sweden founded a brief colony in America called New Sweden. Continually challenged by its neighbors, Sweden fought a series of wars with Denmark, Russia, Poland, and Saxony during the early 18th century. The Swedish king Charles XII won first impressive victories. But his devastating defeat by the Russian Tsar Peter the Great in 1709 commenced Sweden's decline as a European power.[PARAGRAPH:2]The loss of Finland to Russia in 1809 led to the deposition of King Gustav IV. A new constitution was adopted and a Frenchman, Jean Baptiste Bernadotte, was chosen as the Swedish crown prince. After Napoleon's defeat in 1814, Norway was taken from Denmark and given to Sweden to substitute its loss of Finland. The union of Sweden and Norway lasted until 1905, when Norway peacefully gained its independence. Bernadotte came to the throne in 1818 as King Charles XIV John and was the founder of the present Swedish royal house.[PARAGRAPH:2]The constant years of war impoverished Sweden. A lack of financial prospects caused a large number of Swedes to emigrate from the country. Sweden was never again to go to war, adopting the policy of neutrality and nonalignment that continues today. The growth of Swedish industry in the early 20th century restored its economy. Sweden also developed its social welfare system that guaranteed the needs of existence to every Swedes. Sweden was able to uphold its neutrality in both World War I and II, establishing itself as a haven for refugees escaping the damage of both these wars. Sweden has also sought to promote peace in not only itself, but in all countries. Many of Sweden's troops served in the United Nations peacekeeping forces.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Sweden -->
  <!-- Civilization Dutch -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Dutch</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>荷兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Netherlands</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>尼德兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Dutch</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>荷兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_DUTCH_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Originally several separate territories under the control of the Holy Roman Empire, and then united into one state under Habsburg rule (16th century), the Netherlands did not acquire national independence until the conclusion of the Eighty Years' War (1568-1648 AD) when the Spanish formally renounced all claims to Dutch sovereignty in the Treaty of Mnster.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Eighty Years' War was sparked by Spanish religious oppression and an occupation by Spanish forces led by the Duke of Alba, during which over one thousand people were sentenced to death, including two prominent and popular Dutch nobles; these actions caused dissention among the Dutch people. In 1568 Willem, Prince of Orange, returned from a self-imposed exile (in order to avoid prosecution by the Duke of Alba) and led the uprising against the Spanish occupation.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Dutch fight for independence can be seen as a war against religious oppression, with the Pacification of Ghent treaty being a written representation of this sentiment. Signed on November 8th, 1576 the document specified an alliance between the Dutch provinces, in which religious differences would be put aside for the purposes of expelling the Spanish and restoring local provincial control to the Netherlands.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the seventeenth century the Dutch began using their large military and merchant navies to both create their own trading posts along the African coast and rob those of the Portuguese in an effort to reach valuable markets in India and Indonesia. The inrush of treasure, trade and knowledge from these trading and military expeditions was extremely beneficial, and during this first half of the seventeenth century the Dutch experienced a Golden Age of cultural and economic growth. This Golden Age would soon come to a crushing end.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1795, France, under Napoleon I, conquered the Dutch mainland. The Netherlands quickly declined in influence and power, locally and internationally, with the British taking most of their colonial possessions. After Napoleon was defeated a few colonial territories were restored to the Dutch and remained under their control until the decolonization of the twentieth century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Many historians regard the Dutch empire as the first truly capitalist country. In addition to developing the first stock exchange, many modern services such as corporate insurance and retirement funds were attributed to Dutch inventiveness.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Netherlands is also the birthplace of one of the world's early democratic institutions - the Dutch Water Boards. Due to the unique topography of the Netherlands - about half of the mainland is a foot or more under sea level - the country's waterways must be constantly monitored and controlled in order to prevent flooding that would result in tremendous loss of life and property. Each Water Board is in charge of one of the nation's 27 water districts and all matters pertaining to local water management. The creation of these water boards predates the Netherlands itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]The modern Netherlands, with a diverse population and liberal laws towards drugs, prostitution, abortion, same-sex marriage, and euthanasia, has been a constant haven for refugees from other countries. Cultural minorities are encouraged to protect their own cultural identity while at the same time integrate into Dutch culture at large, further reinforcing the open-minded ideals for which Dutch ancestors fought and died.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]Originally several separate territories under the control of the Holy Roman Empire, and then united into one state under Habsburg rule (16th century), the Netherlands did not acquire national independence until the conclusion of the Eighty Years' War (1568-1648 AD) when the Spanish formally renounced all claims to Dutch sovereignty in the Treaty of Mnster.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Eighty Years' War was sparked by Spanish religious oppression and an occupation by Spanish forces led by the Duke of Alba, during which over one thousand people were sentenced to death, including two prominent and popular Dutch nobles; these actions caused dissention among the Dutch people. In 1568 Willem, Prince of Orange, returned from a self-imposed exile (in order to avoid prosecution by the Duke of Alba) and led the uprising against the Spanish occupation.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Dutch fight for independence can be seen as a war against religious oppression, with the Pacification of Ghent treaty being a written representation of this sentiment. Signed on November 8th, 1576 the document specified an alliance between the Dutch provinces, in which religious differences would be put aside for the purposes of expelling the Spanish and restoring local provincial control to the Netherlands.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the seventeenth century the Dutch began using their large military and merchant navies to both create their own trading posts along the African coast and rob those of the Portuguese in an effort to reach valuable markets in India and Indonesia. The inrush of treasure, trade and knowledge from these trading and military expeditions was extremely beneficial, and during this first half of the seventeenth century the Dutch experienced a Golden Age of cultural and economic growth. This Golden Age would soon come to a crushing end.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1795, France, under Napoleon I, conquered the Dutch mainland. The Netherlands quickly declined in influence and power, locally and internationally, with the British taking most of their colonial possessions. After Napoleon was defeated a few colonial territories were restored to the Dutch and remained under their control until the decolonization of the twentieth century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Many historians regard the Dutch empire as the first truly capitalist country. In addition to developing the first stock exchange, many modern services such as corporate insurance and retirement funds were attributed to Dutch inventiveness.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Netherlands is also the birthplace of one of the world's early democratic institutions - the Dutch Water Boards. Due to the unique topography of the Netherlands - about half of the mainland is a foot or more under sea level - the country's waterways must be constantly monitored and controlled in order to prevent flooding that would result in tremendous loss of life and property. Each Water Board is in charge of one of the nation's 27 water districts and all matters pertaining to local water management. The creation of these water boards predates the Netherlands itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]The modern Netherlands, with a diverse population and liberal laws towards drugs, prostitution, abortion, same-sex marriage, and euthanasia, has been a constant haven for refugees from other countries. Cultural minorities are encouraged to protect their own cultural identity while at the same time integrate into Dutch culture at large, further reinforcing the open-minded ideals for which Dutch ancestors fought and died.</Chinese>
    </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Dutch -->
  <!-- Civilization Lithuania -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Lithuanians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>立陶宛文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Lithuania</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>立陶宛</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Lithuanian:Lithuanians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>立陶宛</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LITHUANIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The history of Lithuania between 1219 and 1295 deals with the establishment and early history of the first Lithuanian state, the Grand Duchy of Lithuania. The beginning of the 13th century marks the end of the prehistory of Lithuania. From this point on the history of Lithuania is recorded in chronicles, treaties, and other written documents. In 1219, twenty-one Lithuanian dukes signed a peace treaty with Halych-Volhynia. This event is widely accepted as the first proof that the Baltic tribes were uniting and consolidating.[PARAGRAPH:2]Mindaugas, the duke who governed southern Lithuania between the Neman and Neris Rivers, eventually became the founder of the state. Mindaugas is referred to as the ruler of all Lithuania in the Livonian Rhymed Chronicle in 1236. The means by which he managed to acquire this title are not well-known. In 1251, Mindaugas agreed to receive baptism and relinquish control over some lands in western Lithuania, for which he was to receive a crown in return. As promised, Mindaugas was crowned at some time during the summer of 1253 (The exact date and location of the coronation is not known), and the Kingdom of Lithuania, proclaimed by the pope in 1251, was soundly established. Pope Innocent IV supported Mindaugas, hoping that a new Christian state could stem the inroads being made by the Golden Horde, a state of Mongol Empire. On July 17, 1251, the pope signed two crucial papal bulls. One of them ordered the Bishop of Chelm to crown Mindaugas as King of Lithuania, appoint a bishop for Lithuania, and to build a cathedral.[PARAGRAPH:2]Immediately after his coronation, Mindaugas transferred some western lands to the Livonian Order - portions of Samogitia, Nadruva, and Dainava. There is some discussion as to whether in later years Mindaugas gave even more lands to the Order. Relative peace and stability was established for about eight more years. Mindaugas used this opportunity to concentrate on expansion to the east. The Livonian Order used this period to consolidate their control over Samogitian lands. The Samogitians responded by electing Algminas as their war leader. In 1259, the Livonian Order lost the Battle of Skuodas, and in 1260, it lost the Battle of Durbe. The first loss encouraged a rebellion by the Semigalians, and the later loss spurred the Prussians into an uprising against the Order. Encouraged by Treniota, his nephew, Mindaugas broke peace with the Order. Some chronicles hint that he also relapsed into his former pagan beliefs. All the diplomatic achievements made since his coronation were lost. As a result of the war, Mindaugas was assassinated by the Order and Lithuania lapsed into political chaos.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1295, a new dynasty rose: the Gediminids. The Gediminids were to rule Lithuania for the next several centuries. Vytenis, the first Gediminid ruler, was able to recapture lands lost after the death of Mindaugus, and established a defensive network along his border with the Teutonic Order. Lithuanian expansion reached its height under Gediminas, who annexed or vassalized most of Kieven Rus, and parts of the Golden Horde. Lithuania reached its peak under Vytautas the Great, who backed economic development of his state and introduced many reforms. Under his rule the Grand Duchy of Lithuania slowly became more centralized, as the governors loyal to Vytautas replaced local princes with dynastic ties to the throne. Under Vytautas, Lithuanian and Polish forces defeated the Teutonic Order.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, in the 16th century, Moscow began making aggressive expansion west, and Lithuania developed closer ties with Poland, eventually unifying under the Treaty of Lublin. However, after the partitions of Poland, Lithuania was annexed by Russia. During the Napoleonic Wars, French forces proclaimed a new Grand Duchy, which never materialized, as shorty afterwards Napoleon's forces were pushed west by the Russians, who again annexed Lithuania. Lithuania remained part of Russia until after World War I, where it was formed as a new Republic. During World War II, however, Soviet forces annexed Lithuania. Following a brief occupation by Nazi forces shortly afterwards, Lithuania was absorbed into the USSR. In the early 1990s, Lithuania restored its sovereignty and now continues to grow into an economically strong country.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The history of Lithuania between 1219 and 1295 deals with the establishment and early history of the first Lithuanian state, the Grand Duchy of Lithuania. The beginning of the 13th century marks the end of the prehistory of Lithuania. From this point on the history of Lithuania is recorded in chronicles, treaties, and other written documents. In 1219, twenty-one Lithuanian dukes signed a peace treaty with Halych-Volhynia. This event is widely accepted as the first proof that the Baltic tribes were uniting and consolidating.[PARAGRAPH:2]Mindaugas, the duke who governed southern Lithuania between the Neman and Neris Rivers, eventually became the founder of the state. Mindaugas is referred to as the ruler of all Lithuania in the Livonian Rhymed Chronicle in 1236. The means by which he managed to acquire this title are not well-known. In 1251, Mindaugas agreed to receive baptism and relinquish control over some lands in western Lithuania, for which he was to receive a crown in return. As promised, Mindaugas was crowned at some time during the summer of 1253 (The exact date and location of the coronation is not known), and the Kingdom of Lithuania, proclaimed by the pope in 1251, was soundly established. Pope Innocent IV supported Mindaugas, hoping that a new Christian state could stem the inroads being made by the Golden Horde, a state of Mongol Empire. On July 17, 1251, the pope signed two crucial papal bulls. One of them ordered the Bishop of Chelm to crown Mindaugas as King of Lithuania, appoint a bishop for Lithuania, and to build a cathedral.[PARAGRAPH:2]Immediately after his coronation, Mindaugas transferred some western lands to the Livonian Order - portions of Samogitia, Nadruva, and Dainava. There is some discussion as to whether in later years Mindaugas gave even more lands to the Order. Relative peace and stability was established for about eight more years. Mindaugas used this opportunity to concentrate on expansion to the east. The Livonian Order used this period to consolidate their control over Samogitian lands. The Samogitians responded by electing Algminas as their war leader. In 1259, the Livonian Order lost the Battle of Skuodas, and in 1260, it lost the Battle of Durbe. The first loss encouraged a rebellion by the Semigalians, and the later loss spurred the Prussians into an uprising against the Order. Encouraged by Treniota, his nephew, Mindaugas broke peace with the Order. Some chronicles hint that he also relapsed into his former pagan beliefs. All the diplomatic achievements made since his coronation were lost. As a result of the war, Mindaugas was assassinated by the Order and Lithuania lapsed into political chaos.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1295, a new dynasty rose: the Gediminids. The Gediminids were to rule Lithuania for the next several centuries. Vytenis, the first Gediminid ruler, was able to recapture lands lost after the death of Mindaugus, and established a defensive network along his border with the Teutonic Order. Lithuanian expansion reached its height under Gediminas, who annexed or vassalized most of Kieven Rus, and parts of the Golden Horde. Lithuania reached its peak under Vytautas the Great, who backed economic development of his state and introduced many reforms. Under his rule the Grand Duchy of Lithuania slowly became more centralized, as the governors loyal to Vytautas replaced local princes with dynastic ties to the throne. Under Vytautas, Lithuanian and Polish forces defeated the Teutonic Order.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, in the 16th century, Moscow began making aggressive expansion west, and Lithuania developed closer ties with Poland, eventually unifying under the Treaty of Lublin. However, after the partitions of Poland, Lithuania was annexed by Russia. During the Napoleonic Wars, French forces proclaimed a new Grand Duchy, which never materialized, as shorty afterwards Napoleon's forces were pushed west by the Russians, who again annexed Lithuania. Lithuania remained part of Russia until after World War I, where it was formed as a new Republic. During World War II, however, Soviet forces annexed Lithuania. Following a brief occupation by Nazi forces shortly afterwards, Lithuania was absorbed into the USSR. In the early 1990s, Lithuania restored its sovereignty and now continues to grow into an economically strong country.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Lithuania -->
  <!-- Civilization Scotland -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Scottish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>苏格兰文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Scotland</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>苏格兰</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Scottish</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>苏格兰人</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SCOTLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Kingdom of the Picts (based in Fortriu by the 6th century) was the state that eventually became known as "Alba" or "Scotland". The development of "Pictland", according to the historical model developed by Peter Heather, was a natural response to Roman imperialism. Another view places emphasis on the Battle of Dun Nechtain, and the reign of Bridei m. Beli (671-693), with another period of consolidation in the reign of engus mac Fergusa (732-761).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Kingdom of the Picts as it was in the early 8th century, when Bede was writing, was largely the same as the kingdom of the Scots in the reign of Alexander I (1107-1124). However, by the tenth century, the Pictish kingdom was dominated by what we can recognise as Gaelic culture, and had developed a traditional story of an Irish conquest around the ancestor of the contemporary royal dynasty, Cined mac Ailpn (Kenneth MacAlpin).[PARAGRAPH:2]From a base of territory in eastern Scotland north of the River Forth and south of the River Oykel, the kingdom acquired control of the lands lying to the north and south. By the 12th century, the kings of Alba had added to their territories the English-speaking land in the south-east and attained overlordship of Gaelic-speaking Galloway and Norse-speaking Caithness; by the end of the 13th century, the kingdom had assumed approximately its modern borders. However, processes of cultural and economic change beginning in the 12th century ensured Scotland looked very different in the later Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]The push for this change was the reign of David I and the Davidian Revolution. Feudalism, government reorganisation and the first legally recognised towns (called burghs) began in this period. These institutions and the immigration of French and Anglo-French knights and churchmen facilitated cultural osmosis, whereby the culture and language of the low-lying and coastal parts of the kingdom's original territory in the east became, like the newly acquired south-east, English-speaking, while the rest of the country retained the Gaelic language, apart from the Northern Isles of Orkney and Shetland, which remained under Norse rule until 1468. The Scottish state entered a largely successful and stable period between the 12th and 14th centuries, there was relative peace with England, trade and educational links were well developed with the Continent and at the height of this cultural flowering John Duns Scotus was one of Europe's most important and influential philosophers.[PARAGRAPH:2]The death of Alexander III in March 1286, followed by that of his granddaughter Margaret, Maid of Norway, broke the centuries-old succession line of Scotland's kings and shattered the 200-year golden age that began with David I. Edward I of England was asked to arbitrate between claimants for the Scottish crown, and he organised a process known as the Great Cause to identify the most legitimate claimant. John Balliol was pronounced king in the Great Hall of Berwick Castle on 17 November 1292 and inaugurated at Scone on 30 November, St. Andrew's Day. Edward I, who had coerced recognition as Lord Paramount of Scotland, the feudal superior of the realm, steadily undermined John's authority. In 1294, Balliol and other Scottish lords refused Edward's demands to serve in his army against the French. Instead the Scottish parliament sent envoys to France to negotiate an alliance. Scotland and France sealed a treaty on 23 October 1295, known as the Auld Alliance (1295-1560). War ensued and King John was deposed by Edward who took personal control of Scotland. Andrew Moray and William Wallace initially emerged as the principal leaders of the resistance to English rule in what became known as the Wars of Scottish Independence (1296-1328).[PARAGRAPH:2]The nature of the struggle changed significantly when Robert the Bruce, Earl of Carrick, killed his rival John Comyn on 10 February 1306 at Greyfriars Kirk in Dumfries. He was crowned king (as Robert I) less than seven weeks later. Robert I battled to restore Scottish Independence as King for over 20 years, beginning by winning Scotland back from the Norman English invaders piece by piece. Victory at the Battle of Bannockburn in 1314 proved the Scots had regained control of their kingdom. In 1315, Edward Bruce, brother of the King, was briefly appointed High King of Ireland during an ultimately unsuccessful Scottish invasion of Ireland aimed at strengthening Scotland's position in its wars against England. In 1320 the world's first documented declaration of independence, the Declaration of Arbroath, won the support of Pope John XXII, leading to the legal recognition of Scottish sovereignty by the English Crown.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, war with England continued for several decades after the death of Bruce. A civil war between the Bruce dynasty and their long-term Comyn-Balliol rivals lasted until the middle of the 14th century. Although the Bruce dynasty was successful, David II's lack of an heir allowed his half-nephew Robert II to come to the throne and establish the Stewart Dynasty. The Stewarts ruled Scotland for the remainder of the Middle Ages. The country they ruled experienced greater prosperity from the end of the 14th century through the Scottish Renaissance to the Reformation. This was despite continual warfare with England, the increasing division between Highlands and Lowlands, and a large number of royal minorities.[PARAGRAPH:2]This period was the height of the Franco-Scottish alliance. The Scots Guard - la Garde cossaise - was founded in 1418 by Charles VII of France. The Scots soldiers of the Garde cossaise fought alongside Joan of Arc against England during the Hundred Years War. In March 1421, a Franco-Scots force under John Stewart, 2nd Earl of Buchan, and Gilbert de Lafayette, defeated a larger English army at the Battle of Baug? Three years later, at the Battle of Verneuil, the French and Scots lost around 7000 men. The Scottish intervention contributed to France's victory in the war.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1502, James IV of Scotland signed the Treaty of Perpetual Peace with Henry VII of England. He also married Henry's daughter, Margaret Tudor, setting the stage for the Union of the Crowns. For Henry, the marriage into one of Europe's most established monarchies gave legitimacy to the new Tudor royal line. A decade later, James made the fateful decision to invade England in support of France under the terms of the Auld Alliance. He was the last British monarch to die in battle, at the Battle of Flodden. Within a generation the Auld Alliance was ended by the Treaty of Edinburgh. France agreed to withdraw all land and naval forces. In the same year, 1560, John Knox realised his goal of seeing Scotland become a Protestant nation and the Scottish parliament revoke papal authority in Scotland. Mary, Queen of Scots, a Catholic and former queen of France, was forced to abdicate in 1567.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1603, James VI, King of Scots inherited the thrones of the Kingdom of England and the Kingdom of Ireland, and became King James I of England and Ireland, and left Edinburgh for London. With the exception of a short period under the Protectorate, Scotland remained a separate state, but there was considerable conflict between the crown and the Covenanters over the form of church government. The Glorious Revolution of 1688-89 saw the overthrow of the King James VII of Scotland and II of England by the English Parliament in favour of William and Mary. As late as the 1690s, Scotland experienced famine, which reduced the population of parts of the country by at least 20 per cent.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1698, the Scots attempted an ambitious project to secure a trading colony on the Isthmus of Panama. Almost every Scottish landowner who had money to spare is said to have invested in the Darien scheme. Its failure bankrupted these landowners, but not the burghs. Nevertheless, the nobles' bankruptcy, along with the threat of an English invasion, played a leading role in convincing the Scots elite to back a union with England.[PARAGRAPH:2]On 22 July 1706, the Treaty of Union was agreed between representatives of the Scots Parliament and the Parliament of England and the following year twin Acts of Union were passed by both parliaments to create the united Kingdom of Great Britain with effect from 1 May 1707.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]The Kingdom of the Picts (based in Fortriu by the 6th century) was the state that eventually became known as "Alba" or "Scotland". The development of "Pictland", according to the historical model developed by Peter Heather, was a natural response to Roman imperialism. Another view places emphasis on the Battle of Dun Nechtain, and the reign of Bridei m. Beli (671-693), with another period of consolidation in the reign of engus mac Fergusa (732-761).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Kingdom of the Picts as it was in the early 8th century, when Bede was writing, was largely the same as the kingdom of the Scots in the reign of Alexander I (1107-1124). However, by the tenth century, the Pictish kingdom was dominated by what we can recognise as Gaelic culture, and had developed a traditional story of an Irish conquest around the ancestor of the contemporary royal dynasty, Cined mac Ailpn (Kenneth MacAlpin).[PARAGRAPH:2]From a base of territory in eastern Scotland north of the River Forth and south of the River Oykel, the kingdom acquired control of the lands lying to the north and south. By the 12th century, the kings of Alba had added to their territories the English-speaking land in the south-east and attained overlordship of Gaelic-speaking Galloway and Norse-speaking Caithness; by the end of the 13th century, the kingdom had assumed approximately its modern borders. However, processes of cultural and economic change beginning in the 12th century ensured Scotland looked very different in the later Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]The push for this change was the reign of David I and the Davidian Revolution. Feudalism, government reorganisation and the first legally recognised towns (called burghs) began in this period. These institutions and the immigration of French and Anglo-French knights and churchmen facilitated cultural osmosis, whereby the culture and language of the low-lying and coastal parts of the kingdom's original territory in the east became, like the newly acquired south-east, English-speaking, while the rest of the country retained the Gaelic language, apart from the Northern Isles of Orkney and Shetland, which remained under Norse rule until 1468. The Scottish state entered a largely successful and stable period between the 12th and 14th centuries, there was relative peace with England, trade and educational links were well developed with the Continent and at the height of this cultural flowering John Duns Scotus was one of Europe's most important and influential philosophers.[PARAGRAPH:2]The death of Alexander III in March 1286, followed by that of his granddaughter Margaret, Maid of Norway, broke the centuries-old succession line of Scotland's kings and shattered the 200-year golden age that began with David I. Edward I of England was asked to arbitrate between claimants for the Scottish crown, and he organised a process known as the Great Cause to identify the most legitimate claimant. John Balliol was pronounced king in the Great Hall of Berwick Castle on 17 November 1292 and inaugurated at Scone on 30 November, St. Andrew's Day. Edward I, who had coerced recognition as Lord Paramount of Scotland, the feudal superior of the realm, steadily undermined John's authority. In 1294, Balliol and other Scottish lords refused Edward's demands to serve in his army against the French. Instead the Scottish parliament sent envoys to France to negotiate an alliance. Scotland and France sealed a treaty on 23 October 1295, known as the Auld Alliance (1295-1560). War ensued and King John was deposed by Edward who took personal control of Scotland. Andrew Moray and William Wallace initially emerged as the principal leaders of the resistance to English rule in what became known as the Wars of Scottish Independence (1296-1328).[PARAGRAPH:2]The nature of the struggle changed significantly when Robert the Bruce, Earl of Carrick, killed his rival John Comyn on 10 February 1306 at Greyfriars Kirk in Dumfries. He was crowned king (as Robert I) less than seven weeks later. Robert I battled to restore Scottish Independence as King for over 20 years, beginning by winning Scotland back from the Norman English invaders piece by piece. Victory at the Battle of Bannockburn in 1314 proved the Scots had regained control of their kingdom. In 1315, Edward Bruce, brother of the King, was briefly appointed High King of Ireland during an ultimately unsuccessful Scottish invasion of Ireland aimed at strengthening Scotland's position in its wars against England. In 1320 the world's first documented declaration of independence, the Declaration of Arbroath, won the support of Pope John XXII, leading to the legal recognition of Scottish sovereignty by the English Crown.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, war with England continued for several decades after the death of Bruce. A civil war between the Bruce dynasty and their long-term Comyn-Balliol rivals lasted until the middle of the 14th century. Although the Bruce dynasty was successful, David II's lack of an heir allowed his half-nephew Robert II to come to the throne and establish the Stewart Dynasty. The Stewarts ruled Scotland for the remainder of the Middle Ages. The country they ruled experienced greater prosperity from the end of the 14th century through the Scottish Renaissance to the Reformation. This was despite continual warfare with England, the increasing division between Highlands and Lowlands, and a large number of royal minorities.[PARAGRAPH:2]This period was the height of the Franco-Scottish alliance. The Scots Guard - la Garde cossaise - was founded in 1418 by Charles VII of France. The Scots soldiers of the Garde cossaise fought alongside Joan of Arc against England during the Hundred Years War. In March 1421, a Franco-Scots force under John Stewart, 2nd Earl of Buchan, and Gilbert de Lafayette, defeated a larger English army at the Battle of Baug? Three years later, at the Battle of Verneuil, the French and Scots lost around 7000 men. The Scottish intervention contributed to France's victory in the war.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1502, James IV of Scotland signed the Treaty of Perpetual Peace with Henry VII of England. He also married Henry's daughter, Margaret Tudor, setting the stage for the Union of the Crowns. For Henry, the marriage into one of Europe's most established monarchies gave legitimacy to the new Tudor royal line. A decade later, James made the fateful decision to invade England in support of France under the terms of the Auld Alliance. He was the last British monarch to die in battle, at the Battle of Flodden. Within a generation the Auld Alliance was ended by the Treaty of Edinburgh. France agreed to withdraw all land and naval forces. In the same year, 1560, John Knox realised his goal of seeing Scotland become a Protestant nation and the Scottish parliament revoke papal authority in Scotland. Mary, Queen of Scots, a Catholic and former queen of France, was forced to abdicate in 1567.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1603, James VI, King of Scots inherited the thrones of the Kingdom of England and the Kingdom of Ireland, and became King James I of England and Ireland, and left Edinburgh for London. With the exception of a short period under the Protectorate, Scotland remained a separate state, but there was considerable conflict between the crown and the Covenanters over the form of church government. The Glorious Revolution of 1688-89 saw the overthrow of the King James VII of Scotland and II of England by the English Parliament in favour of William and Mary. As late as the 1690s, Scotland experienced famine, which reduced the population of parts of the country by at least 20 per cent.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1698, the Scots attempted an ambitious project to secure a trading colony on the Isthmus of Panama. Almost every Scottish landowner who had money to spare is said to have invested in the Darien scheme. Its failure bankrupted these landowners, but not the burghs. Nevertheless, the nobles' bankruptcy, along with the threat of an English invasion, played a leading role in convincing the Scots elite to back a union with England.[PARAGRAPH:2]On 22 July 1706, the Treaty of Union was agreed between representatives of the Scots Parliament and the Parliament of England and the following year twin Acts of Union were passed by both parliaments to create the united Kingdom of Great Britain with effect from 1 May 1707.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Scotland -->
  <!-- Civilization Novgorod -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Novgorodians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Novgorod</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Novgorodian:Novgorodians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>诺夫哥罗德</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NOVGOROD_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Slightly predating the chronology of the legend of Rurik (which dates the first Norse arrival in the region around 858-860), an earlier record for the Scandinavian settlement of the region is found in the Annales Bertiniani (written up until 882) where a Rus' delegation is mentioned as having visited Constantinople in 838 and, intending to return to the Rus' Khaganate via the Baltic Sea, were questioned by Frankish Emperor Louis the Pious at Ingelheim am Rhein, where they said that although their origin was Swedish, they had settled in Northern Rus' under a leader who they designated as chacanus (the Latin form of Khagan, a title they had likely borrowed from contact with the Avars).[PARAGRAPH:2]In 882, Rurik's successor, Oleg of Novgorod, conquered Kiev and founded the state of Kievan Rus'. Novgorod's size as well as its political, economic, and cultural influence made it the second most important city in Kievan Rus'. According to a custom, the elder son and heir of the ruling Kievan monarch was sent to rule Novgorod even as a minor. When the ruling monarch had no such son, Novgorod was governed by posadniks, such as the legendary Gostomysl, Dobrynya, Konstantin, and Ostromir.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of all their princes, Novgorodians most cherished the memory of Yaroslav the Wise, who sat as Prince of Novgorod from 1010 to 1019, while his father, Vladimir the Great, was a prince in Kiev. Yaroslav promulgated the first written code of laws (later incorporated into Russkaya Pravda) among the Eastern Slavs and is said to have granted the city a number of freedoms or privileges, which they often referred to in later centuries as precedents in their relations with other princes. His son, Vladimir, sponsored construction of the great St. Sophia Cathedral, more accurately translated as the Cathedral of Holy Wisdom, which stands to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In Norse sagas the city is mentioned as the capital of Gardariki. Four Viking kings-Olaf I of Norway, Olaf II of Norway, Magnus I of Norway, and Harald Hardrada-sought refuge in Novgorod from enemies at home. No more than a few decades after the 1030 death and subsequent canonization of Olaf II of Norway, the city's community had erected in his memory Saint Olaf's Church in Novgorod.[PARAGRAPH:2]The town of Visby in Gotland functioned as the leading trading center in the Baltic before the Hansa League. At Novgorod in 1080, Visby merchants established a trading post which they named Gutagard (also known as Gotenhof). Later, in the first half of the 13th century, merchants from northern Germany also established their own trading station in Novgorod, known as Peterhof. At about the same time, in 1229, German merchants at Novgorod were granted certain privileges, which made their position more secure.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1136, the Novgorodians dismissed their prince Vsevolod Mstislavich. The year is seen as the traditional beginning of the Novgorod Republic. The city was able to invite and dismiss a number of princes over the next two centuries, but the princely office was never abolished and powerful princes, such as Alexander Nevsky, could assert their will in the city regardless of what Novgorodians' said. The city state controlled most of Europe's northeast, from lands east of today's Estonia to the Ural Mountains, making it one of the largest states in medieval Europe, although much of the territory north and east of Lakes Ladoga and Onega was sparsely populated and never organized politically.[PARAGRAPH:2]One of the most important local figures in Novgorod was the posadnik, or mayor, an official elected by the public assembly (called the Veche) from among the city's boyarstvo, or aristocracy. The tysyatsky, or "thousandman", originally the head of the town militia but later a commercial and judicial official, was also elected by the Veche. Another important local official was the Archbishop of Novgorod who shared power with the boyars. Archbishops were elected by the Veche or by the drawing of lots, and after their election, were sent to the metropolitan for consecration.[PARAGRAPH:2]While a basic outline of the various officials and the Veche can be drawn up, the city-state's exact political constitution remains unknown. The boyars and the archbishop ruled the city together, although where one official's power ended and another's began is uncertain. The prince, although his power was reduced from around the middle of the 12th century, was represented by his namestnik, or lieutenant, and still played important roles as a military commander, legislator and jurist. The exact composition of the Veche, too, is uncertain, with some historians, such as Vasily Klyuchevsky, claiming it was democratic in nature, while later scholars, such as Marxists Valentin Ianin and Aleksandr Khoroshev, see it as a "sham democracy" controlled by the ruling elite.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 13th century, Novgorod, while not a member of the Hanseatic League, was the easternmost kontor, or entrepot, of the league, being the source of enormous quantities of luxury (sable, ermine, fox, marmot) and non-luxury furs (squirrel pelts).[PARAGRAPH:2]Throughout the Middle Ages, the city thrived culturally. A large number of birch bark letters have been unearthed in excavations, perhaps suggesting widespread literacy, although this is uncertain (some scholars suggest that a clerical or scribal elite wrote them on behalf of a largely illiterate populace). It was in Novgorod that the Novgorod Codex, the oldest Slavic book written north of Macedonia, and the oldest inscription in a Finnic language (Birch bark letter no. 292) were unearthed. Some of the most ancient Russian chronicles (Novgorod First Chronicle) were written in the scriptorium of the archbishops who also promoted iconography and patronized church construction. The Novgorod merchant Sadko became a popular hero of Russian folklore.[PARAGRAPH:2]Novgorod was never conquered by the Mongols during the Mongol invasion of Rus. The Mongol army turned back about 200 kilometers (120 mi) from the city, not because of the city's strength, but probably because the Mongol commanders did not want to get bogged down in the marshlands surrounding the city. However, the grand princes of Moscow, who acted as tax collectors for the khans of the Golden Horde, did collect tribute in Novgorod, most notably Yury Danilovich and his brother, Ivan Kalita.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1259, Hordes tax-collectors and census-takers arrived in the city, leading to political disturbances and forcing Alexander Nevsky to punish a number of town officials (he cut off their noses) for defying him as Grand Prince of Vladimir (soon to be the khan's tax-collector in Russia) and his Mongol overlords. In the 14th century, raids by Novgorod pirates, or ushkuiniki, sowed fear as far as Kazan and Astrakhan, assisting Novgorod in wars with the Grand Duchy of Moscow.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the era of Old Rus' State, Novgorod was a trade hub at the northern end of both the Volga trade route and the "route from the Varangians to the Greeks" along the Dnieper river system. A vast array of goods were transported along these routes and exchanged with local Novgorod merchants and other traders. The farmers of Gotland retained the Saint Olof trading house well into the 12th century. Later German merchantmen also established tradinghouses in Novgorod. Scandinavian royalty would intermarry with Russian princes and princesses.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the great schism, Novgorod struggled from the beginning of the 13th century against Swedish, Danish, and German crusaders. During the Swedish-Novgorodian Wars, the Swedes invaded lands where some of the population had earlier paid tribute to Novgorod. The Germans had been trying to conquer the Baltic region since the late 12th century. Novgorod went to war 26 times with Sweden and 11 times with the Livonian Brothers of the Sword. The German knights, along with Danish and Swedish feudal lords, launched a series of uncoordinated attacks in 1240-1242. Novgorodian sources mention that a Swedish army was defeated in the Battle of the Neva in 1240. The Baltic German campaigns ended in failure after the Battle on the Ice in 1242. After the foundation of the castle of Viborg in 1293 the Swedes gained a foothold in Karelia. On August 12, 1323, Sweden and Novgorod signed the Treaty of Nteborg, regulating their border for the first time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The city's downfall occurred partially as a result of its inability to feed its large population, making it dependent on the Vladimir-Suzdal region for grain. The main cities in the area, Moscow and Tver, used this dependence to gain control over Novgorod. Eventually Ivan III forcibly annexed the city to the Grand Duchy of Moscow in 1478. The Veche was dissolved and a significant part of Novgorod's population was either killed or deported. The Hanseatic League kontor was closed in 1494 and the goods stored there were seized by Muscovite forces.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]Slightly predating the chronology of the legend of Rurik (which dates the first Norse arrival in the region around 858-860), an earlier record for the Scandinavian settlement of the region is found in the Annales Bertiniani (written up until 882) where a Rus' delegation is mentioned as having visited Constantinople in 838 and, intending to return to the Rus' Khaganate via the Baltic Sea, were questioned by Frankish Emperor Louis the Pious at Ingelheim am Rhein, where they said that although their origin was Swedish, they had settled in Northern Rus' under a leader who they designated as chacanus (the Latin form of Khagan, a title they had likely borrowed from contact with the Avars).[PARAGRAPH:2]In 882, Rurik's successor, Oleg of Novgorod, conquered Kiev and founded the state of Kievan Rus'. Novgorod's size as well as its political, economic, and cultural influence made it the second most important city in Kievan Rus'. According to a custom, the elder son and heir of the ruling Kievan monarch was sent to rule Novgorod even as a minor. When the ruling monarch had no such son, Novgorod was governed by posadniks, such as the legendary Gostomysl, Dobrynya, Konstantin, and Ostromir.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of all their princes, Novgorodians most cherished the memory of Yaroslav the Wise, who sat as Prince of Novgorod from 1010 to 1019, while his father, Vladimir the Great, was a prince in Kiev. Yaroslav promulgated the first written code of laws (later incorporated into Russkaya Pravda) among the Eastern Slavs and is said to have granted the city a number of freedoms or privileges, which they often referred to in later centuries as precedents in their relations with other princes. His son, Vladimir, sponsored construction of the great St. Sophia Cathedral, more accurately translated as the Cathedral of Holy Wisdom, which stands to this day.[PARAGRAPH:2]In Norse sagas the city is mentioned as the capital of Gardariki. Four Viking kings-Olaf I of Norway, Olaf II of Norway, Magnus I of Norway, and Harald Hardrada-sought refuge in Novgorod from enemies at home. No more than a few decades after the 1030 death and subsequent canonization of Olaf II of Norway, the city's community had erected in his memory Saint Olaf's Church in Novgorod.[PARAGRAPH:2]The town of Visby in Gotland functioned as the leading trading center in the Baltic before the Hansa League. At Novgorod in 1080, Visby merchants established a trading post which they named Gutagard (also known as Gotenhof). Later, in the first half of the 13th century, merchants from northern Germany also established their own trading station in Novgorod, known as Peterhof. At about the same time, in 1229, German merchants at Novgorod were granted certain privileges, which made their position more secure.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1136, the Novgorodians dismissed their prince Vsevolod Mstislavich. The year is seen as the traditional beginning of the Novgorod Republic. The city was able to invite and dismiss a number of princes over the next two centuries, but the princely office was never abolished and powerful princes, such as Alexander Nevsky, could assert their will in the city regardless of what Novgorodians' said. The city state controlled most of Europe's northeast, from lands east of today's Estonia to the Ural Mountains, making it one of the largest states in medieval Europe, although much of the territory north and east of Lakes Ladoga and Onega was sparsely populated and never organized politically.[PARAGRAPH:2]One of the most important local figures in Novgorod was the posadnik, or mayor, an official elected by the public assembly (called the Veche) from among the city's boyarstvo, or aristocracy. The tysyatsky, or "thousandman", originally the head of the town militia but later a commercial and judicial official, was also elected by the Veche. Another important local official was the Archbishop of Novgorod who shared power with the boyars. Archbishops were elected by the Veche or by the drawing of lots, and after their election, were sent to the metropolitan for consecration.[PARAGRAPH:2]While a basic outline of the various officials and the Veche can be drawn up, the city-state's exact political constitution remains unknown. The boyars and the archbishop ruled the city together, although where one official's power ended and another's began is uncertain. The prince, although his power was reduced from around the middle of the 12th century, was represented by his namestnik, or lieutenant, and still played important roles as a military commander, legislator and jurist. The exact composition of the Veche, too, is uncertain, with some historians, such as Vasily Klyuchevsky, claiming it was democratic in nature, while later scholars, such as Marxists Valentin Ianin and Aleksandr Khoroshev, see it as a "sham democracy" controlled by the ruling elite.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 13th century, Novgorod, while not a member of the Hanseatic League, was the easternmost kontor, or entrepot, of the league, being the source of enormous quantities of luxury (sable, ermine, fox, marmot) and non-luxury furs (squirrel pelts).[PARAGRAPH:2]Throughout the Middle Ages, the city thrived culturally. A large number of birch bark letters have been unearthed in excavations, perhaps suggesting widespread literacy, although this is uncertain (some scholars suggest that a clerical or scribal elite wrote them on behalf of a largely illiterate populace). It was in Novgorod that the Novgorod Codex, the oldest Slavic book written north of Macedonia, and the oldest inscription in a Finnic language (Birch bark letter no. 292) were unearthed. Some of the most ancient Russian chronicles (Novgorod First Chronicle) were written in the scriptorium of the archbishops who also promoted iconography and patronized church construction. The Novgorod merchant Sadko became a popular hero of Russian folklore.[PARAGRAPH:2]Novgorod was never conquered by the Mongols during the Mongol invasion of Rus. The Mongol army turned back about 200 kilometers (120 mi) from the city, not because of the city's strength, but probably because the Mongol commanders did not want to get bogged down in the marshlands surrounding the city. However, the grand princes of Moscow, who acted as tax collectors for the khans of the Golden Horde, did collect tribute in Novgorod, most notably Yury Danilovich and his brother, Ivan Kalita.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1259, Hordes tax-collectors and census-takers arrived in the city, leading to political disturbances and forcing Alexander Nevsky to punish a number of town officials (he cut off their noses) for defying him as Grand Prince of Vladimir (soon to be the khan's tax-collector in Russia) and his Mongol overlords. In the 14th century, raids by Novgorod pirates, or ushkuiniki, sowed fear as far as Kazan and Astrakhan, assisting Novgorod in wars with the Grand Duchy of Moscow.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the era of Old Rus' State, Novgorod was a trade hub at the northern end of both the Volga trade route and the "route from the Varangians to the Greeks" along the Dnieper river system. A vast array of goods were transported along these routes and exchanged with local Novgorod merchants and other traders. The farmers of Gotland retained the Saint Olof trading house well into the 12th century. Later German merchantmen also established tradinghouses in Novgorod. Scandinavian royalty would intermarry with Russian princes and princesses.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the great schism, Novgorod struggled from the beginning of the 13th century against Swedish, Danish, and German crusaders. During the Swedish-Novgorodian Wars, the Swedes invaded lands where some of the population had earlier paid tribute to Novgorod. The Germans had been trying to conquer the Baltic region since the late 12th century. Novgorod went to war 26 times with Sweden and 11 times with the Livonian Brothers of the Sword. The German knights, along with Danish and Swedish feudal lords, launched a series of uncoordinated attacks in 1240-1242. Novgorodian sources mention that a Swedish army was defeated in the Battle of the Neva in 1240. The Baltic German campaigns ended in failure after the Battle on the Ice in 1242. After the foundation of the castle of Viborg in 1293 the Swedes gained a foothold in Karelia. On August 12, 1323, Sweden and Novgorod signed the Treaty of Nteborg, regulating their border for the first time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The city's downfall occurred partially as a result of its inability to feed its large population, making it dependent on the Vladimir-Suzdal region for grain. The main cities in the area, Moscow and Tver, used this dependence to gain control over Novgorod. Eventually Ivan III forcibly annexed the city to the Grand Duchy of Moscow in 1478. The Veche was dissolved and a significant part of Novgorod's population was either killed or deported. The Hanseatic League kontor was closed in 1494 and the goods stored there were seized by Muscovite forces.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Novgorod -->
  <!-- Civilization Prussia -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Prussians</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>普鲁士文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Prussia</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>普鲁士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Prussian:Prussians</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>普鲁士</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PRUSSIA_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Prussia -->
  <!-- Civilization Aragon -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Aragonese</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉贡文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Aragon</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉贡</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Aragonese</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>阿拉贡人</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARAGON_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Crown of Aragon was a composite monarchy, also nowadays referred to as a confederation of individual polities or kingdoms ruled by one king with a personal and dynastic union of the Kingdom of Aragon and the county of Barcelona. At the height of its power in the 14th and 15th centuries, the Crown of Aragon was a thalassocracy (a state with primarily maritime realms) controlling a large portion of present-day eastern Spain, parts of what is now southern France, and a Mediterranean "empire" which included the Balearic Islands, Sicily, Corsica, Sardinia, Malta, Southern Italy (from 1442) and parts of Greece (until 1388). The component realms of the Crown were not united politically except at the level of the king, who ruled over each autonomous polity according to its own laws, raising funds under each tax structure, dealing separately with each cortes. Put in contemporary terms, it has sometimes been considered that the different lands of the Crown of Aragon functioned more as a confederacy of cultures rather than as a single country. In this sense, the larger Crown of Aragon must not be confused with one of its constituent parts, the Kingdom of Aragon, from which it takes its name.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1469, a new dynastic familial union of the Crown of Aragon with the Crown of Castile by the Catholic Monarchs, joining what contemporaries referred to as "the Spains" led to what would become the Kingdom of Spain under King Philip II. The Crown existed until it was abolished by the Nueva Planta decrees issued by King Philip V in 1716 as a consequence of the defeat of Archduke Charles in the War of the Spanish Succession.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]The Crown of Aragon was a composite monarchy, also nowadays referred to as a confederation of individual polities or kingdoms ruled by one king with a personal and dynastic union of the Kingdom of Aragon and the county of Barcelona. At the height of its power in the 14th and 15th centuries, the Crown of Aragon was a thalassocracy (a state with primarily maritime realms) controlling a large portion of present-day eastern Spain, parts of what is now southern France, and a Mediterranean "empire" which included the Balearic Islands, Sicily, Corsica, Sardinia, Malta, Southern Italy (from 1442) and parts of Greece (until 1388). The component realms of the Crown were not united politically except at the level of the king, who ruled over each autonomous polity according to its own laws, raising funds under each tax structure, dealing separately with each cortes. Put in contemporary terms, it has sometimes been considered that the different lands of the Crown of Aragon functioned more as a confederacy of cultures rather than as a single country. In this sense, the larger Crown of Aragon must not be confused with one of its constituent parts, the Kingdom of Aragon, from which it takes its name.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1469, a new dynastic familial union of the Crown of Aragon with the Crown of Castile by the Catholic Monarchs, joining what contemporaries referred to as "the Spains" led to what would become the Kingdom of Spain under King Philip II. The Crown existed until it was abolished by the Nueva Planta decrees issued by King Philip V in 1716 as a consequence of the defeat of Archduke Charles in the War of the Spanish Succession.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Aragon -->
  <!-- Civilization Morocco -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Moroccans</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>摩洛哥文明</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Morocco</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>摩洛哥</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>
      <Text>Moroccan:Moroccans</Text>
      <Gender>Male</Gender>
      <Plural>0:1</Plural>
    </English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>摩洛哥</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MOROCCO_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]In 670 AD, the first Islamic conquest of the North African coastal plain took place under Uqba ibn Nafi, a general serving under the Umayyads of Damascus. The Umayyad Muslims brought their language, their system of government, and Islam to Morocco. Many of the Berbers slowly converted to Islam, mostly after Arab rule had receded. The first independent Muslim state in the area of modern Morocco was the Kingdom of Nekor, an emirate in the Rif Mountains. It was founded by Salih I ibn Mansur in 710, as a client state to the Rashidun Caliphate. After the outbreak of the Great Berber Revolt in 739, the Berbers formed other independent states such as the Miknasa of Sijilmasa and the Barghawata.[PARAGRAPH:2]According to medieval legend, Idris ibn Abdallah had fled to Morocco after the Abbasids' massacre of his tribe in Iraq. He convinced the Awraba Berber tribes to break their allegiance to the distant Abbasid caliphs in Baghdad and he founded the Idrisid Dynasty in 788. The Idrisids established Fes as their capital and Morocco became a centre of Muslim learning and a major regional power. The Idrissids were ousted in 927 by the Fatimid Caliphate and their Miknasa allies. After Miknasa broke off relations with the Fatimids in 932, they were removed from power by the Maghrawa of Sijilmasa in 980.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the 11th century onwards, a series of powerful Berber dynasties arose. Under the Almoravid dynasty and the Almohad dynasty, Morocco dominated the Maghreb, much of present-day Spain and Portugal, and the western Mediterranean region. In the 13th and 14th centuries the Merinids held power in Morocco and strove to replicate the successes of the Almohads by military campaigns in Algeria and Spain. They were followed by the Wattasids. In the 15th century, the Reconquista ended Muslim rule in central and southern Spain and Portugal and many Muslims and Jews fled to Morocco.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portuguese efforts to control the Atlantic sea trade in the 15th century did not greatly affect the interior of Morocco even though they managed to control some possessions on the Moroccan coast but not venturing further afield inland.[PARAGRAPH:2]On another note and according to Elizabeth Allo Isichei, "In 1520, there was a famine in Morocco so terrible that for a long time other events were dated by it. It has been suggested that the population of Morocco fell from 5 to under 3 million between the early sixteenth and nineteenth centuries."[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1549, the region fell to successive Arab dynasties claiming descent from the Islamic prophet, Muhammad: first the Saadi dynasty who ruled from 1549 to 1659, and then the Alaouite Dynasty, who remained in power since the 17th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under the Saadi Dynasty, the country repulsed Ottoman incursions and a Portuguese invasion at the battle of Ksar el Kebir in 1578. The reign of Ahmad al-Mansur brought new wealth and prestige to the Sultanate, and a large expedition to West Africa inflicted a crushing defeat on the Songhay Empire in 1591. However, managing the territories across the Sahara proved too difficult. After the death of al-Mansur the country was divided among his sons.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1666 Morocco was reunited by the Alaouite Dynasty, who have been the ruling house of Morocco ever since. Morocco was facing aggression from Spain and the Ottoman Empire lies pressing westward. The Alaouites succeeded in stabilizing their position, and while the kingdom was smaller than previous ones in the region, it remained quite wealthy. Against the opposition of local tribes Ismail Ibn Sharif (1672-1727) began to create a unified state. With his Jaysh d'Ahl al-Rif (the Riffian Army) he seized Tangier from the English in 1684 and drove the Spanish from Larache in 1689.[PARAGRAPH:2]Morocco was the first nation to recognize the fledgling United States as an independent nation in 1777. In the beginning of the American Revolution, American merchant ships in the Atlantic Ocean were subject to attack by the Barbary pirates. On 20 December 1777, Morocco's Sultan Mohammed III declared that American merchant ships would be under the protection of the sultanate and could thus enjoy safe passage. The Moroccan-American Treaty of Friendship, signed in 1786, stands as the U.S.'s oldest non-broken friendship treaty.</English>    
     <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]In 670 AD, the first Islamic conquest of the North African coastal plain took place under Uqba ibn Nafi, a general serving under the Umayyads of Damascus. The Umayyad Muslims brought their language, their system of government, and Islam to Morocco. Many of the Berbers slowly converted to Islam, mostly after Arab rule had receded. The first independent Muslim state in the area of modern Morocco was the Kingdom of Nekor, an emirate in the Rif Mountains. It was founded by Salih I ibn Mansur in 710, as a client state to the Rashidun Caliphate. After the outbreak of the Great Berber Revolt in 739, the Berbers formed other independent states such as the Miknasa of Sijilmasa and the Barghawata.[PARAGRAPH:2]According to medieval legend, Idris ibn Abdallah had fled to Morocco after the Abbasids' massacre of his tribe in Iraq. He convinced the Awraba Berber tribes to break their allegiance to the distant Abbasid caliphs in Baghdad and he founded the Idrisid Dynasty in 788. The Idrisids established Fes as their capital and Morocco became a centre of Muslim learning and a major regional power. The Idrissids were ousted in 927 by the Fatimid Caliphate and their Miknasa allies. After Miknasa broke off relations with the Fatimids in 932, they were removed from power by the Maghrawa of Sijilmasa in 980.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the 11th century onwards, a series of powerful Berber dynasties arose. Under the Almoravid dynasty and the Almohad dynasty, Morocco dominated the Maghreb, much of present-day Spain and Portugal, and the western Mediterranean region. In the 13th and 14th centuries the Merinids held power in Morocco and strove to replicate the successes of the Almohads by military campaigns in Algeria and Spain. They were followed by the Wattasids. In the 15th century, the Reconquista ended Muslim rule in central and southern Spain and Portugal and many Muslims and Jews fled to Morocco.[PARAGRAPH:2]Portuguese efforts to control the Atlantic sea trade in the 15th century did not greatly affect the interior of Morocco even though they managed to control some possessions on the Moroccan coast but not venturing further afield inland.[PARAGRAPH:2]On another note and according to Elizabeth Allo Isichei, "In 1520, there was a famine in Morocco so terrible that for a long time other events were dated by it. It has been suggested that the population of Morocco fell from 5 to under 3 million between the early sixteenth and nineteenth centuries."[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1549, the region fell to successive Arab dynasties claiming descent from the Islamic prophet, Muhammad: first the Saadi dynasty who ruled from 1549 to 1659, and then the Alaouite Dynasty, who remained in power since the 17th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under the Saadi Dynasty, the country repulsed Ottoman incursions and a Portuguese invasion at the battle of Ksar el Kebir in 1578. The reign of Ahmad al-Mansur brought new wealth and prestige to the Sultanate, and a large expedition to West Africa inflicted a crushing defeat on the Songhay Empire in 1591. However, managing the territories across the Sahara proved too difficult. After the death of al-Mansur the country was divided among his sons.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1666 Morocco was reunited by the Alaouite Dynasty, who have been the ruling house of Morocco ever since. Morocco was facing aggression from Spain and the Ottoman Empire lies pressing westward. The Alaouites succeeded in stabilizing their position, and while the kingdom was smaller than previous ones in the region, it remained quite wealthy. Against the opposition of local tribes Ismail Ibn Sharif (1672-1727) began to create a unified state. With his Jaysh d'Ahl al-Rif (the Riffian Army) he seized Tangier from the English in 1684 and drove the Spanish from Larache in 1689.[PARAGRAPH:2]Morocco was the first nation to recognize the fledgling United States as an independent nation in 1777. In the beginning of the American Revolution, American merchant ships in the Atlantic Ocean were subject to attack by the Barbary pirates. On 20 December 1777, Morocco's Sultan Mohammed III declared that American merchant ships would be under the protection of the sultanate and could thus enjoy safe passage. The Moroccan-American Treaty of Friendship, signed in 1786, stands as the U.S.'s oldest non-broken friendship treaty.</Chinese>
    </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Morocco -->
  <!-- Civilization Papal States -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_DESC</Tag>
    <English>The Papal States</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>教宗国</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Papal States</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>教宗国</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Papal</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>教宗</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PAPAL_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]The Papal States emerged from the ashes of the Western Roman Empire. As Christianity grew, wealthy Roman patrons donated large tracts of land to the Church, and soon the Bishop of Rome (the title of "Pope" was not instituted until later) was the largest landholder in Italy, giving him a good deal of economic and political power in the region, along with his growing spiritual might. During the sixth century AD, the Eastern Roman Empire (based in Constantinople), launched a reconquest of Italy, taking much of the southern part of the peninsula. They took Rome as well, but proved unable to protect her from the growing Lombardian menace to the north.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thus the protection of Rome largely devolved upon the Bishop of Rome, by then the most powerful person in the region. Of necessity he had to raise armies and build fortifications to defend the Holy City from the Lombards, who were tightening their stranglehold on Rome. Over time the Bishops began to chafe under Constantinople's rule and sought to become fully independent from the Eastern Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Popes found their champion in Pepin the Short, who in return for Pope Stephen II's support of his deposing the last of the Merovingian kings and assuming control of all of the Frankish lands, invaded Italy and drove the Lombardians from the areas around Rome. He gave these liberated lands to the Pope, officially creating the Papal States.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Papal States would exist for another ten centuries. It was finally dismantled during the Italian unification struggles which took place in the 1860s and '70s.</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
     <Chinese>[TAB]The Papal States emerged from the ashes of the Western Roman Empire. As Christianity grew, wealthy Roman patrons donated large tracts of land to the Church, and soon the Bishop of Rome (the title of "Pope" was not instituted until later) was the largest landholder in Italy, giving him a good deal of economic and political power in the region, along with his growing spiritual might. During the sixth century AD, the Eastern Roman Empire (based in Constantinople), launched a reconquest of Italy, taking much of the southern part of the peninsula. They took Rome as well, but proved unable to protect her from the growing Lombardian menace to the north.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thus the protection of Rome largely devolved upon the Bishop of Rome, by then the most powerful person in the region. Of necessity he had to raise armies and build fortifications to defend the Holy City from the Lombards, who were tightening their stranglehold on Rome. Over time the Bishops began to chafe under Constantinople's rule and sought to become fully independent from the Eastern Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Popes found their champion in Pepin the Short, who in return for Pope Stephen II's support of his deposing the last of the Merovingian kings and assuming control of all of the Frankish lands, invaded Italy and drove the Lombardians from the areas around Rome. He gave these liberated lands to the Pope, officially creating the Papal States.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Papal States would exist for another ten centuries. It was finally dismantled during the Italian unification struggles which took place in the 1860s and '70s.</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Papal States -->
  <!-- Civilization Independent -->
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Independent Cities</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
    <English>Independents</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
    <English>Independent</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>独立城邦</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <TEXT>
    <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDEPENDENT_PEDIA</Tag>
    <English>[TAB]I will survive</English>
    <L1 />
    <L2 />
    <L3 />
    <L4 />
    <Chinese>[TAB]我要活下去</Chinese>
  </TEXT>
  <!-- Civilization Independent -->
</Civ4GameText>